OURDEN 字幕組出品
翻譯+校對：ABEL，Big Hall，Calbee，GeVid，魷魚暮良
翻譯+校對：JustinAlberto，Swaggy Disc，Yung GluMi
時間軸+後期：Jimmy貝殼，ABEL，早睡晚起的老濕
<i>Violent street gangs from Los Angeles</i>
洛杉磯街頭犯罪團夥
ZM.OURDEN.NET
Weibo:@OURDEN
<i>are now trafficking in drugs
in cities far from their own turf.</i>
開始在各自管轄地區參與販毒活動…
<i>Crips, the bloods.</i>
以Crip幫和Blood幫為首
<i>Has enabled the gangs
to become richer,</i>
毒品使得幫派迅速獲利
<i>better armed and better organized.</i>
幫派規模和武裝力量都日益增強
<i>Drugs are menacing our society.</i>
毒品氾濫，正在威脅著我們的社會
<i>The war on drugs is focused
on crack, the super-addictive...</i>
對毒品的戰爭中
我們最大的敵人是一種極易成癮的新型毒品“快克”
<i>the Los Angeles police
department's crash program.</i>
洛杉磯警署開始對毒品宣戰
<i>They will have
no dark alleyways to hide in.</i>
涉毒犯罪分子們將無處遁形
<i>I, Lieutenant Colonel North,</i>
我 Colonel North 中校
Colonel North，前美國海軍陸戰對中校
曾被指控有運毒嫌疑
<i>I don't recall that conversation.</i>
不記得有過這樣的對話
<i>You are now about to witness
the strength of street knowledge</i>
“你即將見證這來自街頭底層的力量”
Dr.Dre 在 Straight Outta Compton 這首歌裡的Intro
#NowPlaying: "Talking To My Diary" by Dr. Dre
I'm about to give you this right here.
我這就弄好這點兒貨
Yeah?
嗯？
Who is it?
誰啊？
You know who it is.
你知道是誰
Open the fucking door.
他媽的開門！
Open the door.
快開門
Hurry up, man. Open the fucking door.
喲，快點哥們，快開門
What's up, cuz?
你好啊，哥們
What's up, homie?
你好，夥計
A'ight.
好了吧
E.
E
So, wassup with you and this code knock
既然咱們敲門有暗號
and asking me to say my name at the door?
你還讓我報名字幹嘛？
We don't trust you motherfuckers.
因為我不信任你們這些混子
What y'all tryin' to do?
勸你還是信
Oh, you ain't heard?
Best runner got cracked.
你沒聽說？我手下跑貨最得力的小夥被逮了
Sent his young ass up to YA.
被關到少管所了
Y.A. Youth Authority 專門關押少年犯的地方
That's sad.
那挺慘的
Fuck that gotta do with me?
這他媽跟我有毛關係
Hey, Tasha!
嘿，Tasha!
I'm right here.
在這呢
Hey, get this dude a 40.
給這哥們拿瓶啤酒
God.
啊
Hurry up!
快點的！
Nigga, I look thirsty?
我看上去很口渴嗎？
I look thirsty to you?
你看我現在口渴嗎？
Here.
給
Bitch, I just said I wasn't thirsty!
草，我他媽剛說了，我不渴
Hold up. Why you gotta be so ruthless, Eric?
唉，唉，唉，別急，你幹嘛脾氣這麼火，Eric?
I'm straight.
我不用
What, y'all don't want something to drink?
怎麼，你不想先喝點兒東西嗎？
You want some pussy?
難道你想先玩幾個妞兒？
Not from these little strawberry
bitches you got up in here.
我可不要你這兒的這些貨色
I want my fucking money.
Where the money at?
我來要錢的，我的錢在哪呢？
Fuck you being so disrespectful
in my house for, cuz?
你他媽的敢這麼不尊重我的地盤？
Nigga, this a dope house
that you already disrespecting.
你們在這屋裡販毒呢，還用談什麼尊重？
Yeah, we good.
外面沒事兒
So bottom line is we short...
跟你直說，我們現在手頭緊
So you gonna have to let us hold onto that.
你得讓我們緩一緩再給錢
Oh, yeah?
是嗎？
Well, my people sitting right across the
street from your mama house right now.
我的人現在正在你老媽家街對面等信兒
Cause if I don't show up,
they gonna show out.
如果我不按時出現，他們就會動手
Greenleaf, right?
That's the street she stay on?
綠葉大街，你老媽就住那兒吧？
You really wanna take it there?
你他媽的真要玩這麼絕？
You already took it there.
你已經玩的夠絕的了！
Shit, it's one time.
They got a battering ram.
靠，是條子，他們開大傢伙來了
Get to the back, Rock!
Hey, man, get to the back!
快到後門去，快到後面
They better not find a motherfucking thing!
別讓他們查到我們的東西！
Get all that shit up in the roof.
我們的貨物快藏到天花板裡
Hurry up!
快點！
Man, get to the back!
哥們，快到後面去
- You know what to do with it.
- Yeah.
你應該知道怎麼處理 - 知道
Keisha!
- What's taking you so long?
- Shit.
別磨蹭了！ - 靠
Hurry up!
快點！
Step up, girl!
來，上來
Tasha!
Go, go, go!
上，上，上！
Oh, shit.
我擦
Fuckin' dog.
這破狗
#NowPlaying: "Everybody Loves The Sunshine" by Roy Ayers Ubiquity
<i>My life, my life, my life.</i>
<i>In the sunshine.</i>
<i>Everybody loves the sunshine.</i>
<i>Sunshine.</i>
What happened?
幹嘛呢？
Whatcha mean? What happened with what?
什麼？我沒幹嘛啊
Andre, boy, don't play with me.
Andre, 別裝沒事兒人
Do you even care how it makes me look?
你讓我下次怎麼有臉見人家？
Called in favors to get your thoughtless ass
我求人給你這不爭氣的小子一次面試機會
an interview and you can't even show up?
結果你居然都不去露個面？
Look, I'm sorry, Ma. I just...
對不起，老媽，主要是……
I got so caught up in this DJ stuff, I forgot.
正好有一個活動請我去DJ，所以我給忘了
You have a child, Andre.
你都有孩子了，Andre
Spinnin' records ain't paying
none of the bills around here.
整天玩那些唱片你能養活誰？
Whatchu talkin' about? I get paid.
你說什麼呢，是有錢賺的啊
$50. So that makes you rich?
50塊，這就算有錢啦？
It's a start. Damn!
好歹是個開始啊
Why you riding me so hard?
你為什麼總這麼催我
I'm not riding you, baby.
I'm trying to make you understand.
我不是在逼你，我只是想讓你明白
And you know how I run my house.
你也知道在家裡我是怎麼主事的
Now you gonna have to go to school
or you gonna have to go to work.
你要麼繼續上學，要麼就去工作賺錢
Now I don't even care if you are a janitor.
我不管你去做什麼工作
I don't care what the hell you do...
門衛也好，做什麼工作都好
Long as I own the company. I know, I know.
只要我能有個自己的事業，我記得，我記得
But you don't own the company.
你現在去的地方根本不是你去掌握的
- Lonzo does.
- Okay.
Lanzo 是老闆。 - 好啦
You think we're done here?
你以為我說完了？
- Yeah, I mean, you keep...
- You got something to say to me?
是啊，你…  - 你有什麼想說的？
You don't care what I'm fightin' for, okay?
你根本不知道也不在乎我的夢想是什麼
I already know what
I want to do with my life
我知道我這輩子要幹什麼
and it definitely ain't
sitting in some cubicle,
總之絕不是平庸碌碌無為
taking orders on a bullshit-ass job.
去幹那些千篇一律的狗屁工作
Shut up!
你閉嘴！
People used to tell me
I was too young when I had you.
別人說我懷你的時候太年輕了
Dre的媽媽懷他的時候只有16歲
Said I wouldn't be shit.
他們說我這輩子就算完了
Said you wouldn't be shit.
說孩子就算養活了也是一輩子一事無成
Now, I worked my ass off to get us here,
我拼命的工作才讓我們家有個家的樣子
and I refuse to let you throw it all away.
我絕不會讓你把現在的生活給丟掉
Hey, I grabbed some of your stuff.
我這兒還找到一些你的東西
Good lookin' out, T.
好嘞，謝了，T
When you comin' back?
你什麼時候回來？
Man, I don't even know.
說不準啊
Got a lotta things to figure out.
我有好多事兒要去琢磨
Can I come with you?
我能跟你走嗎？
Really?
真的？
You've been crying this whole time
about us sharing a room.
我在家裡你老抱怨我們家太擠了
And now you wanna come with me.
現在你又要跟我走？
Man, get out of here.
老弟，別逗了
You know Mom. She just...
你也知道……
She just want the best for you.
老媽就是想讓你出人頭地
Hey, I know that, T.
我知道，T
But check this out,
I want the best for me too.
不過你要知道，我也是想要出人頭地的
Ar'ight?
明白了？
That mean I gotta go.
所以我也得離開一陣了
Look, when I get set up right,
對了，當我混的差不多了
I'mma bring you with me.
我再回家來帶上你
Don't even worry about it.
I'mma have you in Miami.
不用擔心我，我會帶你去邁阿密玩兒
For real?
真的？
- You gotta get me in Miami.
- Yeah, man.
那你可一定要帶我去邁阿密見識下
Don't play, man. Get me somewhere.
別逗我哈，帶我出去見識見識，哪都行
Hey, I'll call you later.
嗯我會給你打電話的
For now, stay your little
ass outta trouble.
不過現在你得小心別招惹麻煩
Yeah, yeah.
好吧，好吧
Hey, nah. For real.
嘿，說真的
- Ar'ight, bruh.
- Ar'ight.
好啦，老哥  -  好的
#NowPlaying: "Jam-Master Jay" by Run-D.M.C.
<i>Kick off shoes, jump on the jock</i>
踢飛鞋子，跳入舞池
<i>Listen to the Jam Master as he starts to rock</i>
當Jam Master開始表演時，不要錯過
<i>His name is Jay and he's on his way</i>
牢記他的名字是Jay，他正在成名之路
這首歌出現在Run-D.M.C.的第一張同名專輯中
介紹了他們的DJ和製作人Jam-Master Jay
<i>To be the best DJ in the US of A</i>
目標成為全美國最牛的DJ
What you been up to, Cube?
在幹嘛呢 Cube？
Shit, writin' rhymes.
靠，寫詞兒呢
You a poet now?
你成詩人了？
The flyest one you know, nigga.
是你認識的最吊的詩人
This nigga. Okay. I'll see you.
哥們你真行
- Hi, Mr. Davis.
- Hi.
嗨 Mr. Davis  -  嗨
I wish somebody would try me though.
我倒是希望有人敢來動我試試
That's all I'm saying. You feel me?
我說的就這意思，你懂的
- Hey!
- Shit, nigga! Come here!
嘿  -  夥計，來，過來
#NowPlaying: "More Bounce to the Ounce" by Zapp & Roger
Hey, what up, cuz?
嘿，幹嘛呢哥們？
What up, cuz?
你好啊，哥們
Whatcha doin', nigga?
怎麼樣啊哥幾個？
Hey, cuz!
嗨，哥們
What up?
怎麼樣，哥們？
Wassup?
怎麼著
What's good, nigga?
怎麼樣，哥們？
All good? Hey, what up, cuz?
還行？怎麼著哥們？
Crip!
Crip幫！
Crip幫是與Blood幫對立的大幫派
Get outta here, man. You old mark-ass.
啊真沒勁，老傢伙們
You see that shit?
你看見沒？
Shut it down!
熄火！
Open up the goddamn door, man.
把他媽的車門打開！
What's going on?
什麼事
Shut the fuck up, blood.
他媽的閉嘴！
Y'all niggas ready to die today?
你們這幫玩意兒想死啊？
Don't get quiet now.
現在啞巴了？
All that shit
y'all was throwin' up out the window?
剛剛從窗口往外喊什麼廢話？
What's up with it, huh?
都什麼毛病？
You didn't think we saw that, huh?
以為我們沒看見？
Let me see how you do that shit again.
Let me see.
來來來，再說兩句，再說兩句
I was just playin', man, I swear.
I was only playin', man.
我說著玩的，真的，我只是開玩笑，哥
You think niggas out here are playin'? Huh?
你以為我上來也是開玩笑的？
Niggas die every day.
他媽的每天都有人掛
I kill Crips for breakfast.
我殺Crip幫的人當晨練
Don't you ever put your motherfucking hands
up on no school bus, nigga.
以後別把手伸到車窗外亂擺什麼手勢
You understand me?
你懂嗎？
- Yeah.
- Huh?
明白  - 嗯？
Yeah.
明白
Y'all motherfuckers need
to gang bang them books
你們就應該好好啃你們的書本
instead of tryin' to be
somethin' y'all ain't.
別他媽裝逼拿樣
Shit, you never know.
沒混過，懂個屁
'Cause I might be the one
to kill your motherfucking ass.
也我就是取你小命的人
Remember me.
給我記住
O.G. Two Tone, Crenshaw Mafia, blood.
2-Tone，哥是Crenshaw幫的老炮
#NowPlaying: "Just Another Day" by The Game, Asia Bryant
<i>Another day in Compton, the thrill is high</i>
這是康普頓的日常，危險就在身邊
<i>Know somebody's watching, but I don't know why</i>
沒有原因，有雙眼睛在俯視這城市
Somebody 寓意，上帝
<i>Feel the fire burning, it touches the sky</i>
邪惡的火焰在燃燒，火光沖天
火焰暗喻康普頓的犯罪活動
<i>Feeling coming at you, I won't die tonight</i>
感覺這火焰不停靠近，但我會繼續生存
Yo, Dre and Jinx in there?
嗨，Dre 和 Jinx 在嗎？
Yup, they in there.
嗯，在裡面呢
- Hey, Auntie.
- Hi, baby.
嗨，小姨  - 嘿，寶貝
- How you doin'?
- Just fine.
還好嗎  - 還好啊
- Lavetta, where Dre and Jinx at?
- They're in the back.
Lavetta，Dre 和 Jinx 在哪呢？
- 在後面呢
Excuse me.
好的
Come on. Chill out.
好了，別鬧
- Hey, little mama.
- Take your nap.
嘿，小姑娘
- 吃點兒零食
Why didn't you say hi?
你怎麼不打招呼呀？
#NowPlaying: "Al Naafiysh (The Soul)" by Hashim
- Wuddup, Cube?
- Wuddup?
你好 Cube？ - 你好
Ooh.
喔~
Whoo!
哇哦
Do that shit!
走起來
Damn, Dre!
牛逼啊，Dre!
Whoo!
喔！
Damn.
屌！
Whoo!
哇哦！
Yeah!
耶
That's right.
帶感！
Whoo!
哇喔
Whoo! Fuck that shit up, Dre!
喔！玩的太燥了，Dre
- Yo.
- That shit was dope, homie!
喲  - 這段節奏太屌了
- What's up, Cube?
- Man!
你怎麼樣 Cube?
I had some crazy shit
happen on the bus today.
今兒在校車上差點出大事兒
I had a Crenshaw Mafia O.G. get on the bus,
一個Crenshaw幫的混子上了校車
pulled a gun out on us,
掏槍指著我們
gave a fucking motivational speech
and then bumped out.
來了一通幫派演講然後下車了
The shit was crazy.
真瘋了這幫人
You wanna avoid some more crazy shit,
要想近期平安無事
you better not get up
on that stage and fuck up.
你最好別搞砸咱們這次演出
Ain't nobody gonna fuck up, man.
演出我才不會出岔子呢
- You must be stayin' a while.
- Yup.
你是要打算在這住一陣子嘍？ - 嗯
Mama kicked him out 'cause of that mouth.
他媽把他趕出家門了，就因為他愛頂嘴
Shut your ass up.
閉上你這嘴
She didn't kick me out. I left.
不是她趕我走，是我自己要走
Whatever.
隨你怎麼說
That's what
they all say, homie. Right?
別人都這麼說你的，好吧？
You got them rhymes?
你歌詞寫好沒？
Man, I stay with the rhymes.
那當然，哥的詞本不離手
Man, I'm talkin'
about that hard shit.
我說的可是夠狠的詞
- All I write is that hard shit, Dre.
- Okay.
我寫的東西都特別狠，Dre
So wassup, man? You ready for Doo-to's?
那好啊，那你準備好去 Doo-To's 了嗎？
Shit, is Doo-to's ready for me?
靠，Doo-To's 準備好迎接我了嗎？
You know that's Compton, right?
They got body bags at the door.
你知道這是康普頓吧？夜店門口都放著運屍袋
Okay.
好吧
Your ass better bring it,
你最好把現場帶動起來
'cause if you don't,
you might end up in one for real.
萬一你演砸了，你可能就進去了
Body bag?
運屍袋？
Man, I don't know about that shit.
這我還真不知道
Ain't nobody
fucking with you, Jinx.
沒人願意跟你一塊混了，Jinx.
Stupid, man.
Tell your moms to fix this fucking AC.
跟你老媽說趕緊修好空調行不行
Man, what are you doing here, homeless?
哥們你在我這幹嘛？無家可歸啦？
Get off of me, nigga!
你放開我，老黑
- Fuck you! Get the fuck off me.
- Stay down.
我靠，別動我！ - 都給我趴下！
We didn't do shit!
我什麼也沒幹
The fuck you holding me for?
Get the fuck off me!
你憑什麼抓我？別他媽動我
Where the fuck you going?
你他媽往哪兒走？
Hey, man, I'm just trying to get home, man.
I'm not even doin' nothin'.
嘿，我只是要回家，我可只是路過
Put your fucking hands on top of
your head. Interlace your fingers.
把你手交叉放腦袋上
Spread your fucking legs.
腿分開站好
You need to stay the fuck down.
你給我他媽的趴好！
Man, this hood is fuckin' hot!
這引擎蓋太燙啦
Shut the fuck up!
你給我閉嘴
What the hell is going on out here?
這兒發生什麼事啦？
Look, these boys,
they all grew up on this block, okay?
喂，這些孩子都是在這個街區長大的
- You need to get back in the house.
- That's my son.
你現在需要立即回屋  - 那是我兒子啊
- That's my... O'Shea! That's my son.
- You need to get back in the house.
那是我兒子，是我兒子
- 你現在需要立即回屋
- Lady, I'm telling you...
- Damn.
這位女士，我告訴你
- 靠
You get back inside, or I promise you,
趕緊回家，否則我保證
I will ruin your fuckin' night!
你今晚沒好果子吃
Man, you ain't got to talk
to my mom's like that.
喂，你怎麼能跟我媽用這種語氣說話？
Shut the fuck up! Motherfuckin' nigger.
閉上嘴，你們這群黑鬼
Oh, I'm a nigger now?
你罵我是黑鬼？
Wait a minute my ass, motherfucker.
等一等？等個屁
Okay.
好吧
Officer, can you explain
why you jacking us right now?
警官，你能告訴我為什麼抓我嗎？
Man, I ain't explaining shit to you.
我他媽不用跟你解釋
Get the fuck up off the street.
你給我從街上滾回去
I'm on my property.
I can stand right here. You got that?
我站在我自己家土地上，我有權站這兒，你明白嗎
Son! We right here.
兒子！我們就在這
Where you got the fuckin' rocks, homeboy?
你的貨藏哪兒了？
Not everybody's slangin' dope, man.
老大，不是每個人都是毒販啊
I don't give a fuck! This LAPD.
去你媽的，我們是員警
- I'm the only gangster out here.
- All right.
我們洛城員警才掌管這一片街區！ - 好吧
They all check out.
好了都檢查過他們了
Check out? Check what, man?
Y'all are just over here fuckin' with us.
檢查？查什麼啊，你們就是在這故意整我們
Get up.
起來
We got cards on all of 'em anyway.
反正我們都掌握著他們的資訊
Pick your shit up.
把你的破爛撿起來
Stay out of trouble, man.
別他媽惹事兒
- Get the fuck out of here.
- Get your ass up!
行了你滾蛋吧  - 行了走吧
Let's go. Head home.
走吧，回家
Stay back.
退後
We ain't doin' shit, man!
我們可什麼都沒做
Get the fuck outta here.
趕緊給我走人
We didn't even fucking do shit!
我們他媽的什麼都沒做
Start fuckin' walking.
聽見沒，趕緊滾
Hey. Hey. Head home!
嘿，嘿，趕緊回家
O'Shea.
兒子…
Ice Cube 本名 O'Shea Jackson, Sr.
Fuck the police, homie!
去他媽的員警
Get the fuck out of here!
趕緊滾
Yo, this is bullshit!
真他媽倒楣
#NowPlaying: "I Didn't Mean to Turn You On" by Cherrelle
You really want to be here?
你真想來這地方？
This club full of Pirus.
這裡可有很多道上的混子
Pirus 是指Blood幫的成員
We straight.
我們不是惹事兒來的
Yeah, thanks for the tip, homie.
另外，多謝你的提醒，哥們
These niggas.
這些人
I just wanna say this.
You should be a model.
我覺得，你應該去當模特兒
Yeah, you look like a model.
是啊你看上去就像模特兒
Just sayin', you know.
嗯我覺得，是的
I look in your eyes and I see a Capricorn.
我一看你的眼睛就知道你是摩羯座
You're a Capricorn, right?
你是摩羯座的對吧？
I mean, I can look at a girl
and I know their sign, you know?
我看到一個妹子就能猜對她的星座
It's just something I do.
哥就是這麼神
Uh... Mmm-hmm.
嗯，嗯
I hope I'm not
disrespecting you, right?
希望我沒冒犯到你哈
- Uh-huh. Not at all.
- Good.
沒有啊  - 那就好
- Yella!
- Good.
Yella！
Lonzo coming, man.
Lanzo 來了
- Nah, nah. <i>Weak at the Knees.
</i>-Huh?
不是這首，拿 Weak At The Knees
"Weak At The Knees" by Steve Arrington's Hall Of Fame
<i>Weak at the Knees.</i>
拿 Weak At The Knees
- Hey.
- Wassup?
嘿  - 來了
I'mma go outside and make sure
nothing's poppin' off, all right?
我出去看看外面有沒有什麼亂子
I want you to keep these fat asses shakin'.
你放的歌要讓這幫人們繼續搖下去
Don't play none of that
street-ass rap shit, ar'ight?
別放哪些什麼街頭說唱的東西
I want these motherfuckers
to think about pussy, not pistols.
要讓這幫顧客們想要女人，而不是手槍
- Yella!
- Huh?
Yella!  - 嗯？
I saw you talking to my lady, man.
我看見你跟我的女人聊天呢
Keep your motherfuckin' hands to yourself.
你最好給我學老實點兒
All right.
好
Man, why you always fuckin'
with Lonzo's girl, man?
你怎麼總是跟 Lanzo 的妞兒聊天？
Why not?
為什麼不？
I can't be afraid
of a grown man in high heels, Dre.
我還怕一個穿高跟鞋的男人不成？
Cube, you up.
Cube，到你了
<i>Hey, yo, Compton!</i>
嘿喲，康普頓
<i>I got my little homie.</i>
給大家介紹我的哥們
<i>He 'bout to come
and bust a little rhyme for y'all.</i>
他會給大家來一段說唱表演
<i>I want y'all to give it up</i>
大家熱情歡迎我的朋友
<i>for Ice-motherfuckin'-Cube!</i>
他就是 Ice Cube!
Rap: "Gangsta Gangsta" by N.W.A
<i>Here's a little
somethin' 'bout a nigga like me.</i>
像我這樣的人，有些事情是一定要記住的
<i>Never shoulda been let
out the penitentiary.</i>
那就是永遠不要讓我邁出監獄一步
<i>Ice Cube would like to say.</i>
我現在很明確告訴你
<i>That I'm a crazy mutherfucka
from around the way.</i>
我是一個來自街頭的瘋小子
<i>Since I was a youth I smoked weed out.</i>
老子還年輕的時候就習慣抽葉子
<i>Now I'm the mutherfucka
that you read about.</i>
現在我已經成為一名寫詞人
<i>Takin' a life or two.</i>
殺過幾個人
雙關他過著兩種完全不同的生活，Cube是大學生，同樣見證了康普頓的混亂
<i>That's what the hell I do.</i>
這就是我的生活
<i>You don't like how I'm
livin' well, fuck you!</i>
你不喜歡我的生活方式，好吧...去你的！
<i>This is a gang and I'm in it.</i>
這就是一個幫派，我正是其中一員
<i>My man Dre'll fuck you up in a minute.</i>
Dre的節奏帶感，分分鐘讓你淪陷
<i>With a right left.</i>
一記左勾拳
將DJ打碟技術形容成拳術
<i>Right, left you're toothless.</i>
右鉤拳，讓你陷入危險
<i>And then you say goddamn they ruthless.</i>
你愣住了，只覺得：“這幫哥們真他媽狠！”
<i>Everywhere we go they say damn!</i>
我們所到之處，尖叫不斷
<i>Ice Cube's fuckin' up the program.</i>
我要把這一切規律搞亂
<i>And then you realize we don't care
We don't just say no.</i>
然後你卻發現我們根本毫不在乎，我們不會拒絕
曾經的美國第一夫人南茜·雷根提出對毒品“Just Say No”的口號
<i>We too busy sayin' yeah!</i>
因為我們忙著大喊“Yeah！”
<i>About drinkin' straight
out the eight bottle.</i>
是時候幹掉這瓶8-ball酒了
8 Bottle代表的是一款麥芽酒的品牌，俗稱8-ball
<i>Do I look like a motherfuckin' role model?</i>
我的造型看起來像一個好榜樣嗎？！
<i>To a kid lookin' up to me.</i>
對那些跟風的孩子說
<i>Life ain't nothin' but bitches and money</i>
生活其實只是關於妹子和票子
<i>'Cause I'm tha type of
nigga that's built to last.</i>
因為無論環境如何殘酷，我都能生存到最後
<i>If you fuck with me
I'll put my foot in your ass.</i>
最好別招惹我，因為我分分鐘把你廢掉
<i>I don't give a fuck 'cause I keep bailin'.</i>
要知道我根本不在乎，因為我天天忙於炫耀
<i>Yo, what the fuck are they yellin'?</i>
喲，你說他們在喊叫什麼？！
- Fucking right! I told you. I told you.
- Yes, you did.
不錯吧，我說什麼來著  - 太燥了
That's what I'm talking about, man.
沒錯，就是這麼燥
Now, see, I'm this close
to firing your monkey ass.
媽的，我就快把你給開掉了
What, you trying to start
a riot up in here?
你要幹嘛，你想在我這煽動騷亂嗎？
I told you. Didn't I tell you I don't want
that hardcore shit played in my club?
我有沒有告訴過你，別在我這店裡放這些髒話連篇的歌
As soon as I turn my back,
you do that shit anyway.
我他媽剛走，你就放這東西
I'm just trying to help
your business out, Lonzo.
我只是想幫夜店提高點人氣 Lonzo
You saw they went crazy for that shit.
你看觀眾都特別喜歡這種歌
Don't worry about my business, ar'ight?
我不用你操心我的生意
You just remember,
the only reason you up on that stage
你給我記住，你能在我這臺上演出
is 'cause I put you up
on that motherfuckin' stage.
全是靠老子給你這個機會
Now, you a badass DJ, I'll give you that,
but you don't like to listen, Dre.
你這DJ不太稱職了 Dre，我說什麼你都不聽
And I get tired of arguing all the time.
我也懶得跟你吵這些了
'Cause you know,
there's a lot of cats that'll come in here
你知道，有很多小鬼想來我這
and they'll play exactly
what I want 'em to play.
我叫他們放什麼歌，他們就放什麼
Like that shit right there.
就像現在放的這些音樂
Cats that understand that you don't
bite the hand that feeds you.
他們知道，不要反咬給他們飯吃的人
Now you take a backseat
to that shit, nigga.
你現在給我回去放這些歌
These fucking marching jackets and shit.
去他媽的這些土爆的流行音樂
Marching my ass. You march
your ass and do what the fuck I say.
土個屁，你趕緊按我說照做
Hey, Dre.
嘿 Dre
#NowPlaying: "Love You Down" by Ready for the World
Don't even trip on him, homie.
你幹嘛跟他這麼認真
Nigga ain't got no fucking vision, man.
他根本就沒有點兒遠見
That's why I'mma fuck his bitch.
After he leave.
所以這就是我為啥要聊他的妞兒，等他走了的
Not with that shit on.
可別穿這身衣服去聊
How you liking this little spot? Hey!
這地方怎麼樣？  - 嘿！
Dr. Dre.
Dr. Dre
Wassup, E?
你好啊 E
It's been a minute, man.
有陣子沒見啦
I love your jacket, by the way.
你這外套挺拉風啊
You baggin' on me.
別取笑我了
You know I don't like wearing this shit.
你知道我討厭這造型
That's Lonzo's shit, man.
You know it's part of the gig.
這是 Lanzo 要求的，工作的一部分
Yeah. You remember
the homie Ren from Kelly Park, right?
你還記得 Cali Park 的哥們 Ren 嗎？
- Wassup?
- Wuddup, Dre?
你好  - 你好 Dre
- Wuddup?
- Wassup, man?
你好  - 你好，哥們
Look, I heard you been, um,
我聽說你去了
spending some time at your auntie's house.
你小姨家住了一段時間
How's the couch life?
睡沙發舒服嗎？
It's fucked up.
太難受了
I'm too tall for that shit.
沙發太小，不夠躺
Plus I got my woman and baby livin' there.
It's hard, man.
我女人和孩子還在那，手頭也挺緊的
But you know,
everybody can't do what you do.
不過，也不是每個人都能幹的了你那行啊
Yeah, Dre. Well, what I do
gettin' played out quick, man.
說是這麼說，我那行也不是旱澇保收
Motherfuckers just getting locked up
and laid down out here, you know?
這些跑貨的關的關，死的死
- Mmm-hmm.
- I gotta make some changes.
嗯嗯  - 我得作出一下改變了
Changes ain't bad.
改變是好事兒
I'm thinking about
making a few changes myself.
我也想過我自己要改變一下
Whatcha mean?
你意思是？
Whatchu think about
dumping some money into this music shit?
你有沒有想過砸點錢來做音樂？
Look, I got some ideas.
我這是有一些小想法
<i>Let's give it up for Dr. Dre.</i>
“讓我們歡迎Dr.Dre!”
Fuck! I gotta get back up there.
靠，我得過去了
That's your calling, man.
嗯，叫你了
Tell Lonzo I said, "Fuck him." Ar'ight.
幫我跟 Lanzo 說一聲“尼瑪”
Hey, E.
嘿 E
Think about it.
考慮下啊
Ar'ight.
好的
Wassup? Do I know you?
我靠，你誰啊？
What?
你說什麼？
- Get 'em up.
- Hell no!
給我閃開！ - 我靠
Hey, don't be fuckin'
with my little brother, nigga!
嘿，你別動我弟弟
What the fuck did he do?
他怎麼你了？
Nigga lookin' at me
like he know me or somethin'.
這哥們盯著我好像我欠他錢似的
Man, I told you about this shit!
我早跟你說了別惹麻煩
<i>- Clear the parking lot.
</i>-I told you to go the fuck home.
“所有人離開停車場”
- 早說了讓你回家
The fuck wrong with you, man?
你什麼毛病啊
You better chill the fuck out.
你給我靜一下
One time.
條子
Hey! We told everybody
to clear this parking lot!
嘿，我說，都離開這個停車場
We just standing here.
我們就在這站會兒
Get outta here!
出什麼事兒了
What's going on?
怎麼了？
Hey! Head home.
嘿！回家去
I fell.
我摔倒了
You fell? He fell?
你摔倒了？他是摔倒了嗎？
That's what he said.
嗯他是這麼說的
I didn't ask you what he said.
我問你他說什麼了嗎？
Get the fuck home!
趕緊滾回家
I am home.
這就是我家
Head home. Go!
趕緊走，走！
If you don't start walking...
你還不滾蛋的話…
Or what?
就怎麼？
Turn around. Hands on your head.
轉過身去，手放頭上
Come here.
過來
You have the right to remain silent.
你有權保持沉默
Stop resisting, boy.
不要反抗
- What up, sucker-punch?
- You already know what it is.
怎麼樣，單挑王？ - 你懂的，這裡的套路
Sucker punched that dude, man.
是不是看不爽就把他們揍了
Hey, man, nah, nah, nah. That was Tyree.
不是，他惹我弟弟 Tyreese
You know he got that temper and shit.
你知道他是急脾氣
Always getting me into
fucking trouble, man.
總是給我找麻煩
So what they lock you up for?
那他們為什麼關你
I was literally just standing there, man.
That's it.
我還真是就站在原地沒走，沒別的
As far as they was concerned.
就是被他們看不順眼唄
That's the gangsterist
shit I heard all week.
這是我這幾天聽到最痞的話了
Man, it's stupid.
哥們別逗了
But I was thinking about what you
was saying last night, though, man.
我考慮了你昨晚上說的事兒
Oh, yeah? And?
是嗎？然後呢？
It's interesting.
有點意思
How long?
你說要多久
Really, like, how long do you think that
shit you doing out there gonna last?
真的，你幹的那一行，還要多久可能會放棄
'Cause it ain't no happy endings
in that game, man.
那種生意都不會有什麼好結果的
You saying a lot for a nigga
你剛被保釋出來
who just got bailed outta jail.
話還挺多啊
I'm just saying, if you can slang dope...
我就是說嘛，如果你販……
- Nigga!
- What, man?
喂喂！  - 什麼？
Just tell the whole fuckin'
world I sell dope.
你生怕別人不知道嗎？
Yo, yo. You can slang dope,
you can slang records, man. It's easy.
喲，你能販毒的話，也能販唱片
You got a mind for that shit, E.
你有這方面天賦，E
So whatchu talking about doing?
Lil' homie from last night?
那你說一起做這事兒的是誰，昨兒演出那個哥們？
Nah, man. He in a group.
也不是，他在另一個組合
You know, they a trip, but...
這樣搞可能也不好辦
But that shit, the reality raps,
that's what I'm talking about, man.
但，這麼說吧，描述現實的說唱，這才是我們要的
That's it.
就是這個
My boy, D.O.C.,
he coming in from Dallas, dope.
我有個哥們夠牛逼，達拉斯來的DOC
My little homie, Ren, rap too.
我哥們 Ren也會說唱
Oh, yeah?
是嗎？
Hey, look, I got these cats,
H.B.O., Home Boys Only
我還認識一個組合，H.B.O.“兄弟幫”
from New York, dope voices, man.
從紐約來的，他們聲音很棒
Some whack-ass lyrics, though.
不過他們的歌詞就太挫了
I'm saying, Cube,
he wrote this shit for 'em, it's crazy.
Cube 幫他們寫了點詞，絕對牛
Shit, we could probably
do something with that.
我想，我們也許真能做這事兒
That's what I'm saying, man.
Start a label or something, man.
是啊我就是這麼想的，我們可以先建一個廠牌
A label?
廠牌？
That's kinda fucking far-fetched, Dre.
是不是這想的太早了，Dre
Yeah, but check this out,
可能吧，不過你想想
what would you call a
record label like that?
我們這樣的廠牌，你會取一個什麼名字
Ruthless.
冷酷
Ruthless?
冷酷？
- Just like these fucking police, nigga.
- Ruthless.
就像這幫員警一樣，冷酷無情
#NowPlaying: "Boyz-N-The Hood" by N.W.A
Let's get the fuck from around here.
Trying to get me sent to jail.
咱們撤吧，在這晃容易被逮了
Get your simple ass in the car.
小夥，趕緊上車
<i>What the fuck is "gankin"?
And what's a "6-4"?</i>
這個 Ganking 是什麼意思？ -  6-4 又什麼意思？
<i>- Yeah.
</i>-It's a car. A 6-4 Impala.
是車，雪弗蘭 64款 黑斑羚
"Ganking" is when you jack somebody, man.
Ganking 意思是你打劫別人
It's not a big deal.
The shit just sound better.
不是事兒，用這些詞會聽起來更痞一些
<i>Yo, man, it's too much
cursing for radio play.</i>
哥們，這上面髒話太多電臺是不能播放的
I mean, besides, who gives a fuck
about Compton anyway? Right?
而且再說了，誰在乎康普頓這個城市哈？
Hold the fuck up. Hey. Hold up, man.
你們等等吧，等等
Hey, y'all got something
to say about Compton?
哎，你們對康普頓有啥看法嗎？
'Cause we might have a problem
up in this bitch.
那我們可能還真他媽的有點問題
Huh!
嗯？
<i>No? Then do the lyrics,</i>
沒有？那就按我們的歌詞唱
<i>'cause I'm really losing my patience,
ar'ight?</i>
我已經快沒有耐心了
Stop fucking embarrassing me, man.
別讓我為難
<i>Hey, man. I ain't with this shit.</i>
那我不錄了
Yeah, man. Fuck this shit.
對，去他媽的
- Fuck this Jheri curl rap bullshit, man.
- Where y'all going?
這些破歌詞都去見鬼去吧
Fuck you! Wearing a Kangol
don't make you LL Cool J, nigga.
去你媽的！你帶個袋鼠牌的帽子可不代表你就是 LL Cool J !
What the fuck you gonna do about it?
Whatcha gonna do, mark-ass nigga?
你想幹嘛？你想幹什麼，挫B？
Hey.
嘿
Let's roll, B.
我們走
B-street-looking motherfucker.
只會裝逼拿樣的慫貨
Fucking Jheri curl ass.
小卷毛混蛋
Keep talkin' that bullshit
on your way out the door, nigga.
滾出門的時候再叨逼叨
Well, there goes the talent, Dre.
這就是你說的歌手啊 Dre
Shut the fuck up, E.
你別說了 E
- I'm saying...
- Come on, man.
只是說嘛…
How the fuck we suppose
to make a record label and hit records
你說沒有人來唱的話
and we ain't got no talent?
我們怎麼能錄歌出專輯啊？
I mean, you said, hold up my side of
the deal. You said, put some money up.
我說，你讓我停一下老生意，讓我砸點錢
So, it's time for you to deliver.
現在是你應該來想想辦法了
Why don't you do this shit, E?
我看不如直接你來唱
Nah, for real.
Get in there on the mic.
說真的呢，你來麥克風這試試
You ain't got shit to lose.
It's your money. You paying for it.
你沒什麼可以損失的，我們花的是你的錢，你得加入進來
No, I can't. 'Cause I'm not a rapper.
There's your rapper.
我不成，我之前沒說唱過，他才是你們的Rapper
I'm in a group already, man.
我已經加入一個組合了
Jinx and them
would trip on me if I do anything.
我來唱的話，我隊友Jinx就會有意見了
Look, I understand
that you wanna keep throwing your life away
我知道，你想把你的時間都浪費在
with Jinx and the backyard
boogie band or whatever...
你和Jakes的那個小爛樂隊上
But I'm the Berry Gordy of this shit.
但我才是這一行的決策人
So, whenever y'all figure out
what y'all wanna do,
所以你們想好了怎麼做
just let me know.
就告訴我
Come on, man.
Look, the song is about you, E.
這首歌其實就是描寫你的，E
Eazy-motherfuckin'-E. I'm telling you.
描寫的是 Eazy-E，你懂的
Come on, man.
說真的
You the only muthafucka with a 6-4.
你有一輛 64款 黑斑羚
- You got a 6-4?
- I don't have a car.
你有嗎？  - 我都沒車
You got a 6-4?
你有嗎？
I got a po' Porsche, man.
我只有輛破車
Nigga, come on, man.
哥們，你來吧
You ain't doing nothing.
你什麼都沒做呢
But you the business man,
so, you know.
但這是你的生意，哥們
It's on you.
你來決定
We got a cool-ass song, though.
我們寫這歌絕對夠酷
I think you could hit that shit.
我覺得這歌能打出名聲來
I'm not sold, Dre.
我還沒被說服 Dre
Whatchu mean, you not sold?
You just gonna sit there?
你什麼意思，還沒被說服，你就打算一直坐那？
You're kinda being a ho right now, Eric.
Eric 你這樣還真有點像個小婊子
Fuck y'all, niggas.
去你們的
Berry Gordy to save the day.
那就走起來吧，還說什麼
I ain't scared.
我可沒怵
- You ain't scared?
- What's up then?
你沒怕？
<i>What are you doing?</i>
你幹嘛呢？
E, let me produce. Man.
我來製作啊
<i>Feel like it's getting weird.</i>
感覺有點怪啊
Man, shut up and get comfortable.
別說話，你調整一下狀態
Let's go.
開始
<i>Cruisin' down the street in my 6-4.</i>
開著我的 6-4 在街上閑轉悠
Shit.
我去！
The fuck?
我靠
<i>What the fuck is so funny?</i>
你們他媽笑什麼？
<i>Nothing. Oh, E, can you hear me?</i>
沒，沒什麼，E，你能聽到我們？
Yeah, I can hear you
and how much y'all fucking laughing.
當然能聽到，你們笑的聲那麼大
<i>Hey, E, you good.
Just hit that first beat hard, man.</i>
哎 E，你唱的還行，但第一拍要卡住節奏
You gotta come in on beat.
一定要保持卡住節奏
<i>Cruisin' down the street.</i>
開著我的…
You cruisin'.
找開著車的感覺
- You good, Eric.
- All right?
你行的，Eric
No, no, no, no. You good, you good.
沒事，沒事，可以的
It's dope. But on beat.
聲音很好，但要卡住拍子
Again. All right? Let's go.
再來一次，好吧，來
You cruising. All right?
找開著車的感覺
<i>Cruisin' down the street in my 6-4.</i>
開著我的 6-4 在街上閑轉悠
<i>- Shit.
- That ain't it.</i>
靠，還是不行
<i>- It really ain't.
</i>-Hey, hey, Dre.
確實不行
- 嘿，嘿，Dre
He gotta go if we're gonna do this.
Cube, you gotta go.
他們必須出去我能發揮，Cube 你得出去
<i>Get the fuck outta here, Yella.</i>
哈哈你出去吧Yella
<i>- He not talkin' to me.
</i>-Nah, nigga, both of y'all.
他沒說我  - 沒有，我說你倆都出去
<i>You talking to me?</i>
你說我？
<i>- Bye.
</i>-Go, Cube.
拜拜！走吧 Cube
- And Yella, get the fuck outta here, man.
- Me too?
都出去，Yella 也出去  - 我也出去？
Yeah, so we can get this shit done.
嗯，這樣才能唱…
Write the song, Cube.
Shut the fuck up, Cube.
“寫首歌吧，Cube”，“現在閉嘴，Cube”
<i>- Take these with you, Cube.
</i>-What'd I do?
給你倆中指，Cube
- For real?
- Yes, man. Come on.
哎，走吧
You know what? Whatever. Whatever.
啊？那好吧，好吧
You motherfucker.
你們這幫……
<i>- Come on, E.
</i>-You finished, Dre?
好了吧  - 你笑完沒Dre？
<i>You wanna laugh too?
I stay in this bitch by myself.</i>
你還想笑？我自己一人留這好了
Hey, just say the words, ar'ight?
嘿，就照歌詞唱就行了
What does that even mean?
什麼意思？
<i>Man, just say the shit with me.
Ar'ight? Cruisin'.</i>
就跟我學這麼說，開著…
<i>Cruisin'.</i>
開著！
<i>Yeah, "Cruisin'". Let's go.</i>
沒錯，開著… 開始
<i>Dre, you know this shit
ain't gonna never work.</i>
Dre，這麼下去永遠也不行
A'ight. You trying to be funny.
好吧，你又想搞笑了
But, you see how you said that shit, right?
Like you believe it.
不過你看，你說這話的感覺，就是相信你自己的話
<i>Yeah, I believe that shit.</i>
當然了，我自己說的
Then say this shit like
you believe it, man.
所以你唱歌詞的時候也要有底氣
<i>Like it's a motherfuckin' Sunday</i>
就好像一個周日下午
and you cruisin' down Crenshaw
in a motherfuckin' 6-4.
然後你在你的地盤，開著你的雪弗蘭在街上閒逛
<i>Come on. Say that shit like you believe it,
man, like it's your words.</i>
對，就把這些詞當成真實的，就是你自己的話那樣真實
<i>Feel that shit.</i>
想像一下
<i>Stop playing around. Loosen the fuck up.</i>
別鬧了，放鬆一下，找找感覺
<i>There you go.</i>
準備開始
<i>Cruisin' down the street in my 6-4.</i>
開著我的 6-4 在街上閑轉悠
<i>Oh, shit. Hey, that was dope, E.</i>
噢，不錯！帶感啊 E
That shit was dope, man. Yeah.
這句感覺太正了！
<i>That's what I'm talking about, man.</i>
我說的就這意思！
<i>You feelin' that shit, right?</i>
你有沒有找到到這個感覺？
Now we only got 59 more lines
to punch in, but it's all good.
我們現在只剩下59句要錄了，沒事，還好
<i>We gonna get through it.
Let's go on to the next one.</i>
我們繼續幹，開始下一句
#NowPlaying: "Boyz-N-The Hood" by N.W.A
<i>I went to get them out but there was no bail.</i>
我試圖把他們弄出來，但卻居然被禁止保釋了
<i>The fellas causing a riot in the county jail.</i>
因為這傢伙在牢裡也閒不住大掀風雲
<i>Two days later in the municipal court.</i>
兩天之後，庭審日之時
<i>Kilo G on trial cold cut a fart.</i>
庭上 Kilo G 悠然自得，一不留神放了個屁
<i>Destruction of the court said the judge.</i>
法官給他加了條罪狀，藐視法庭
<i>On a six year sentence my man didn't budge.</i>
終審六年監禁，可我的兄弟根本不屌他
<i>Bailiff came over to turn him in.</i>
正當法警起身，準備將他銬起
<i>Kilo G looked up and gave a grin.</i>
Kilo G 卻抬起頭，一咧嘴
<i>He yelled out "fire!" then came Suzy.</i>
大喊“開火”，同案犯 Suzy 突然發難
<i>The bitch came in with a submachine Uzi.</i>
她抱著把烏茲衝鋒槍猛然殺出
<i>Police shot the girl but didn't hurt her.</i>
只惜救駕未果，她亦被逮捕
<i>Both upstate for attempted murder</i>
雙雙被指控謀殺未遂
<i>'Cause the boyz n tha hood are always hard.</i>
但是我們街上的孩子總是這麼凶
<i>You come talking that trash
we'll pull your card.</i>
你若敢來大放厥詞，我們就抽了你的老底兒
<i>Knowing nothing in life but to be legit.</i>
沒什麼文化，但做事的規矩絕對明白
<i>Don't quote me,
boy 'cause I ain't said shit.</i>
嘴巴最好放老實點，別引火上身
Yes.
棒
All right, Eazy.
屌爆了 Eazy!
Hell yes, Dre!
太燥了 Dre!
- Yeah?
- Yes.
是吧  - 沒錯
Hey, D.O.C.
嘿，D.O.C.
Whatchu think, man?
你覺得怎麼樣，哥們？
You think they gonna feel
that shit in Dallas?
你覺得這歌在達拉斯能火嗎
Man, to be honest, man,
that shit is super dope, nigga.
說真的，哥們，這歌太他媽飛了
- Hell yeah!
- For real, nigga.
絕對  - 牛逼，哥們
Hey, Lonzo. Whatchu think?
嘿 Lanzo，你覺得怎麼樣？
Sound like some waste-of-time shit to me.
我感覺你們在浪費時間
Look, trust me, this shit
ain't gonna work, ar'ight?
聽我的，這歌根本不靈
You ain't gonna get no radio play
with that shit right there.
這種破歌根本沒機會上電臺你懂嗎
- Oh, for real?
- Oh, for very real.
真的？  - 那當然，絕對沒錯
Y'all need to wrap this shit up too
你們應該好好考慮考慮
'cause I need you to get back
on that slow jam that we talked about.
應該找找慢歌的感覺
This whole reality of rap
shit y'all tryin' to do.
你們想搞的這種所謂的現實說唱
Talkin' about low-riders and jail,
nobody wanna hear that shit.
說這些社會底層和監獄的東西，有誰願意聽？
Now you need to get back in there and
work on that slow jam that we worked on.
你們還是應該去創作點兒慢歌
And I'm serious
說真的
about all you motherfuckers taking up
my time and that's coming outta your pay.
你們這些混球寫歌佔用的時間，我都要從你們工資裡扣掉
No disrespect, Eazy,
'cause I know you real.
無意冒犯你，E，你是混道上的
But you, motherfucker,
I ain't gonna take that shit from you.
但是你，你搞這種歌，我是不會看好的
20 years from now,
you gonna fucking thank me. Watch.
二十年之後你會感謝我現在的忠告的
Nigga, 20 years
from now, you still gonna be
二十年之後，你還會在這個
recording love songs
in this dusty-ass garage.
破錄音棚裡錄你的慢歌
Fuck outta here.
快別扯了
Wrap this shit up.
滾出我這兒
Yeah. Okay. You got it.
好啊，照做
No, you got it!
不，是你們照做
- Yes!
- I told you. Didn't I tell you?
你看，我說過吧，你還不信
You told me, man. I should've believed you.
沒錯你說過，我應該信你的
What the fuck did you all get from that
that you're high-fiving and shit?
他說這些你們還高興什麼勁兒？
Cube. Man, if Lonzo think
it ain't gonna be shit,
Cube，如果 Lanzo 覺得這歌不行
we know we got a motherfucking hit!
那反而說明這歌一定會火起來
- Exactly.
- For real.
絕對  - 沒錯
'Cause he don't know shit about music.
因為他音樂品位太差勁啦
He don't know good music
when he hears it.
他根本不懂音樂哈
Play that shit again!
來，再放一遍
Dre...
You a fucking genius. You a fucking genius.
你這個天才，你真是天才
<i>Went to the park to get the scoop.</i>
去趟公園和我的哥們碰頭
<i>Knuckleheads out there
cold shooting some hoops.</i>
他們正在那的籃球場打球
<i>A car pulls up
Who can it be?</i>
看遠遠的是誰來了？
<i>A fresh El Camino rollin', Kilo G.</i>
Kilo G 駕著他的全新的肌肉車
El Camino 經典的美式肌肉車
<i>He rolled down his window
And he started to say.</i>
搖下窗戶，跟兄弟們說
<i>It's all about makin' that GTA</i>
俠盜飛車不過和我們如出一轍
G.T.A: grand theft auto,意思是這輛新車是偷來的
<i>'Cause the boyz n tha hood are always hard.</i>
因為我們街上的孩子總是這麼凶
<i>You come talking that trash
we'll pull your card.</i>
你若敢來大放厥詞，我們就抽了你的老底兒
<i>Knowing nothing in life but to be legit.</i>
沒什麼文化，但做事的規矩絕對明白
<i>Don't quote me,
boy 'cause I ain't said shit.</i>
嘴巴最好放老實點，別引火上身
Thank you.
謝謝
These phones are burning up.
我們的熱線都快被打爆了
This is 1580 KDAY.
這裡是 1580Hz，KDAY電臺
This is Greg Mack with the Mack Attack,
我是Mack Attack節目主持人 Greg Mack
and I gotta give it up to my boy, Dr. Dre,
下麵是我不得不說的，我的哥們 Dr.Dre
who is coming
with Compton's very own Eazy-E.
還有來自我們康普頓的Eazy-E
<i>And you're listening to</i> Boyz-N-The Hood
送上這首單曲，Boyz In The Hood
<i>the number-one requested song</i>
持續六周的熱門
<i>for six weeks and counting.</i>
點播率最高的單曲
Ar'ight. Guess I'll see you soon.
好了，估計我們還很快會再拿貨
Excuse me.
你好
- Yeah?
- I heard your record.
嗯？  - 我聽了你的唱片
I'm Jerry Heller.
我叫 Jerry Heller
Eric Wright.
我是 Eric Wright
Real pleasure to meet you, man.
真的很高興見到你
Same here.
我也是
Uh, would it...
呃，你能…
Here, let me get those for you.
Let me get those for you.
讓我幫你拿吧，我幫你拿
Would it be possible
to have a word with you for a second, Eric?
我們可以私下談一談嗎 Eric?
About what?
談什麼？
About music.
談音樂
After you.
帶路
All right. Come on.
好的，走吧
So, I thought your album was good, man.
我真的覺得你的音樂很不錯
Just good?
不錯？
Mmm.
嗯
Hey, hey, hey, hey! No.
嘿，嘿，嘿，嘿！不是
I thought it was exceptional.
我是說，挺棒的
- Exceptional?
- Yes.
挺棒？  - 對
Fantastic.
Please, just sit down, all right?
非常出色，請坐
We'll start this again. Come on.
請坐，咱再談談
All right. I'm gonna try this again. Okay?
好，我重新說一下
All right.
好
As a music manager, let me tell
you what I can do for you, Eric.
作為音樂經紀人，讓我跟你說一下我能為你做什麼，Eric
I will make you legit.
我能讓你走上正軌
It seems as if I could
do something for you.
其實看來好像是我能幫你的忙
I see. You think because
I don't have some flashy office
我知道，你以為我這辦公室不是什麼豪華的地方
I don't know what I'm talking about?
所以我在跟你裝腔作勢？
I worked with Elton John.
I worked with Otis Redding.
我和 Elton John, Otis Redding 都有過合作
Let me see.
I worked with War. I worked with Styx.
我還有跟… War 樂隊，Styx 樂隊…
- I worked with, uh...
- Have you worked with anybody this decade?
我還跟……  - 你有跟這個年代的人合作過嗎？
Okay.
好吧
Let me tell you what I see here, Eric.
跟你描述一下我看到的現實
A lot of raw talent, a lot of braggadocio.
我看到太多地下藝人喜歡自吹自擂
Bravado. Uh...
掀點小風浪
But if you think anyone's
gonna talk to you,
但你覺得會有什麼人會主動發現你
you think anyone
is gonna let you in the building
會有什麼人讓你進入主流大眾的視線
where somebody might listen to you or talk
to you, you think that's gonna happen?
或者什麼機遇會輕易找上你，你覺得自己闖有這樣的機會？
You're crazy, man. I'm sorry.
那抱歉，你沒戲
That is what I can do for you.
但我可以幫你做到
I can make you legit.
我可以帶你走上正軌
I can get you in that building.
And I will protect you.
帶你進入主流，而且我可以保護你
I will block out all the noise
of this crazy fuckin' business
我會去遮罩那些雜亂的反對的聲音
and we can build something big.
我們就可以做成大事
But you gotta believe in me
the way that I believe in you.
但你必須像我信任你一樣信任我
The way that I believe in this,
像我相信這張專輯的實力一樣
because you have a unique talent, Eric.
因為你的天賦是獨一無二的，Eric
Very special.
非常出色
Don't fuck around.
別浪費掉機會
But, you know what?
這樣吧
If you can't handle it,
如果你覺得這事兒
if it's too much fuckin' pressure
for you, then fine.
對你來說還太大，壓力太大，也沒事
Get outta here.
你走吧
Wait. I'm listening.
等等，我在考慮
You got more music for me?
你能給我更多音樂嗎
- Absolutely.
- Good.
那必須的  - 那好
'Cause you are gonna
have to follow this up, quick. All right?
因為你需要跟著這股勁繼續出歌
Now, what does N.W.A stand for, huh?
你們這個 N.W.A. 是什麼意思？
No Whites Allowed? Something like that?
白人都靠邊站？這意思嗎
Nah.
不是
Niggas With Attitudes.
有思想的黑人
You're fucking kidding me.
你不是在逗我吧？
All right. We can work with that.
嗯，行吧，我們做做試試
- Good. I like that. I like that a lot.
- You better.
好，我喜歡，有性格，我很喜歡  -  必須的
Fantastic.
太棒了
非常棒
#NowPlaying: "(Not Just) Knee Deep - Original" by Funkadelic
What up, what up? What's up, fam?
大家好嗎，大家好，大家好
- Hey.
- What's up, baby?
嘿  - 你好啊
Dre.
Dre
Hey, fellas, y'all got any idea
嘿，哥幾個，你們知道
why I asked y'all to
wear all black tonight?
為什麼我讓大家都穿一身黑嗎？
'Cause we a all-star group.
因為我們是全明星組合
And to be a all-star group
要當全明星組合
we gotta look like it,
要看著像
sound like it, dress like it.
聽著要像，穿的也要像
You mind tellin' me
what the fuck happened in your situation?
你能告訴我，你他媽這是什麼情況嗎？
Man, kiss my ass.
This the only clean shit I had left.
哥們得了吧，我就這件乾淨衣服
That's saying a lot
about how you live.
你瞧你這德行
Are we getting paid to wear all black?
我們不穿全黑的衣服就沒報酬嗎？
Look, I ain't lookin' out for your ass
no more, man. Put this on.
得了，我下次不管你了，穿上這件
Oh, shit, there go Mr. Drummond.
哎，看肯德基爺爺來了
Nah, nah. That's Mr. Furley
不是不是，我看他像弗利大叔
from <i>Three's Company.</i>
《三人行》裡面的那個
Hey, that's good, Ren.
哈哈說得好
Y'all finished?
你們笑完沒？
This man been out there
shopping our stuff around
他幫我們忙前忙後採購演出需要的東西
trying to get money for Ruthless.
想法子幫我們 Ruthless 唱片賺錢
He tryin' to get us distribution.
他幫我們組織唱片發售
He tryin' to get us on tour.
他幫我們組織這個巡迴演出
He could probably bring some real money
他能幫我們賺到大錢
- to the table...
- Okay.
賺大錢  - 好
- So let's take this shit serious.
- Okay.
所以我們態度也認真點兒  - 好的
And then what, E?
那然後呢 E?
All he do is take 20 off the top.
We cut 80, but that's how managers work.
他只是從收入裡抽掉兩成，我們拿八成，這是他作為經紀人的工作報酬
Fellas, all right. I'm sorry I'm late.
How's everybody doing?
不好意思我來晚了，大家準備的怎麼樣了
I'm gonna be honest with you.
We've had a lot of passes.
實話說，找投資的事兒我們錯過了幾個機會
Uh, people are scared of you guys.
Big time.
投資人比較怕你們組合，非常怕
They think that you're dangerous.
他們覺得你們太危險
Uh, I happen to think
that that's a good thing.
但我覺得這種害怕反而是好事兒
These fucking guys,
they need some more convincing.
這些人還需要一些感染力，說服力
They're so fucking timid.
So I invited them here to the show.
他們太謹慎了，所以我乾脆邀請他們來看現場了
So you've got to kick ass tonight.
所以你們今晚表現必須超一流
- Can you do that?
- Hell yeah.
能搞定嗎？  - 沒問題
They're gonna be here.
Scare the shit out of them.
他們會在現場看，用實力震住他們
Blow the fucking roof off, all right?
燥翻這個現場
Have a good show.
好好表現
Hey, can this motherfucker
嘿，這個 Jerry
Jerry Heller bring in more pussy?
能給我們帶幾個妞兒過來嗎？
'Cause that shit's worth 20 percent.
能的話，我看就值兩成
Hey, man. But, for real though.
They want N.W.A, let's give 'em N.W.A.
嘿，說正經的，他們想要 N.W.A，我們就要表現得更像 N.W.A
Hell yeah!
絕對沒錯
- Ar'ight?
- Ar'ight.
行嗎？，行！
Let's go get this money!
一塊開始賺大錢
<i>Now everybody say, "Yeah!"</i>
大家一起來！
Yeah!
耶！
<i>Hell yeah!</i>
沒錯！
Hell yeah!
<i>Louder! Scream!</i>
大聲點！尖叫！
#Rap: "Dopeman" by N.W.A
<i>It was once said by a
man who couldn't quit.</i>
從前有個癮君子說
<i>Dope man, please can I have another hit.</i>
毒販大哥，能讓我再吸一口嗎
<i>The dopeman said,
"Cluck, I don't give a shit".</i>
毒販子說：我他媽才不管你
<i>If your girl kneel down and suck my dick.</i>
除非叫你的女人過來給哥跪舔
<i>It all happened and the
guy tried to choke her.</i>
所以就這麼發生了，她差點被嗆死
<i>Nigga didn't care
she ain't nothin' but a smoker.</i>
沒人同情，因為她也是個煙鬼
<i>That's the way it goes
that's the name of the game.</i>
一切就這麼繼續，這就是街頭的遊戲
<i>Young brothers gettin'
over by slangin' caine.</i>
年輕的孩子靠賣可卡因致富
<i>Gold around his neck in 14K heaven.</i>
他帶著14k的金鏈來炫富
<i>Bitches clockin' on the dick 24/7.</i>
女人們整日整夜騎在他的下面
<i>Plus he's makin' money
keep the bassheads waitin'.</i>
他從那些苦苦等待的癮君子身上賺錢
<i>Rollin' six-fos with the fresh-ass Daytons.</i>
坐著經典64 Impala，嶄新的Dayton輪轂
<i>Livin' in Compton California, C-A.</i>
享受生活，住在加州的康普頓
<i>His Uzi up your ass if he don't get paid.</i>
如果你沒付錢，他會用衝鋒槍討債
<i>Niggas beggin' for credit
he's knockin' out teeth.</i>
想要賒帳的哥們被打的滿地找牙
<i>Clockin' much dollars
on the first and fifteenth.</i>
在政府救濟金發放的日子他會大賺特賺
很多癮君子都非常窮，用救濟金買毒品
<i>Big wad of money nuttin' less than a 20.</i>
全都是大票子，面值都20塊以上
<i>Yeah, you want a five-oh
the dopeman's got plenty.</i>
喲，你要找員警？毒販子早已都買通
<i>To be a dopeman boy, you must qualify.</i>
想要成為毒販，你必須夠資格
<i>Don't get high off your own supply.</i>
永遠不要在你自己的貨上嗨
<i>From a ki to a G it's all about money.</i>
從賣克到千克都是綠油油的鈔票
<i>Ten piece for a champ base pipe comes free.</i>
要是一次買的夠多，他送你個煙斗
<i>If people out there are
not hip to the fact.</i>
很多人還不能理解這個事實
<i>If you see somebody gettin'
money for crack he's the.</i>
如果你看到誰從毒品掙錢，他就是
<i>Dopeman! Dopeman!
Sing that shit.</i>
毒販，毒販！大家一起唱
<i>Dopeman! Dopeman!
Louder.</i>
毒販，毒販！大點聲
<i>Dopeman! Dopeman!
Just can't quit.</i>
毒販，毒販！沒法金盆洗手
<i>Dopeman! Dopeman.</i>
毒販，毒販！
<i>Hey, suck this, bitch.</i>
來跪舔吧！
<i>Well, I'm the dopeman
Yeah, boy, I wear corduroy.</i>
沒錯我就是毒販，習慣穿條絨襯衫
<i>Money up to here, but unemployed.</i>
我賺的錢特多，但是不用上班
<i>You keep smoking that rock and
my pocket's getting bigger.</i>
只要你們一直吸粉兒，我的錢包就更鼓了
<i>Yo, got that five-o
Double up, nigga.</i>
給你五盎司，價格要翻一倍
<i>Yeah, high rolling, big money I'm folding.</i>
花錢如流水，我的進賬更是快
<i>Bitch on my tip for the dick I'm holdin'.</i>
沒錢的婊子們如果想吸點兒
<i>Strung strawberry jocking me so early.</i>
那就得學會各種花樣討好我
<i>Ho, you want a hit,
you gotta get your knees dirty.</i>
想來一包？可能需要給我跪舔
<i>Well, that's my life
That's how it's cut.</i>
沒錯這就是我的生活，我的生意
<i>- Hey, dopeman.
- Bitch, shut the fuck up.</i>
嘿，毒販！ 婊子們都閉嘴
<i>Gotta make a run
It's a big money deal.</i>
我得行動起來，才能賺得更快
<i>Gankers got the fake,
but you can get the real from the.</i>
搶劫犯都太沒勁了，想要玩真的，那就找…
<i>- Dopeman! Dopeman!
- Yeah, that's me.</i>
毒販，毒販！沒錯，就是我！
<i>- Dopeman! Dopeman!
- Can I get a "g"?</i>
毒販，毒販！能不能再來點？
<i>- Dopeman! Dopeman!
- I just can't quit.</i>
毒販，毒販！沒法金盆洗手！
What do you think?
你覺得怎麼樣？
Jerry, you're my friend,
Jerry 我們是朋友
but Compton? I don't think so.
Queens, maybe.
Compton這地方，感覺不靠譜，紐約皇后區可能還好點兒
Listen, if you find
the next Bon Jovi, call me, okay?
如果你能發現下一個 Bon Jovi 再告訴我吧
- Good luck.
- Thanks for coming.
祝你好運  - 多謝你能過來
- Sure thing.
- Yeah.
沒事  - 好
<i>Somebody say "Do that shit
Do that shit, do it".</i>
跟我說：“走起來，走起來，走起”
<i>Do that shit, do that shit, do it.</i>
“走起來，走起來，走起”
<i>Say, "Do that shit, do that shit, do it".</i>
說：“走起來，走起來，走起”
<i>Do that shit, do that shit, do it.</i>
“走起來，走起來，走起”
<i>Say, "Do that shit, do that shit, do it".</i>
說：“走起來，走起來，走起”
<i>Do that shit, do that shit, do it.</i>
“走起來，走起來，走起”
All right.
來了
You wrecked
these motherfuckers tonight, boy.
你們今晚真是燥翻現場了
The stage was shaking so much I thought
my needle's about to jump off the record!
演出舞臺顛的太猛，我感覺唱片都快滑掉了
Yo, I was trippin' off them knowing the
words, though. That shit was crazy.
喲，我沒想到觀眾都會唱我們的歌詞，太爽了
Hey, y'all, I'm telling you,
Compton is definitely on the map, yo.
嘿，Compton這下絕對殺入說唱圈地圖了
- Damn right.
- That's for damn sure.
絕對沒錯  - 那必須沒錯
Man, I figured you were gonna represent
tonight. Good shit, my nigga.
哥們，我就知道你今晚表現一定特別棒
Wuddup? Whatchu been up to?
You still out there in Vegas?
嘿，哥們你最近忙什麼呢，你還在拉斯維加斯忙呢？
- This is Suge.
- What's up?
這位是 Suge  - 你好
Man, I just been back and forth, man.
Doing some security bodyguard work.
我一直是各地奔波，做點兒什麼保鏢類的工作
If y'all need my services, let me know.
你如果需要這方面工作，記得找我
Security?
保鏢？
I don't think we gonna need
no bodyguards, man.
我覺得我們還不太需要
We might got that covered.
我們自己罩得住
But you never know
what you need until you need it.
但你預測不到什麼時候你會需要保護
Look, I just came here to give y'all props.
I got people waiting on me.
就是過來打個招呼，表演太棒了，還有人在等我，先走了
Excuse me.
插個話…
Uh, okay. That was
這場演出……
one hell of a show.
真的太棒了
Nice job.
表現棒極了
Very, very nice, gentlemen. Outstanding!
非常非常好，極其出色
You kicked ass, yeah.
You definitely did. You definitely did.
今晚表演太酷了，絕對的，絕對的
Okay, this is Eazy-E and N.W.A, obviously.
嗯，這位是 Eazy-E. 和 N.W.A. 組合
Guys, this is Bryan Turner.
各位，這位是 Bryan Turner
- How you doin', fellas?
- Ice Cube.
大家好  -  我是 Ice Cube
- Pleasure.
- Bryan runs Priority Records.
你好  - Briain 是優選唱片公司老總
And he wants to sign you.
他想簽約你們
Yeah, immediately.
對，越快越好
Fellas, I got to say, I loved the show.
All right?
各位，我必須要說今天的演出太精彩了
What you did with that crowd out there,
I mean, I've never seen anything like that.
你們跟觀眾的互動效果也非常棒，之前從沒見過這麼有特色的現場演出
So, I think, honestly,
if y'all wanted to, you guys
所以誠懇的說，如果你們願意
- would fit perfectly with our label.
- Yes.
非常歡迎加入我們唱片公司  - 好啊
That'll work.
可以啊
Nah, nah, nah, nah. No, it won't. Nah.
啊，不，不，等等
Well, hold on, man.
I mean, Priority Records.
等一下，我是說，優選唱片
I've never heard of it.
I mean, what you got?
我從來沒聽過啊，你們簽約了誰？
Like, is it Def Jam?
Like, the Beastie Boys? You know?
你們是不是像 Def Jam這種大公司？大牌組合例如 Beastie Boys?
Run DMC? You know what I'm saying?
有沒有簽約類似 Run DMC 這類說唱組合
Or is it more R&B?
或者說更加偏向 R&B?
You know, Prince, Michael Jackson.
比如 Prince啊, Michael Jackson啊這些明星
- It's, uh, a little more...
呃，這個嘛……
- More R&B as of right now, but...
- Yeah.
我們簽約的，大部分是 R&B 歌手  - 嗯對
Yeah, we represent nothing big,
對，不過目前沒有太大牌的
but mostly R&B.
大部分是 R&B 歌手
Who dat?
都是誰呢
It's, uh, California Raisins.
呃，有加州葡萄乾
Who?
誰？
It's the California Raisins.
加州葡萄乾
The raisins from the commercial singing.
是那個給葡萄飲料做廣告的
"I Heard it Through the
Grapevine" and shit?
唱葡萄乾之歌的動畫樂隊？
Yes, Cube, the little-ass raisins.
啊會唱歌的葡萄乾？
That would be the one.
嗯就是那個
Hear it out.
Don't get ahead of yourselves, okay?
大家注意一下別笑這麼誇張
I was laughing, too,
I promise, then I started cashing checks.
我也覺得挺逗，不過不管怎麼樣，他們很賺錢
So, look, I gotta tell ya, those little
fuckers, they went gold last year.
我不得不說，“小葡萄乾”他們去年唱片銷量達到了黃金
- Gold?
- Almost platinum. Yeah.
黃金？ -  就快達到白金唱片級別了
What do you say, fellas?
You wanna go make a record?
你們覺得怎麼樣？你們想不想也錄一張專輯？
I mean...
我想……
- Yeah!
- Yeah...
當然要啊  - 當然要
- Thank you. Appreciate it.
- Good?
謝謝你  - 怎麼樣
He seriously dug it. He really dug it.
他真的喜歡你們的音樂，是真的欣賞
- We did it, Jerry.
- He did.
太好了，我們做到了  -  嗯
- Thank you, man.
- You did it.
謝謝你  -  是你做到的
Straight Outta Compton 專輯錄製階段
A'ight, so, look, your rhymes ain't tight,
it ain't makin' the record.
大家聽好，如果我們的押韻不精彩，作品就算不上好
This ain't Lonzo's shit,
this the real deal. Ar'ight?
這可不是我們在後臺隨便錄的那些歌
So your shit better be dope. Who up?
所以大家的唱段要玩的更牛，誰先來
Ren up.
Ren 先來
- Get 'em, Ren.
- Get that shit, Ren.
來一段 Ren  -  走起來 Ren
- I got this. Ready?
- Lorenzo.
準備好了，沒問題
All right. Let's see.
好嘞，來吧
Hey, Yella. Play that shit.
嘿 Yella，放節奏
<i>Ruthless, plenty of that and much more.</i>
冷酷無情，這是我們的廠牌的標記
<i>So at the party,
Ren is controllin' the floor.</i>
所以即使在Party，也是我MC Ren在掌控全域
<i>That you step and do your dance routine
It ain't a dream, my man.</i>
你的舞步和你的節奏都被我操縱，這不是夢境
<i>You're in a gangsta scene.</i>
你現在置身黑幫場景
<i>I go to the party
I hip, I hop the spot.</i>
在這HIP-HOP的街拍下，我盡情發揮
<i>I dunno what it is but the girls get hot.</i>
不知道是什麼魔力，就讓姑娘們都嗨了
<i>Perspirin' like they're on fire and.</i>
讓美女們都濕身起舞，這裡好像熱帶雨林
<i>Their so-called boyfriends
with 'em are retirin'.</i>
我讓她們的所謂男友都提前退休
<i>And for this reason I'm a walkin' threat.</i>
就是這個原因，我是你們的最大威脅
<i>So when I'm on stage I want, shh...</i>
所以當我這樣的巨星登場
<i>Quiet on tha set.</i>
我要你們保持肅靜
<i>Express yourself.</i>
表達自己！
<i>I'm expressin' with my full capabilities.</i>
我不遺餘力的表達自己
<i>And now I'm livin' in
correctional facilities</i>
然而現在我活在勞改所裡
<i>'Cause some don't agree with how I do this
I get straight meditate like a Buddhist.</i>
因為有些人對我的行為不太順眼，實話講，我像佛教徒一樣冥想
<i>Express yourself.</i>
表達自己！
<i>N.W.A take two.</i>
N.W.A 第二段
Yeah!
耶
Hell yeah, Dre.
牛逼，Dre
Yeah, man!
太酷了
You feel that shit, right?
Hey, check this out.
感覺到了吧？你聽聽
Fuck it up.
給勁兒
Yeah.
耶
That's what I'm talking about, man.
But you hear the difference, right?
你們也感覺到區別了是吧？
Yeah, way better than the shit
I came up with.
比我剛開始做的那個效果強多了
- I know.
- Fuck you.
那是啊  - 去你的
Excuse me, gentlemen.
I thought you'd like to know
打擾一下各位，我想應該告訴大家一下
our deal with Priority Records is done.
我們和優選唱片公司的合同準備好了
- Yes! That's whassup, man!
- Money!
那太棒啦  - 賺錢了
Contracts right here for you to sign.
這些檔是需要你簽字的
- Thank you, my good man.
- Music keep sounding like this,
謝謝你了  - 我們的音樂這麼棒
this album is gonna be incredible.
這張專輯一定會超火爆的
Well, you're welcome, Jerry.
嗯，不客氣哈 Jerry
Very strong lyrics too, Cube. Very strong.
歌詞也非常有力量，Cube，非常棒
- Appreciate that, Jerry.
- Mmm-hmm.
謝了 Jerry  -  嗯嗯
So what's up with our contracts, though?
那我們幾個的合約呢？
They're getting done right now.
Lawyers are drawing 'em up.
也都快弄好了，律師們正在準備
Jerry on top of that,
but did you just switch all the straws?
嗯，Jerry盯著這事兒呢，你們放心吧不用催了
Yo, Dre. There's something outside
you need to take care of.
哥們，有點事你得出來處理一下
Right now. Trust me.
真的，馬上
Serious.
正經事
Uh-oh. Really?
哦是嗎？
- We can split that.
- Cube. Right there, hush.
我們可以分這個  - Cube，在那呢，別吵
- Not this time.
- You know what I got for you.
別在這會兒啊  - 你看我這有什麼
So let me get this straight.
You gonna do this right here, right now?
說真的，你非要現在在這跟我說這個？
What am I supposed to do?
那你要我怎麼辦？
We're sleeping in a twin bed
at your auntie's house.
我跟女兒在你小姨家都寄宿了多久了？
We have a baby, Andre.
我們有孩子的，Andre
You expect me to wait
for what you doin' in there?
你還期望我一直等你忙你自己的事？
And you in the streets fuckin' around?
你忙什麼了，不過是在街頭閑混
- Are you crazy?
- What?
你瘋啦？  - 什麼？
I'm out here bustin' my fuckin' ass
我在這走不開
day and fuckin' night
tryin' to create something.
沒日沒夜的忙著創作東西
You gonna come up in here talkin' about
some fuckin' bitches? Are you crazy?
你過來只會叨叨我，我看你才是瘋了
- You don't get it.
- No, you don't get it, Lavetta.
你跟本沒明白  - 不，是你不明白 Lavetta
Daddy!
爹地…
It's all right, baby.
沒事的，寶貝
Chill out, man.
別說了你
Tyra, it's gonna be okay. All right.
Tyra，一切會好起來的，好嗎
- All right, baby?
- Bye, Dre.
好嗎，寶貝  -  拜，Dre
Daddy love you.
老爸愛你
- You cool?
- Fuck no, man. I'm far from cool.
你還好嗎？  - 去他媽的，煩死了
- What happened, Dre? What she say?
- What'd you do?
出什麼事了，她說什麼了？你怎麼她了
Shit! Here we go again.
我靠又來了
Shit. One time, one time.
我靠，條子，是條子
We cool. We ain't even doin' shit.
We not doin' shit.
沒事，我們又沒搞事，我們沒事兒
You guys lost?
你們迷路了？
Nah.
沒啊
You niggas supposed to be somewhere?
你們是應該出現在這嗎？
Yeah! Here. We working.
是啊，我們在這工作
Oh, you working?
哦，在這工作？
Yeah, I bet.
哼，看樣子還真是
- What we do?
- We'll find out in a minute what you did.
我們幹什麼了？
-  一會就查出來了
- What's this?
- Shut the fuck up.
你這什麼意思？
-  閉嘴
- The fuck?
- Get your ass on the ground now.
搞什麼？
- 給我趴到地上
Get on the ground!
給我趴到地上
On the ground?
What am I supposed to do with this?
趴地上？我還拿著東西呢
Get on the ground.
給我趴到地上
What we do?
我們犯什麼事了？
Get down! Get on the ground, now!
都趴下，趴地上！馬上！
Get your punk ass on the ground. Let's go.
你們幾個小混蛋，都趴地上
Get the fuck down.
快點趴下
Hands behind your back.
Interlock your fingers.
手放到背後，十指扣緊
- This is fucked up.
- Interlock 'em!
真混蛋
- 十指扣緊！
The fuck you got us
on the ground like this for, officer?
我們什麼也沒幹
-  警官，為什麼非要讓我們這樣？
For our protection.
There's seven of you and four of us.
這叫保護安全，你們七個人，我們四個要保護自己安全
So sit tight and let us do our job.
趴好別動，別妨礙我們的工作
Hey, officer, I'm sorry.
What is going on out here?
嘿，警官先生，這是怎麼了？
Sir, can you stay right there, please?
先生，請你別過來
We're trying to check these bangers,
make sure they're clean.
我們正檢查這幾個小混混，確保他們沒有威脅
All right, I'm sorry,
these are not bangers, okay?
哦不好意思，他們不是混混
These, um... These are artists.
他們，呃，他們是藝人
- Excuse me. Artists?
- Yeah.
什麼，他們是藝人？  - 是啊
- Seriously?
- Yeah.
說真的？  - 真的是
- What kind of artists?
- Rappers.
什麼藝人啊？  - 說唱歌手
And they're working with me
in the studio right now.
他們在我的工作室錄音
Well, see, rap is not an art.
And I'm sorry, who are you?
我告訴你，說唱不算藝術，還有，你誰啊
I'm the manager.
我是經紀人
Well, you're wasting your time,
Mr. Manager.
好吧，我告訴你，經紀人先生，你在浪費時間
- You gotta be kidding me.
- You're wasting your time.
你在開玩笑吧？  - 你在浪費你的時間
- Really?
- These clients of yours, these rappers...
真的嗎？  - 你的這些客戶，這些所謂說唱歌手
- Yeah.
- They look like gang members.
嗯  -  他們看起來就像黑幫混混
You can't come down here and arrest people
just because of what they look like.
你不能憑別人的打扮就逮捕人啊
What, are you crazy?
But, that's police harassment.
你瘋了嗎，這是非法的警方騷擾
- You said you're a manager, right?
- Yeah.
你說你是經紀人對嗎  - 是啊
- Not a fuckin' lawyer.
- Does that matter?
你他媽又不是律師
-  這有關係嗎？
You cannot come down here
and harass these guys
你們不能跑來這地方，因為他們是黑人
- because they're black! People have rights!
- Calm down.
就逮捕他們啊，人們有人權的！  - 冷靜點
Step back! Step back!
你退後！退後！
I'll step back, you let them up.
Get up, guys.
我這就退後，你讓他們起來  - 你們起來吧
Come on. Eric!
起來啊 Eric!
- You don't tell them to get up.
- Get up.
這兒輪不到你叫他們起來  -  起來
- I'm stepping back.
- We will decide that.
我這就退後  - 這裡由我們來做決定
You have no idea the people I know.
I'm gonna call the Mayor's office.
你們根本不知道我都認識什麼關係，我可以給市長辦公室打電話
Step back.
退後
Now get up.
現在起來吧
Get up, now!
都起來啊！
Okay. Come on, guys.
好，起來吧
And you keep your people in line,
you understand?
你要看好這幾個人，明白嗎
And the fuck out of Torrance.
滾出 Torrence 區
- Good. Come on, guys.
- You got a problem?
好了，走吧  - 你有什麼問題？
It's my jersey.
弄髒我的外套了
You ain't tough now, huh?
現在不凶了？
Eric, come on. Let's go.
Eric 走吧，我們走
- You got a problem?
- Yella.
你想找麻煩嗎？- Yella.
- I didn't hear you.
- Let's go.
我沒聽見  - 走吧
- Yous a fuckin' sellout.
- Shut up.
媽的，陷害我們  - 閉嘴
- Everything's fine. Okay?
- Yeah.
好了沒事了  - 嗯
- You got something to say?
- Cube.
你有什麼想說的嗎  -  Cube.
You got something to say, boy?
小夥，你有什麼想說的？
Cube. Get inside. Let's get back to work.
Cube 我們快回屋，回去繼續工作
You heard what your master said.
Get inside, boy.
你聽見你主人說的了嗎？進屋去
You shut the fuck up!
你給我閉嘴！
Hey. Get the fuck back inside.
嘿，給我滾進屋去
Get inside, Cube.
咱們進屋 Cube
We're gonna go back and work. Okay?
我們回去繼續工作，好吧？
Leave us alone. You know, leave us alone.
別來招我們，行吧？別找我們麻煩
Fuckin' rap music.
去他媽的說唱音樂
Fuckin' disgraceful.
你們這幫人真沒點尊重
I got something for this beat.
我又寫了一點東西
Hey, yo, Yella, cut it.
嘿 Yella 音樂停一下
What is it lookin' like, Dre? It's hard?
怎麼樣，Dre，夠硬嗎？
Yo.
喲
- Hell yeah, Cube.
- Yeah.
絕對夠硬 Cube
This gonna start some shit,
but this what we need. Hell yeah!
這歌絕對會把話題搞大的，絕對獨一無二
#Rap: "Fuck tha Police" by N.W.A
<i>Fuck the police
comin' straight from the underground.</i>
去他媽的員警，我們是純正的來自地下
<i>A young nigga got it bad 'cause I'm brown.</i>
總被人黑，因為皮膚是黑色
<i>And not the other color so police think.</i>
我們不是白色所以被員警歧視
<i>They have the authority to kill a minority.</i>
他們認為有權去殺戮一個我們這個群體
<i>Fuck that shit, 'cause I ain't the one.</i>
去他媽的，因為我才不會逆來順受
<i>For a punk motherfucker
with a badge and a gun.</i>
他們帶著警徽和槍就能橫行霸道
<i>To be beaten on and thrown in jail.</i>
看誰不爽揍一頓，再扔進監獄
<i>We can go toe to toe in
the middle of a cell.</i>
在同一個牢房裡我倆可以“慢慢反省”
<i>Fucking with me 'cause I'm a teenager.</i>
看我不順眼，只因為我還年輕
<i>With a little bit of gold and a pager.</i>
因為我有點錢，還帶著BP機
當時很多毒販通過傳呼聯繫
<i>Searching my car looking for the product.</i>
就可以搜我的車，看看我是否帶了貨
<i>Thinking every nigga is selling narcotics.</i>
他們認為每個黑人都他媽的在販毒
#Rap: "Straight Outta Compton" by N.W.A
<i>Give a little gust of wind and I'm jetting</i>
當你感受到耳邊有狂風吹過，那就是我離開的訊號
<i>but leave a memory no one'll be forgetting.</i>
我給你們留下了永世不能磨滅的記憶
<i>So what about the bitch
who got shot? Fuck her!</i>
你說那個中槍的賤貨咋樣了？去她媽的
<i>You think I give a damn
about a bitch? I ain't a sucker!</i>
你覺得我關心一個臭婊子？我還沒那麼低端
<i>This is the autobiography of the E</i>
這就像是是Eazy-E的自傳
<i>and if you ever fuck with me.</i>
如果你敢跟我做對
<i>You'll get taken by a stupid
dope brother who will smother.</i>
你就會被一個心狠手辣的哥們給幹掉
<i>Word to the motherfucker.</i>
那些不老實的傢伙聽好了
<i>Straight outta Compton.</i>
哥是康普頓混出來的！
#NowPlaying: "Gangsta Gangsta" by N.W.A
- Yo, Dre.
- Hey, Dre.
喲 Dre  -  嘿
- They lovin' that shit.
- Hey, what's up, Cube?
他們喜歡這張唱片  - 你好啊，Cube
<i>1580 KDAY.
This is Greg Mack of the Mack Attack.</i>
這裡是1580Hz KDAY電臺，我是主持人 Greg Mack
<i>I gotta tell you,
you are witnessing history.</i>
必須得跟你們說，你們正在見證歷史
<i>LA's first super group, N.W.A, with
their new album</i> Straight Outta Compton,
洛杉磯的第一個超級組合N.W.A.憑藉新專輯《Straight Outta Compton》
<i>and they're taking the nation by storm.</i>
正在以風暴之勢席捲全國
Are you going
out there with them or not?
你到底跟不跟他們一塊去巡演？
No. I had enough of that shit in the '70s.
不了，70年代的時候我就受夠陪藝人巡演了
But I'm gonna fly out there a bunch of
times, and I'm gonna check on them.
不過我會飛過去幾次，看看他們的狀態保證不出亂子
Can you just make sure
that everything goes smooth, please?
你能保證巡演一切都妥妥當當嗎？
Of course.
沒問題
I've got enough bad press
with Tipper Gore and the PMRC on my ass.
我這邊可是承受了挺多和諧音樂組織的壓力
I know. It's a good contract.
我知道，那是個好合約
- Getting ready to get outta here, guys.
- Excuse me. What's going on?
準備好要出發了我們
- 等一下，怎麼回事？
What do you have in that bag?
你這個包裡是什麼？
Oh, this right here?
噢，這個包裡？
Just a little of the shit
I was selling in Reno.
這是我在外面買的一點小玩具
- Oh, fuck, put it down.
- Are you kidding me?
哎，快放下  -  開什麼玩笑
Are you fucking nuts?
你瘋了啊？
Jesus, Eric. Are you out of your mind?
老天，Eric 你真瘋了嗎？
- What?
- You can't take that on the bus.
什麼？  - 這東西你怎麼能帶上巡演大巴
How am I supposed to protect myself
when I'm out there on the road
那我們在巡演路上靠什麼保護自己？
riding through Texas and fucking Tennessee
and shit where they lynch niggas?
路過德克薩斯，田納西這些種族歧視嚴重的破地方
- You got me?
- I got you, okay?
你明白嗎？  -  我瞭解
I'm not gonna let you take
an arsenal on tour, Eric.
不過我還是不能讓你帶重武器去巡演啊
Use your fucking head.
你動動腦子想想
Jerry, look, just take care
of the business, a'ight?
Jerry 你就管好我們的事業就行了
And I'm gonna make sure
everything else good.
然後我會保證其他事兒都順順利利
A'ight, look... Otis, get the bags.
Put them on the van.
好的，哎，Otis 把這些包放到小車裡
You feel better? We're not even riding
with them no more, Jerry.
感覺好點沒？ 我們又不是拿著這些東西演出 Jerry
- Unbelievable. Jesus Christ.
- No, no, no, do not put those on the...
我的個天啊，真不敢相信  - 別，別，別，把這些……
Bryan, it's fine. It's fine.
I got it under control.
Bryan 沒事沒事，我來管這些事兒吧
I swear to you, okay?
我發誓不會出事
Handle it, please.
你處理吧，好吧
<i>Can y'all hear that? Can y'all hear that?</i>
你們都聽見了嗎？都聽見了嗎？
Yeah!
耶！
<i>Well, clap your hands then! Come on!</i>
拍響你的雙手！一起來！
Eazy!
<i>Everybody come on!</i>
大家一起來！
Eazy!
<i>Who'd y'all come to see?</i>
你們都想看誰？
Eazy!
<i>A little louder, come on!</i>
再大點聲！
- Eazy!
<i>- Get those hands in the air!</i>
Eazy!
雙手不要放下！
#Rap: "We Want Eazy" by Eazy-E
<i>A miracle of modern creation.</i>
我是創造潮流的天才
<i>Eazy-E's on the set hyped up.</i>
Eazy-E狀態正火熱
<i>With the bass and a little
bit of what ya love.</i>
跟著重低音嗨，還有一些神秘添加劑
<i>From a brother who's
smooth like a criminal.</i>
來我這個最會逃脫的犯罪大師
<i>I mean subliminal.</i>
就像一種潛意識
<i>Otherwise known as a villain.</i>
我的另一面就是一個無惡不作的惡棍
<i>Because I'm ruthless,
when I spot a sucka, I kill 'em.</i>
因為我就是殘忍無情，誰超越我的底線，殺人滅口毫不留情
雙關廠牌名稱 Ruthless
<i>But most I think know not to deal with me.</i>
我的敵人都知道，所以他們都不敢惹我
<i>Yo, it's obvious,
tell 'em who you came to see.</i>
所以這一切顯而易見，你們是來現場看誰！
- Eazy!
- Easy!
Eazy!  Easy!
<i>Everybody, come on.</i>
大家再來一次！
Eazy!
<i>A little louder
Say it!</i>
再大點聲！喊吧！
- Eazy!
<i>- Come on, say it, say it, say it.</i>
Eazy!
來吧，喊起來！喊起來！
<i>Gangster rap has become
incredibly popular and profitable</i>
匪幫說唱現在已經極其流行，並在市場暢銷
<i>by selling lyrics about violence
to a young mainstream audience</i>
他們向那些就連做夢也沒有去過貧民窟的
<i>that wouldn't dream
of going anywhere near a ghetto.</i>
主流大眾年輕人灌輸有關暴力歌詞的歌曲
<i>Not all music stars,
as you know, are model citizens.</i>
眾所周知，很多歌星也並非模範公民
<i>Some have had run-ins with the law.</i>
有些還曾觸犯法律
<i>That's certainly nothing new,
but now a few musicians</i>
這已經不是新鮮事，但現在有幾個音樂人
<i>have taken that to new heights.</i>
將這種暴力煽動推向了新的高度
<i>Or to new depths.</i>
又或是說新的底線
<i>Baby, yeah.</i>
寶貝，耶
<i>That is so good.</i>
爽，就這樣
- Yella.
- Hmm?
Yella - 嗯
You in there watching porn
with the door open?
你居然開著門在看黃片？
Yeah.
是啊
Yo, that's what I said, man.
喲，我也挺悶的
What the fuck?
什麼啊
No, it's not even like that.
不是那個意思
Fuck y'all, man. I'm back here
tryin' to write. Fuck y'all, man.
你去們的，我還在這想著要寫詞呢，去你們的
Oh, you tryin' to write.
哦，你還在寫詞呢？
Good night, Lorenzo.
你快睡吧 Lorenzo
Fuck y'all sleep.
你們還能睡得著？
This shit is crazy.
走起來，瘋狂一把
Yeah, man. This shit is dope.
沒錯，萬一次大的
No, man. No. I gotta go.
All right?
不行，不行，老弟，我要掛了，好嗎
Yo, you gotta let me
come fuck with y'all in Miami.
你可說過要帶我去邁阿密玩的
Okay. So now you try and partake
into some of those fat asses?
好啊，你現在也想要來我們這邊的大妞局裡摻一腳？
Come on, bro, I'm tired of these same...
Man, I need something new.
老哥，你也知道我在這特悶，我可以來點兒新的刺激
<i>No, what you think Ma gonna think</i>
不行，你覺得老媽會怎麼想？
about you comin' on tour, huh?
如果你說你要來我的巡演，嗯？
'Cause you know you got school,
你知道你還在上學呢
and you know she ain't gonna
let you miss that many days, man!
你知道老媽一定不會讓你缺課這麼多天的
- You did.
<i>- Come on, man. That's my point.</i>
但你就能行啊  - 別鬧了，你知道我的意思
Hey. Hold on. Hold on.
嘿，等一下，等一下
- So, look, how Mom doing now?
<i>- She good.</i>
對了，老媽最近怎麼樣？ -  她還好
But, nah, you know her,
constantly working, man. Every day, man.
你也知道她，天天就是忙工作啊
<i>Make sure you take care of her, a'ight?</i>
你一定要照顧好媽，知道嗎？
<i>Hey, look, I'll tell you what,</i>
嘿，這樣吧，我跟你說
you stay your little ass outta trouble.
只要你安分點兒別惹事兒
I'll call you when I'm on the way to Miami,
當我到邁阿密的時候就給你打電話
see about getting you on a flight.
然後看看是不是幫你安排飛到邁阿密
I can come out there, though?
我能去嗎？
<i>- You can come out here, man.
</i>-You promise?
你能來啊  -  你保證？
I got you. I got you, ar'ight?
沒問題，沒問題的
Hey, bring the rubbers, T.
嘿，記得帶套來
Get off the phone.
快別說了
I still got the same ones
you gave me a long time ago.
我這還有你很久之前給我的那些呢
Hey, hey. Hold on, T. Somebody at the door.
嘿，老弟，你等一下，有人在敲門
Here.
給
Hello? Dre?
喂？Dre
Hold on!
等一下！
Yeah, nigga, I'm lookin' for my girl,
Felicia.
夥計，我在找我的女人，Felicia
I heard she was up in one of these rooms.
我聽說她在這幾個房間裡
Ain't no Felicia in here, nigga.
這裡可沒有什麼Felicia，哥們
Mind if I take a look?
那我進去看一眼？
Get the fuck outta my room, man.
滾出我的房間！
This nigga just came
to my motherfuckin' door strapped, man.
這傢伙帶著槍來敲我的門？
Where are you going?
你去哪？
I'll show that nigga strapped.
我給他們瞧瞧什麼叫槍
Hey, where Felicia at?
嘿，Felicia 在哪
- Where Felicia?
- Where's your homegirl.
Felicia 在哪
- 你朋友呢？
You Felicia?
你是 Felicia？
Hey, Felicia. You Felicia?
嘿, Felicia，你是 Felicia嗎？
Felicia? Her dude here.
Felicia？ 她男人來了
All right. So none of y'all
are named Felicia now. Okay.
好吧，現在你們沒一個叫Felicia的
Yella! Hey, Yella!
Yella！嘿，Yella！
Your name Felicia?
你是叫 Felicia？
- You forgot my name?
- No, wait!
你把我名字都忘了？ -  沒啊，等下
- Valerie. Your name Valerie.
- Whatever.
Valerie，你叫 Valerie  -  隨便吧
Felicia! Girl, your nigga's out there.
Felicia，妹子，你男人來了
She's suckin' dick, though.
她正忙著呢
He got guns, girl. Come on!
他拿了槍呢，姑娘，快出來
The nigga is strapped.
他拿著槍
I'll show this nigga right now.
Talkin' about gettin' strapped.
來，咱們給他們瞧瞧，什麼叫武裝到底
Hey, Ren. Nigga outside talking
about gettin' strapped.
嘿，Ren，有幾個哥們在門外拿著槍找事兒
Watch out, man.
小心點，哥們
Hey!
嘿！
Show wassup now.
Talking about gettin' strapped.
叫他們開開眼，什麼叫槍
Hey, Cube, you got me, man.
嘿，Cube，一塊走著
Let's ride, nigga.
Time to go to work.
我們走，辦了他們
Hey. Y'all looking for Felicia?
嘿，你們在找Felicia？
She in there or what?
她是不是在這？
She kinda preoccupied
with some real nigga dick.
她現在正享用著正宗黑鳥呢
The fuck you say, little nigga?
你他媽說什麼呢，小個子？
I said, she got
a motherfuckin' dick in her mouth, nigga.
我說她嘴裡正含著一根黑JB呢！
That ain't fun no more?
不好玩了？
The fuck y'all going?
你們往哪跑啊？
Nigga, she's trying to compensate.
哥們，她玩得正High呢
Wow!
哇喔
Fat niggas was bullshit!
那傢伙嚇尿了
Punk-ass niggas, man.
這些廢柴
Bitch-ass niggas.
廢物
Y'all wild.
你們這夠瘋的
Nigga runnin' so fast, that shit was crazy.
他們也跑得真挺快哈
Don't let that shit bother you.
別為這事兒煩心了
- Tryin' to get me killed?
- Whatever.
你想我們被殺嗎？  - 別說了
Nigga, ain't tryin'
to take no bullet for no bitch,
那哥們可不想為了女人中子彈
I guarantee you that.
那可不嘛
Bye, Felicia.
拜，Felicia
#Rap: "Gangsta Gangsta" by N.W.A
<i>Homies all standin' around just hangin '.</i>
我的兄弟們都跟我一起混
<i>Some dope-dealin', some gang-bangin'.</i>
有的去販毒，有的混幫派
<i>We decide to roll and we deep.</i>
我們自成一派玩的特別髒
<i>See a nigga on Dayton's, and we creep.</i>
開好車的慫貨，成為我們的下一個目標
<i>Real slow, and before you know.</i>
悄悄的跟上他，保證充滿驚喜
<i>I had my shotgun pointed in the window.</i>
在反應過來之前我們槍口就已經對上了你
<i>He got scared and hit the gas.</i>
他嚇尿了，一腳油門想躥
<i>Right then I knew I had to smoke his ass.</i>
想逃？沒門，我只能選擇扣動扳機
You're flying up
the <i>Billboard</i> 200 albums chart.
你們火爆了，現在專輯已經上了公告牌前200名榜單
R&B and hip-hop charts too.
還有 R&B 和 HipHop 榜單
You have any idea
how many records we're selling?
你知道我們現在賣了多少專輯了嗎？
Ruthless has arrived, Eric.
We're fucking huge.
Ruthless廠牌已經做大了
That is dope, Jerry. That's dope.
太棒了 Jerry，太棒了
<i>The combined law enforcement
associations of Texas today</i>
今日，德克薩斯州執法機構聯合協會
<i>called for a halt to sales of the album.</i>
宣佈暫停此專輯的對外銷售
<i>I believe that the rap music
promotes violence against authority</i>
我認為說唱音樂正在激化階層之間的矛盾
<i>and, consequently, violence
against law enforcement.</i>
進而升級成為針對執法機構的威脅
15 on that.
我有十五點！
Man, fuck, man!
啊，我靠
Hey. Come on, man. Put that shit up.
快，把東西拿出來吧
Excuse me. Gentlemen, I'm sorry.
先生們，對不起打擾了
I don't mean to be the bearer of bad news.
我需要跟大家說一條壞消息
What you got?
什麼消息？
Oh, shit.
我靠
What's that?
怎麼了？
Motherfuckin' FBI.
該死的 FBI
What the fuck?
I'm supposed to not care about this?
什麼情況，我們還要鳥他們？
Wait, the FBI? They comin' after us, too?
什麼，聯邦調查局？他們也要對付我們了？
Kind of.
差不多吧
I mean, what the letter say, Jerry?
那封信說了什麼啊，Jerry？
Uh, basically, uh...
大致是...
"A song recorded by the rap group N.W.A"
說唱組合N.W.A在他們的專輯
"on their album <i>Straight Out Of Compton</i>"
《Straight Outta Compton》中錄製的一首歌
"encourages violence
against law enforcement."
宣揚並鼓勵對執法者使用暴力
"Advocating violence and assault is wrong,"
鼓勵暴力和襲擊是錯誤的
"and we in the law enforcement community
take exception to such action."
我們作為執法者，堅決反對這種行為
- Fuck that.
去他的  -  去他媽的
Fuck the law enforcement community.
We got freedom of speech, man.
去他媽的執法機構聯合協會，我們有言論自由
- What the fuck can they do to us?
- Right.
他們能把我們怎麼樣？  - 沒錯
You wanna provoke 'em and find out?
你想激怒他們試試麼？
Because this is a warning, Cube.
這只是一個警告，Cube
And it's about <i>Fuck Tha Police,
</i>in particular, so...
他們針對的就是《Fuck The Police》那一首歌
I think maybe we should not
play that song right now.
所以我想我們還是不要唱那首歌了
Not play what? Fuck that, Jerry.
That's what the song is about.
那還唱什麼？去他媽的，那首歌唱的就是這個意思
Relax, relax.
We're not giving in to anything.
冷靜，我們說什麼也不放棄它
No. No.
不，不
I just say we retire it for now, okay?
我只是說暫時不唱，好吧？
It is a reasonably worded threat.
這還只是一個措辭適當的警告
This isn't street bullshit.
This isn't the Crips and Bloods and crap.
這不是街頭那種挑釁，不是Crip幫，Blood幫
This is the federal government.
這可是聯邦政府調查局
These guys can come after us
a million different ways.
他們可以用各種方法對付我們，搞我們
I don't even want to think about it.
Why provoke them?
我連想都不敢想，咱們為什麼要激怒他們
The fuck does that mean?
你是什麼意思？
If it was the LAPD,
maybe I'd be a little worried,
要是洛杉磯警察局，我還有點擔心
but we can't let them censor us, Jerry.
但我們不能讓他們禁我們的歌 Jerry
- I'm not advocating for censorship, Cube.
- Wait. Wait.
我不是在鼓勵審查和封禁 Cube  -  等一下
Maybe none of us should be worried.
Maybe we should be happy.
也許我們根本不需要擔心，也許我們應該高興才是
- What you mean, E?
- Dunno about happy.
你什麼意思，E？  -  高興？
'Cause you see,
this right here is a gift.
你想想，這其實是一份禮物
It's the FBI, E. Whatchu talking about?
這可是FBI警告，你說什麼呢……
This is free publicity for N.W.A.
這是對N.W.A的免費宣傳
We take this to the press and we show them
我們把它交給媒體，告訴他們...
what type of intimidation,
discrimination, and harassment
我們面臨著來自我們自己的政府
that we dealing with from our government.
何等的恐嚇、歧視和騷擾
- I like that shit.
- I'm with that.
我喜歡這主意  -  我也同意
- That's a different thing.
- My nigga, I feel you.
這樣就不同了  -  哥們，我明白了
- If that's what you wanna do, then we can...
- That's what I wanna do.
如果你們想這麼做，我們...  -  沒錯我想這麼做
That's what we wanna do, Jerry. That's it.
這是我們想做的，Jerry，就這樣
That's what we wanna do.
這是我們想要的
Okay.
好吧
- Yeah?
- You good?
好  - 沒問題吧？
I mean...
我想…
- Hate to be the bearer of bad news...
- Mmm-hmm.
我也需要跟大家說一條壞消息
- But 20!
- 20, man!
我這有二十點！ -  二十點！
Wait a minute, that ain't 20.
等等，二十點？ 不是吧？
- Hey, hey, hey. Shhh.
- What's up?
嘿、嘿、嘿！噓  -  怎麼了
Let's not get thrown out
of another fuckin' hotel.
別太吵，我們別再被這家酒店趕走了
Goodnight, Jerry.
晚安，Jerry
Compton's crap!
康普頓的垃圾！
Go back to Compton!
滾回康普頓去！
<i>Ain't that some shit.</i>
場面還真不小
Speak a little truth
and people lose their minds.
我們就說了一點事實，人們就受不了了
This is not music!
這不算音樂
Shit, the truth is,
they can do whatever they want with 'em.
靠，他們拿這些唱片幹什麼都行
They bought them motherfuckers.
反正他們已經付錢了
#Rap: "8 Ball" by N.W.A.
<i>I don't drink brass monkey,</i>
我不喝低檔飲料兌酒精，我喜歡放縱的節奏
諷刺 Beastie Boys - Rass Monkey
<i>Like to be funky
Nickname Eazy-E yo eight ball junkie.</i>
我喜歡放縱的節奏，大家叫我Eazy-E，我是個最能喝的傢伙
8 Bottle代表的是一款麥芽酒的品牌，俗稱8-ball
<i>Bass drum kicking to show my shit.</i>
重低音的擊打，我的演出開始爆炸
<i>Rapping holding my dick, boy, I don't quit.</i>
說唱就是我的最強項，我不會放棄
<i>Crowd-rocking motherfucker
from around the way.</i>
我的演出現場觀眾總是最躁動
<i>I got a six-shooter, yo, mean hombre.</i>
我有一支左輪6連發，所以別惹我
<i>Rolling through the hood to find the boys.</i>
開車來到我的街區，去找我的哥們
<i>To kick dust and cuss crank up some noise.</i>
我們可以搞起一個戶外Party
<i>Police on my balls
I had to pause</i>
員警瞄上了我，我要藏好我的酒
<i>40 ounce in my lap,
and it's freezing my balls.</i>
酒瓶藏到褲子裡差點凍壞了我的小弟
<i>For the sake of our children,
I implore each of you</i>
為了我們的孩子，我懇求每一位朋友
<i>to be unyielding and inflexible
in your opposition to drugs.</i>
要意志堅決，堅定不移的抵制毒品
'Cause another one called me
and told me she's pregnant by you too.
又有一個姑娘給我打電話說懷了你的孩子
You just got to slow down.
你們得安穩點
You can't fuck every broad on the planet.
你們也不能到一個城市就上一批女人吧
So now, pussy a problem?
現在玩女人也不行了？
Listen, it's gonna be a problem
if you got 4,000 kids.
你要是搞出來一大堆孩子，那還能行嗎？
- Right?
- Yeah.
是吧？  - 嗯
You make some money,
你賺了大錢
you got all these problems.
遇到各種各樣的問題
You're gonna have to take care of 'em.
It's fine.
你要解決這些問題... 都好說
I'll help you take care of 'em.
我會幫你解決的
- Hey, Cube.
- Sorry to interrupt y'all lobster brunch.
嘿，Cube  - 抱歉打擾你們的龍蝦大餐
But what's up, E? Where the contracts at,
man? You forgot about me?
E，我的合同在哪呢？你把我忘了嗎？
Didn't I tell you to... You know what?
我不是跟你說了嗎，那什麼
Jerry, you want to deal with this?
Jerry，你來解釋這個問題吧
I'm not talking to Jerry,
I'm talking to you.
我不是在跟Jerry說話，我在跟你說呢
That's Jerry's job.
這是Jerry的工作
It's my department.
You're absolutely right to ask, Cube.
這還真是我管的，你問我就可以了
The contracts are being
finalized as we speak.
合同正在弄，馬上就完成了
The thing is,
with these attorneys, they'll take forever.
主要是，這些律師的工作特別細
Pouring over it, they'll bleed us dry.
But, they're gonna get done.
仔細研究條款比較費時間，他們也會稍微有點磨蹭
I wish I got paid by the hour
the way they do. You know?
我倒是也希望跟他們一樣拿時薪
Me, too.
我也想
I just want to know what's goin' on since I
did write a lot of lyrics on this record.
這張唱片裡有很多歌詞是我寫的，所以我想弄清楚
Everybody knows
how important you are, Cube.
大家都知道你有多重要，Cube
They do?
是嗎？
That's what's goin' on.
確實如此
We just need some time, that's all.
我們需要一些時間，僅此而已
Everything probably all right.
也許一切都好
I must be trippin'.
也許是我多慮了
Shit tastes pretty good.
這玩意味道真不錯
Someday, right?
就幾天，是吧？
Y'all enjoy your meal.
慢用
Okay.
好
I'm telling you, that guy wants
to be you very frickin' badly.
你看我跟你說吧，他非常想成為你
As if I ain't got enough fucking problems.
就好像我問題還不夠多似的
Excuse me. Can I get a refill?
麻煩你，再來一杯
At some point,
you just gotta trust somebody.
某些時候，你得學會信任別人
You know?
知道嗎
You gotta trust somebody.
你真得需要信任別人
Nah, I just think
you overreacting, man.
我想你是多慮了
Eazy one of us, Cube.
What you thinkin' don't even make sense.
Easy是跟我們一夥的，你所想的有點沒道理
No, what don't make sense is.
不啊，沒道理的是
Eazy and Jerry eating steak and lobster
and we eating Fatburger.
Easy和Jerry吃牛排和龍蝦，我們卻在吃漢堡
Shit don't make no sense.
這可沒道理
Look, I hear you,
but I think we need to ride this wave.
我明白，但是我想我們需要同甘苦
For real.
真的
Don't be jumping to conclusions
until you know for sure.
沒有把握別太早下結論
You know?
明白吧？
It's my moms, man.
是我媽媽
Yo, Dre,
喲 Dre
what's going on?
怎麼了？
Moms just called, man.
我媽剛給我打了個電話
It's Tyree.
Tyree出事了
He's dead.
他死了
What? No.
什麼？ 靠
He got into a fight,
some motherfucker broke his neck.
他和別人打架，別人打斷了他的脖子
It's my little brother, man.
那可是我的弟弟
It's my little baby bro.
我的親弟弟啊
I never told y'all this.
我沒跟大家說過
But when I was 12, my sister got killed.
我十二歲的時候，我姐姐被殺了
Her own husband killed her,
then killed himself.
她丈夫殺了她，然後又自殺了
This dope gang took my cousin too.
我表弟也是被一個幫派的人殺了
Shot him in the trunk of a car.
在車後備箱裡開槍殺了他
Fucking Compton, man.
這他媽就是康普頓
Come on, man, like...
但是，哥們...
It's my fault, man.
這一切都是我的錯
Don't talk like that.
別這麼說…
This never would've happened
if I had him out here, man.
如果我讓他過來跟我一塊，這事可能就不會發生
Come on, Dre.
別這麼想，Dre
It's my fuckin' fault.
這他媽是我的錯
It could've happened in another way.
這種事在哪都有可能發生，逃不脫的
- You can't blame yourself for that, Dre.
- No.
你不能為此責備自己，Dre  -  是啊
Tyree gonna always be with you.
No matter what.
無論發生什麼，Tyree將永遠和你在一起
- That's right.
- Yeah, for real, man.
對… 沒錯
And we always gonna be with you.
我們永遠會和你在一起
Hell yeah.
一定的
We always gonna be brothers.
我們永遠都是兄弟
Fuck.
操
We here, a'ight.
我們在一塊
I'm sorry, man.
節哀
You good, Dre.
保重
<i>This is not on you, Andre.</i>
這不是你的錯，Andre
If I had just brought him on tour with me.
Like he wanted.
如果我帶他去和我一起巡演，就像他所想的
Stop this nonsense now. Stop it.
別再說這些沒有意義的話了
Your brother looked up to you,
你弟弟敬仰你
and you took great care of him,
we both did.
你也很照顧他，我們都很照顧他
It's time to let someone else
take care of him now.
現在該把他託付給上帝了
I'm proud of you.
我以你為榮
No person shall disturb the peace
by participating or abetting
誰也不許參加，或者教唆任何...
in any rude, indecent, drunken,
粗魯的、不得體的、醉酒的
riotous or violent conduct.
暴亂的、或是暴力的行為
Or the use of any vulgar, obscene
或是在公共場合使用粗俗的
or abusive language in a public place.
淫穢的或是侮辱人的話語
Note also, the performance of the song.
還要記住，不允許表演
"F the Police", will not be permitted.
《F The Police》這首歌
Refusal to abide
by all the Detroit City Ordinances
拒絕遵守底特律市執法者管理的
will result in immediate
arrest and forfeiture.
即刻將招致逮捕或罰款
Are we finished here? We got a show to do.
你說完沒有？我們還要去演出呢！
Just watch yourself.
你們給我小心點
Eat a dick.
去你媽
It's "Fuck tha Police."
是 "Fuck tha Police."
<i>Straight outta Compton</i>
沖出康普頓
<i>is a brother that'll smother your mother</i>
我出現讓你的老媽都窒息
<i>and make your sister think I love her.</i>
讓你的妹子都以為我愛上她
<i>Dangerous motherfucker raising hell</i>
從地獄降臨的危險分子
<i>and if I ever get caught I make bail.</i>
即使我被員警抓了，我也可以瞬間保釋
<i>So what about the bitch
who got shot? Fuck her!</i>
你說那個中槍的賤貨咋樣了？去她媽的
<i>You think I give a damn
about a bitch? I ain't a sucker!</i>
你覺得我關心一個臭婊子？我還沒那麼低端
<i>This is an autobiography of the E.</i>
這就像是是Eazy-E的自傳
<i>And if you ever fuck with me.</i>
如果你敢跟我做對
<i>You'll get taken</i>
你就會被一個
<i>by a stupid dope brother who will smother.</i>
心狠手辣的哥們給幹掉
<i>Word to the motherfucker
Straight outta Compton.</i>
那些不老實的傢伙聽好了，哥是康普頓混出來的！
Eazy! Eazy!
<i>Damn, that shit was dope!</i>
耶！大家太燥了
What's up?
怎麼搞？
Let's do this shit.
我們搞起來吧
- What's up?
- Let's do this shit.
怎麼？搞起來吧
- Wassup? Let's go.
- What's up?
怎麼樣？ -  怎麼著？
<i>Hey, hold up, hold up.</i>
嘿，等一下，等一下
<i>Y'all know
what the motherfuckin' police</i>
你們想知道，那些員警在後臺
<i>tried to tell us backstage?</i>
對我們說了什麼嗎？
What?
什麼？
<i>They tried to tell us
what the fuck we can't play.</i>
他們想告訴我們，什麼歌你不許唱
<i>Motherfuckers tried to tell us</i>
他們想告訴我們
<i>what the fuck we can't say.</i>
什麼話，你不能說！
<i>This N.W.A.</i>
我們是 N.W.A.
<i>We do what the fuck we wanna do!</i>
我們願做什麼就去做！
<i>We say what the fuck we wanna say!</i>
我們想說什麼就去說！
<i>So, everybody,</i>
來，每個人
<i>put the middle fingers high in the sky.</i>
都把中指豎起來
<i>And to the punk-ass cop backstage...</i>
沖著那些後臺的員警們
<i>Yo, Dre.</i>
喲，Dre
<i>- What up?
- I got something to say.</i>
怎麼？  -  我有些話想說
<i>Fuck the police.</i>
去他媽的員警
<i>Comin' straight from the underground.</i>
我們是純正的來自地下
<i>A young nigga got it bad 'cause I'm brown.</i>
總被人黑，因為皮膚是黑色
<i>And not the other color so police think</i>
我們不是白色所以被員警歧視
<i>they have the authority to kill a minority.</i>
他們認為有權去殺戮一個我們這個群體
<i>Fuck that shit 'cause I ain't the one.</i>
去他媽的，因為我才不會逆來順受
<i>For a punk motherfucker
with a badge and a gun</i>
他們帶著警徽和槍就能橫行霸道
<i>to be beaten on and thrown in jail.</i>
看誰不爽揍一頓，再扔進監獄
<i>We can go toe to toe in
the middle of a cell.</i>
在同一個牢房裡我倆可以“慢慢反省”
<i>Fucking with me 'cause I'm a teenager.</i>
看我不順眼，只因為我還年輕
<i>With a little bit of gold and a pager.</i>
因為我有點錢，還帶著BP機
<i>Searching my car looking for the product.</i>
就可以搜我的車，看看我是否帶了貨
<i>Thinking every nigga is selling narcotics.</i>
他們認為每個黑人都他媽的在販毒
<i>You'd rather see me in the pen.</i>
希望我能被關在圍欄裡
<i>Than me and Lorenzo rolling in a Benz-o.</i>
但我開著大奔和兄弟在街頭晃悠
<i>Beat a police out of shape.</i>
把你這些SB員警打得不成人樣
<i>Then when I'm finished.</i>
打完之後
<i>Bring the yellow tape.</i>
我會帶著黃色膠帶
<i>To tape off the scene of the slaughter.</i>
親自把現場“保護”起來
<i>Still getting swoll off bread and water.</i>
我在監獄只能吃麵包喝白水
<i>I don't know if they fags or what.</i>
都不知道你是愛搞基還是怎樣
<i>Search a nigga down and grabbing his nuts.</i>
把我的兄弟身上搜遍了，甚至摸了他襠部
<i>And on the other hand,
without a gun they can't get none.</i>
不過話說回來，你沒槍誰怕你那逼樣
<i>But don't let it be a black and a white one</i>
員警不能一黑一白搭檔
<i>'Cause they'll slam ya
down to the street top.</i>
他們把你揍的老媽都不認
<i>Black police showing out for the white cop.</i>
黑哥們當了員警就背叛了黑人兄弟
<i>Ice Cube will swarm.</i>
老子就會干預
<i>On any motherfucker in a blue uniform.</i>
再來一個穿著制服的SB
<i>Just 'cause I'm from the CPT.</i>
只因我來自Compton
<i>Punk police are afraid of me, huh.</i>
他們就開始怕我
<i>A young nigga on the warpath.</i>
我在街頭挑起一場戰爭
<i>And when I'm finished,
it's gonna be a bloodbath.</i>
火拼完了，血必流成河
<i>Of cops, dyin' in LA.</i>
LA的員警，都不得好死
<i>Yo, Dre, I got something to say.</i>
喲 Dre，讓我說……
<i>Fuck tha police!</i>
去他媽的員警
<i>Fuck, fuck, fuck tha police!</i>
去他媽的，去他媽的員警
<i>Fuck tha police!</i>
去他媽的員警
<i>Fuck, fuck...</i>
去他媽的，去他媽的
<i>Fuck tha police!</i>
去他媽的員警
Huh? Fuck!
啊？操！
Come on, nigga.
快跑，哥們
Hell no! They shootin'! Let's go!
我靠，他們開槍了，閃
Go, go! All units, move in.
上，所有小組，行動
Move!
上！
Go, go, go, go, go! Come on, man!
快跑！快跑！
Come on, hurry up! Hurry up!
閃啊！快點，快點！
- Hold up, hold up.
- Let's go, let's go.
等一下，等一下  -  快撤，快點
- Fuck them!
- Come on!
去他媽的  -  快點
Fuck!
操
Shit, shit, shit, shit!
該死，該死
- Fuck this!
- What we gonna do?
我靠，往哪兒走
Get off me!
鬆開我
Get the fuck off me!
放開我啊
Man, get off me, man!
快放開我
Away from the ledge.
離開平臺
Backup!
We need backup in the loading area!
後援，裝載區需要增援
Now!
馬上來
Man!
放開
Come on. Get the fuck off of me, man!
快點放開我
Fuck y'all.
去你媽的
This is completely fucking illegal!
You realize that?
這樣是違法的，你知道嗎？
Let us go! Let me go! Come on, man.
快點走，快點走，趕緊的
- Fuck you! Fuck you!
- Come on.
去你的，去你的
Fuck you! Fuck you!
去你媽，去你媽的
Get in there!
You gotta get in there.
進去！快點進去
Fuck tha police! Fuck tha police!
去他的員警 去他的員警...
Fuck your mama,
fuck your daddy, fuck your grandma!
去你媽，去你爸，去你奶奶的
Fucking...
操…
These motherfuckers.
這幫混蛋
Fuck y'all!
去你們的！
How do you explain
inciting a riot in Detroit?
你如何解釋在底特律掀起的這場騷亂？
What do you have to say about that?
你有什麼想說的？
I have to say that we
didn't incite that shit.
我想說，我們並沒有掀起什麼騷亂
Right. Like, y'all just got a snapshot
of how Americans really feel.
沒錯，你們看到的是美國人民真正的感受
We gave the people a voice.
我們替這些人民發聲
We gave the people truth.
我們向大家提供了真相
Yeah, but your songs, they glamorize
the lifestyle of gangs, guns, drugs.
但是你們的歌，粉飾了含有幫派、槍支和毒品的生活方式
Our art is a reflection of our reality.
我們創作的作品反映的是現實
What you see
when you go outside your door?
你出門之後看到的是什麼
I know what I see.
我知道我所看到的
And it ain't glamorous.
絕對不是太平天下
We get AKs from Russia
and cocaine from Columbia.
AK-47是從俄羅斯來的，毒品是從哥倫比亞來的
And ain't none of us got a passport, so...
我們所有人可都沒有護照，所以...
might wanna check the source.
你最好去查查源頭
Next question.
下一個問題
Will you be more careful
about what you say, how you say it?
你們能不能考慮一下，以後注意點你們要說的話和說話的方式
- No!
- Probably not. Nah.
不會  -  不太可能
Freedom of speech
includes rap music, right?
言論自由包括說唱音樂，對吧？
Well, we exercising our first amendment
as far as I'm concerned.
我們正在實踐第一修正案的條例
And the government wrote that.
這可是政府寫的
So, Cube, what's a guy from Compton
Cube，像你一樣的康普頓小夥
do when he starts making
real money like this?
賺了你這樣的大錢會怎麼花？
Cube?
Cube？
Buy Raider gear.
買 Raiders的衣服
And curl activator.
還有卷髮膠什麼的
Next question.
下一個問題
Good to see you, Cube.
很高興見到你 Cube
I can barely see you, Jerry.
見你一面太難了 Jerry
What's with all the <i>Godfather</i> shit?
幹嘛搞得像電影教父一樣？
Okay.
好吧
I know that you've been very eager to sign
我知道你一直都很想簽合同
a contract with Eric's company,
Ruthless Records.
和Eric的 Ruthless 唱片公司簽
Eric's company? Ain't it your company, too?
Eric的公司？也是你的公司吧？
That's incorrect.
It's not my company. I work for you.
你說錯了，這不是我的公司，我為你們工作
- You work for me?
- Uh-huh.
你為我工作？  -  嗯
I've made that clear from the beginning.
我從一開始就說的很清楚了
All right, cool.
So, I could take this to a lawyer
好吧，那我能把這合同拿給律師看吧？
or somebody, right?
或者朋友什麼的
Cube, those guys are paid to make trouble.
Cube，那些律師就是靠挑刺來賺錢的
They're gonna create problems
where no problems exist.
他們會在沒問題的地方創造問題
Jerry, you know I don't know
what none of this legal shit mean.
Jerry，你知道我對這些法律上的東西一竅不通
All right? None of us do.
對吧？我們這幫人都不懂
So we're gonna need a lawyer
before we sign anything.
所以我們在簽字前需要找個律師
Everybody else has already signed.
其他人都已經簽過了
I thought you knew this.
我以為你知道
You're the only one who hasn't.
就剩你沒簽了
There's also this.
還有這個
$75,000.
七萬五千美元
Shit!
靠
Sign the contract
簽了這合同
and all this money is yours.
這些錢就都是你的了
That's my money anyway, Jerry.
I earned that money.
這本來就是我的錢 Jerry，是我掙來的
- And I wrote a lot of hit songs.
- Mmm-hmm.
我也寫了很多熱門單曲  -  嗯嗯
We've been performing
on this tour for months.
我們這次巡演已經好幾個月了
Sellin' out shows, sellin' records.
賣門票、賣唱片
I know there's plenty of money.
我知道我們掙了很多錢
Really? Jesus Christ.
真的嗎？天啊
Give me my money, Jerry.
把我的錢給我 Jerry
How the hell do you think this works?
你認為這一切是怎麼運轉的？
How the hell do you think
all of this gets paid for?
你認為這一切的花銷是哪裡出的？
The hotel rooms, the tour buses,
酒店房間，大巴...
security, the parties, all this shit.
保安、派對、這一切
How do you think it gets paid for?
You think it's free?
這些花銷是怎麼來的？你認為這一切都是免費的？
Why are you doing this now?
你為什麼現在又說這些？
If we were so good, why didn't you give us
contracts in the beginning?
如果我們那麼好，你怎麼不一開始就讓我們簽合同？
Because nothing is a sure thing, Cube.
因為沒有什麼事一定的，Cube
Even a great talent can crash and burn.
即便是偉大的天賦也會崩潰消逝的
Too much ego, too much excess,
太多自負，太多超負荷
too many expectations.
太多的期望
It tends to ruin things.
You ought to keep that in mind.
這些都會毀了天賦的，這個你必須要清楚
This is Eric's company, right?
這是Eric的公司，對吧？
Bye, Jerry.
再見，Jerry
I'm out.
我不玩了
What up, big Suge?
近來怎樣？Big Suge
Here you go.
給你
Thank you, sir.
謝謝，先生
Hey, what up with D.O.C. and Suge?
嘿，DOC和Suge去幹什麼？
I guess that dude
is gonna be managing him now.
我想那傢伙以後要當他經紀人了
One day
you Bobby Brown's bodyguard,
昨天還是Bobby Brown的保鏢
and the next day, you reppin' talent.
今天就成經紀人了
Come on, man.
行了吧
I guess everybody
wanna get into the act, huh?
我想大家都想參與進來
I guess so.
我想是吧
All right, man.
好吧
I know, right?
沒錯吧？
- How you doin'? You good?
- Here you go.
怎麼樣，你還好嗎？ -  給你
I'm helping you out all I can.
You all right?
我盡全力幫你，你還好嗎？
- Yeah?
- Yeah, I'm good.
還好
- What's going on?
- Just happy to be home.
怎麼回事？  - 回到家很高興
You hungry?
你餓了嗎？
Yeah?
嗯？
I'll be there in a minute. All right?
我一會就過去，好吧
Thanks, man.
謝了
- Thanks for everything, bruh.
- You bet!
謝謝你做的一切  - 沒事
So, Cube.
那麼 Cube
We gonna keep
this momentum going or what?
你這股勁就不能過去嗎？
Nah, man. Not like this.
不是這麼回事
I'd rather be broke than to get fucked.
我寧願破產 ，也不願被別人耍
I told you not to sign that shit, Dre.
我跟你說過不要簽那個合同，Dre
Nigga, I got bills to pay.
And you know that.
哥們，我得付帳單啊，你知道
And I gotta put some money
in my momma's hand after Tyree passed, man.
現在Tyree去世了，我還要再給我媽一些錢
- I feel you.
- Right.
我明白了  -  好吧
We gotta do what we gotta do.
該做的，我們還得去做
They're gonna take care of you.
You their bread and butter.
他們會好好“照顧”你的，你就是他們的魚肉
Cube, we Ruthless.
Cube，我們還是 Ruthless 成員
We N.W.A. They Ruthless.
我們是N.W.A，他們才是“冷酷”
Cube, you comin'?
Cube，你走嗎？
I'm about to get out of here.
我得走了
Take care of yourself, Dre.
你自己多保重，Dre
Peace.
保重
- Mom.
- I missed you.
媽  -  我想死你了
- How you doing?
- I'm good.
最近怎麼樣？  -  還挺好
- Good.
- Come on. Let's get home.
那就好  -  我們回家
All right.
好啊
So you're leaving the group?
你要離開組合？
Yeah, I'm through with the bullshit.
對，我不想摻和了
Eazy put everything on Jerry,
Jerry put everything on Eazy.
Easy讓Jerry管理著一切，Jerry也把一切向Easy交底
It's a two-man show up there.
There ain't no fuckin' group.
這已經是他倆的戲了，根本沒有什麼組合了
I get that,
but I just want you to understand
我明白了，但是你要知道
that you are walking away
from a winning situation.
你正要離開一個大好的局面
Now, how do you feel about this, Kim?
Is he making a big mistake?
你覺得這怎麼樣？Kim，他這步棋是不是走錯了？
- A mistake?
- Yes.
錯誤？  -  是啊
I don't think so, okay.
我不這樣認為
After hearing all the stuff
that he went through, I would've left too.
經歷了這麼多事情，我也會離開的
Look, I want you to express yourself, Cube.
我希望你表達自己 Cube
And I am your biggest fan.
I believe in you.
而我是你最大的歌迷，我很相信你
But I just want you to understand,
但是你要明白一點
there's not a lot of
money in this solo play.
單飛是肯定不如組合賺錢多的
Okay?
明白嗎？
But if the first record hits,
但是如果你第一張唱片暢銷的話
I will make it up to you on the second one.
我答應你，會在第二張上補償你的
Be ready, Bryan.
做好準備吧，Bryan
These records is comin' in fast.
專輯很快就會做出來的
#Rap: "The Nigga Ya Love to Hate" by Ice Cube
<i>I heard payback's a motherfucking nigga.</i>
復仇就像一個被壓抑黑人的靈魂
<i>That's why I'm sick of getting
treated like a goddamn stepchild.</i>
所以我已經受夠了寄人籬下當陪襯的日子
<i>Fuck a punk 'cause I ain't him.</i>
我不是主角所以去他媽的
<i>You gotta deal with the nine-double-M.</i>
你要小心我的9mm口徑手槍
<i>The damn scum that you all hate</i>
你們都要時刻擔驚受怕
<i>just think if niggas decide to retaliate.</i>
因為我早晚要給你們一場報復
<i>They try to keep me from running up.</i>
他們不想讓我表現的太火
<i>I never tell you to get down,
it's all about coming up.</i>
我不想讓你沉醉音樂中，而是要積極思考
<i>So what they do, go and ban the AK?</i>
但政府怎麼想？他們要禁止掉AK
<i>My shit wasn't registered any fucking way.</i>
不過我的槍沒有註冊所以依舊可以上膛
<i>So you better duck away, run and hide out.</i>
你最好躲著點，跑快點，藏好點
<i>When I'm rolling real
slow and the lights out</i>
尤其當我已經準備好要表演的時候
<i>'Cause I'm about to fuck up the program.</i>
我要把這一切規律搞亂
<i>Shooting out the window
of a drop-top Brougham.</i>
從我的敞篷車裡向外機槍掃射
<i>When I'm shooting let's see who drop.</i>
看看我都射死了誰
<i>The police, the media,
suckers that went pop.</i>
員警，媒體，還有跑去玩流行的SB
<i>And motherfuckers that say they too black.</i>
那些吹自己是最純正的老黑
<i>Put 'em overseas
they'll be begging to come back.</i>
送他們回到非洲他們會跪求要回來
<i>They say he promote gangs and drugs.</i>
權力階層說讓黑人繼續玩幫派和毒品吧
<i>You wanna sweep a nigga like me up under the rug</i>
他們想把我這種說真話的人都掃地出門
<i>Kicking shit called street knowledge</i>
還說自己傳播街頭知識？
<i>Why more niggas in the pen than in college?</i>
為什麼現在監獄裡的黑人比學校的都多？
<i>Now cause of that line I might be your cellmate</i>
如果沒有這個界線說不定我們就是獄友
<i>That's from the nigga ya love to hate</i>
我是那個你們特別想去恨的人
#NowPlaying: "Flashlight" by Parliament
You know Cube's record
is in the Top 20 <i>Billboard,</i> right now?
你知道嗎，現在Cube的歌已經上公告牌前20名了
Our shit never been up there.
He blowin' the fuck up, Jerry.
我們的歌還從沒排名這麼靠前，他火起來了，Jerry
It's gonna be fine, Eric.
這沒什麼的 Eric
It's not just N.W.A anymore,
我們現在不止有 N.W.A.
it's our whole Ruthless roster.
我們 Ruthless 唱片公司陣容強大
We got D.O.C.,
we got Michel'le, we got Above the Law.
我們有 D.O.C.，還有 Michel'le, 還有 Above the Law組合
We're moving up to the next level.
我們已經在更高層次了
You know what? Sit down for two seconds.
等一下，坐下，聽我跟你說
Look, we need to keep Dre happy.
我們必須留住 Dre
Yeah.
好
Look at him.
你看他
You think he needs
any more motivation than that?
你覺得他還需要什麼別的動力嗎？
I mean, I get it, Jerry.
我明白 Jerry
He drownin' in pussy and shit,
but that don't mean that he...
他沉迷在女人們的身上，但這不意味他...
Now, you worry too much. Stop, okay?
你擔心的太多了，別這樣，好嗎？
Yeah, ar'ight.
好吧，好吧
Here, sign some checks.
來，簽一下這些支票
- Right now, Jerry?
- Yes, right now.
現在嗎，Jerry？  -  嗯現在簽
- You're gonna be out of your mind later.
- Come on.
過一會你就玩飛了，快點吧
Do it now.
現在就簽
The fact is,
Ren is as good a writer as Cube.
我覺得Ren和Cube一樣，也是個好的寫手
Maybe even better.
甚至可能更好
We got everything covered.
一切都在掌握之中
Just the last one. Okay?
還有一張
- We finished here, Jerry?
- We're finished.
行了搞定沒？ - 完事了
Good. 'Cause I'm about to go fuck.
很好，我要去泡妞了
- Ar'ight.
- Yeah.
走了  -  好
#NowPlaying: "Flashlight" by Parliament
Now I'm only telling you what you told me.
我把你的話再複述一遍
If <i>AmeriKKKa's Most Wanted</i> blew up,
如果《AmeriKKKa's Most Wanted》大賣
you'd pay me the advance for the follow-up.
你就把下一張的預付款給我
Now is that not what the fuck you said?
你他媽是不是這麼說的
That is what I said.
我是這麼說的
But it is more complicated than that, Cube.
不過事情沒這麼簡單 Cube
Right, there are metrics...
現在我們還需要……
Come on, Bryan!
得了吧，Bryan
I got a baby on the way
and a house I just paid for
我孩子馬上就要出生了，房子也剛付款
off the strength of what you told me.
都是考慮到了你承諾給我的錢
I mean, you gave me your word!
你是對我保證過的
Cube, would you just calm down?
Cube，你能不能冷靜一下
Calm down?
冷靜？
I am just trying to give you what you want.
我正在努力為你爭取更好的前景
You not. I been did the work...
你沒有，我創作了作品
I gave you the product.
Give me my money, Bryan!
我給了你作品，那現在把錢給我，Bryan!
When a man does the job,
he's supposed to get paid,
一個人做了他的工作，他就應該得到報酬
and you making it seem like I'm beggin'
for some shit that's technically mine.
現在你讓我看起來，好像在討我自己的錢一樣
Of course you are not begging.
你當然不是在討錢
And I am not trying to be difficult, man.
I promise you.
我也不想給你找麻煩，絕對保證
But you can't help me, right?
但是你幫不了我，對不對？
That's what you telling me?
你想跟我說這個？
My hands are tied, man.
我現在手頭太緊了
Hey!
嘿！
Shoulda kept your word, Bryan.
你應該遵守你的承諾的，Bryan
Jesus Christ, man!
我的天啊
What the fuck are you doing, Cube?
你在幹嘛？Cube
Goddamn!
我靠
I will get you your money, man.
Just... God damn it!
我會把錢給你的，別…… 天哪
You think I give a fuck
about these fucking records?
你以為我他媽會在乎這些唱片？
I put up these fuckin' records!
This my shit!
是我製作的這些唱片，都是我的！
I know that, Cube!
I will get you your money!
我知道啊，我會把錢給你的
God damn it! I'm sorry.
天啊！對不起
Now I'm gonna fuck up your shit.
現在我要開始砸你的東西了
Look, do not...
哎，別啊…
God damn it!
該死
Just, fine.
好說
Take it out what you owe me.
這些都可以從你欠我的錢裡扣掉
Just...
別...
#Rap: "Real Niggaz" by N.W.A.
<i>Prisoner like a hostage.</i>
監獄就像一種變相綁架
<i>Yo, you shoulda covered
your muthafucking head like an ostrich.</i>
你應該像鴕鳥一樣學會認慫
<i>Deep in the dirt 'cause you's a sucker.</i>
把頭深埋進土裡因為你是一個弱雞
<i>And your ass up high
so I can kick the muthafucker.</i>
屁股撅高，讓我好好踹你一腳
<i>Don't try to hang your best abroad</i>
別老想著跟你基友一起玩耍
<i>'Cause my foot will be so
far up your ass, you'll get hemorrhoids.</i>
在你反應過來之前，我一腳給你踢出痔瘡
<i>Before you try to fuck wit Ren.</i>
永遠別想跟MC Ren比狠……
See that shit right there?
That's what I'm talking about.
看見了沒有？這歌絕對行
Fuck that nigga Cube, man.
That nigga ain't shit.
去他媽的 Cube，他算個什麼東西
How you figure, man? His record the
hottest shit out right now, E.
你怎麼知道？他的唱片現在賣的最火
Yeah, man, for real. Cube killed that shit.
沒錯，Cube的新專輯太棒了
So we supposed to
just sit there and not say nothin',
所以我們就跟娘們似的坐在這兒，什麼也不說？
and look like bitches and just take it?
就這麼忍著？
Take what?
忍什麼？
I don't know what the fuck you
talkin' about. I like that shit.
我不知道你在說什麼，我喜歡他的歌
Clown-ass.
小丑
Why you drunk all the goddamn time?
你為什麼總是醉醺醺的？
You need to get your shit together.
You's a motherfucking' artist,
給我打起精神來，就你這樣
if you ain't noticed.
還算什麼藝人
How about you get
your shit together, little nigga.
你還是自己振作起來吧，小個兒
Come on.
走吧
How about you get
your country-ass homeboy.
你跟著你這鄉巴佬朋友走吧
<i>'Cause the vocals were local in nightclubs
And not getting paid in full.</i>
在夜店裡都是我們的聲音，你卻沒有立足之地
<i>They got the nerve to cuss
Only reason niggaz pick up your record</i>
都在亂噴，人們買你的唱片
<i>is cause they thought it was us.</i>
只是誤以為你還是我們的一員
#NowPlaying: "Mothership Connection (Star Child)" by Parliament
Hello.
喂？
<i>Yo, Dre. D.O.C. was in an accident.</i>
喲，Dre，D.O.C.出車禍了
What? An accident?
什麼，出車禍了？
D.O.C. shouldn't even be alive.
D.O.C. 他差點就掛了
Got thrown out a car, hit a tree.
被撞出車外，直接整個人甩到樹上了
Is he paralyzed?
他癱瘓了麼？
<i>No. But his throat got crushed.</i>
沒，但是他的喉嚨被重傷了
He could lose his career over this.
他可能再也不能說唱了
Where your people? Where Eazy and Jerry?
你的團隊呢，Eazy-E 和 Jerry呢？
How the fuck should I know?
我他媽怎麼知道？
Come here.
過來
Whatchu know about Jerry?
Whatchu think about him?
關於Jerry你瞭解多少？你覺得他人怎麼樣？
He a'ight. I guess.
他還行，我覺得
What about your paperwork?
You cool with that?
那你的合同呢，你可以接受麼？
I think.
差不多吧
You think?
差不多？
Look, I just focus on the music, Suge.
哎，Suge 我只想專心做音樂
That's it.
僅此而已
You see that motherfucker in there?
你看到躺在那的倒楣蛋了麼？
Gotta make sure it don't
happen to you, man.
我希望你不會發生同樣的悲劇
Hey, uh...
嘿，呃
Maybe some of your people
can look into my paperwork, too.
或許你手底下的人能幫我好好看看一下我的合同
Most definitely.
沒問題
I'll arrange.
我來安排
Go see your boy.
去再看看你兄弟吧
This place is nice.
這家店很漂亮
You're nice.
I figured I'd take you to a nice place,
你很漂亮，所以我想也應該帶你來個好地方
- Ms. Record Executive.
- Mmm.
我的唱片執行女士  -  嗯
Um, record executive assistant.
呃，是唱片執行助理
But, damn.
不過還是驚喜了
I didn't realize we was going on
like a "date" date.
我沒想到你是叫我來這麼正式的約會
I don't even know how to take that.
我都不知道怎麼弄正式
I got my collared shirt on. I brought
you to this nice restaurant. Really?
穿了比較正式的襯衫，帶你來個不錯的地方
Okay. That is not the
kind of collared shirt
好吧，這件衣服可不是
they was talking about.
那種大家說的襯衫
It's cute, though.
不錯挺好看的
And you didn't take off
your hat like they asked you to.
而且你沒按酒店要求摘掉帽子
And I'm not.
嗯那是
- Oh, really?
- I ain't taking off my hat for nobody.
是嗎？我可不會隨便為誰脫帽
I think they know that.
我覺得他們知道
So what?
怎麼？
You bring all your little
females here, don't you?
你把你看上的各種女孩子都帶來這兒？
The special ones.
只有那些特殊點兒的
Okay.
好吧
I'm playing. I'm playing.
There you go getting sensitive.
我開玩笑呢，你敏感什麼
You don't have to try to impress me.
你其實不用對我這麼特別
We could've went to Fatburger.
我們去漢堡店也可以
Go to Fatburger?
去漢堡店？
Hey! You got a haircut. I love it.
嘿，換了個新髮型！很帥
How's that new house treating you?
你們的新房子還喜歡麼？
It's great. Thanks for asking.
很好，謝謝關心
So, how you liking your new decor?
那你覺得這些新的擺設合你口味麼？
Great.
挺棒的
Yeah, I never did like
the old design anyway, you know?
我感覺這些比以前的強的太多了
What you got for me, Bryan?
你找我有何貴幹，Bryan?
I know you called me up here for somethin'.
我知道你肯定是有事找我
Yeah.
是啊
Uh...
呃
It's N.W.A's new record.
這是N.W.A.的新專輯
I wanted to play it for you first,
before you hear it anywhere else.
我想讓你先聽聽，省得你在別處聽到它
#NowPlaying: "Real Niggaz" by N.W.A.
<i>Break me, take me
But watch me pull the trigger.</i>
你可以打擊我，甚至毀滅我，但你要小心我會扣動扳機
<i>Dre is just a nigga with
heart a nigga that's smart.</i>
我是Dr.Dre，目標明確，手段精明
<i>A nigga that's paid to say
what others are scared to play.</i>
大把賺錢，敢於口無遮攔，大聲呼喊
<i>We started out with too much cargo
So I'm glad we got rid of Benedict Arnold.</i>
發跡之時經歷太多困難，所以很慶倖我們甩掉了叛徒
Benedict Arnold 美國歷史上眾人皆知的叛徒人物
<i>Yo, N.W.A...</i>
喲, N.W.A...
Benedict Arnold?
Benedict Arnold？
Are they trying to say
that you're like a traitor?
他們的意思是影射你是叛徒？
Yeah.
對
I'm a fuckin' traitor?
我他媽是叛徒？
I didn't say shit about them
on <i>AmeriKKKa's Most Wanted!</i>
我在第一張專輯裡可沒說他們壞話
Now they trying to diss?
但現在他們想來一場罵戰？
#Rap: "No Vaseline" by Ice Cube
<i>Goddamn, I'm glad y'all
set it off Used to be hard.</i>
臥槽，你們點燃了導火線，這再好不過了，曾幾何時還算是硬漢
<i>Now you're just wet and soft.</i>
如今卻是徹頭徹尾的軟蛋
<i>First you was down with the AK.</i>
一開始你們總是AK掛在嘴邊
<i>And now I see you on a
video with Michel'le.</i>
而現在你們出現在小妞的MV裡？
Michel’le，R&B女歌手，曾一度是Dr.Dre女友
<i>Looking like straight bozos
I saw it coming that's why I went solo.</i>
徹底的小丑行徑！未卜先知，於是我分道揚鑣選擇單飛
<i>And kept on stompin'.</i>
並且保持著一貫真實作風
<i>While y'all mothafuckers
moved straight outta Compton.</i>
而你們這幫SB富貴了之後卻毅然“搬離出康普頓”？
<i>Living with the whites one big house
And not another nigga in sight.</i>
和白人們一樣住著大豪宅，方圓百里看不見一個黑人
<i>I started off with too much cargo.</i>
我滿載寶藏起航
<i>Dropped four niggas
Now I'm making all the dough.</i>
丟下四個傻缺，我如今大賺特賺
<i>White man just ruling
The Niggas With Attitudes? Who ya fooling?</i>
“有態度的黑哥們”被一個白人統治著，這太搞笑了！
<i>Y'all niggas just phony
I put that on my mama and my dead homies.</i>
你們假的沒邊了，我對我的媽媽和我的死去的瓷發誓
<i>Yella Boy's on your team so you're losing.</i>
Yella 都能入團，你們真是太失敗了
<i>Hey, yo, Dre, stick to producing.</i>
對了Dre，你還是玩玩製作就好
<i>Calling me Arnold but you bent-a-dick.</i>
你叫我Arnold，那你們就是個假雞巴
Benedict諧音Been a dick，叛徒Benedict的雙關，巧妙回應上一首歌
<i>Eazy-E saw your ass and went in it quick.</i>
Eazy 已經把你騙的團團轉你卻一無所知
<i>You got jealous when I got my own company.</i>
而你現在只能嫉妒我擁有了自己的公司
Cube離開之後創建了Street Knowledge
<i>But I'm a man, and ain't nobody humping me.</i>
老子是純爺們，永遠沒人能玩弄我
<i>Trying to sound like</i> Amerikkka's Most.
而你們學著我 Amerikkka's Most 裡的樣子
<i>You could yell all day
but you don't come close</i>
你們努力上十年也是和我相距甚遠
<i>'Cause you know I'm the one
that flowed ya done run 100 miles</i>
因為你知道N.W.A裡我是最屌的，跑了100裡了
<i>but you still got one to go.</i>
但你們還差一裡呢
文字遊戲，雙關引用N.W.A.的EP名稱
<i>With the L-E-N-C-H M-O-B,
and y'all disgrace the C-P-T</i>
和Da Lench Mob作對，你們只能丟康普頓的臉
Da Lench Mob，Cube當時帶出的組合
<i>'Cause you're getting fucked
out your green by a white boy.</i>
因為一個白人把你們都給耍的暈頭轉向，身無分文
<i>With no Vaseline.</i>
直接爆菊，連凡士林都省了！
<i>Now you're getting done without Vaseline.</i>
現在你們不用凡士林，直接爆菊…
採樣自LL Cool J的To Da Break of Dawn
<i>Damn, it feels good to see people, on it.</i>
操，真高興看到有人這麼慘
採樣自Biz Markie – Vapors
<i>The bigger the cap bigger the peeling.</i>
玩得越大，摔得越慘
<i>Who gives a fuck about a punk-ass villain.</i>
誰他媽在乎一個傻B惡棍
MC Ren aka. Villain
<i>You're getting fucked real quick and
Eazy's dick is smelling like MC Ren's shit.</i>
你總是被秒殺操死，Eazy的JB上怎麼有MC Ren的屎味兒？
<i>Tried to tell you a year ago But Willie
D told me to let a ho be a ho, so.</i>
一年前我曾想跟你說點什麼，但Willie D跟我說就讓傻B犯傻B吧
Willie D ，Geto Boys成員，Let a ho be a ho為其一首歌
<i>I couldn't stop you from getting ganked.</i>
我實在沒法讓你不被騙的一貧如洗
<i>Now let's play big-bank-take-little-bank.</i>
現在就玩著大魚吃小魚的遊戲吧
<i>Tried to diss Ice Cube,
it wasn't worth it 'cause</i>
想要Diss我Ice Cube？這生意你們絕對賠的體無完膚
<i>the broomstick fit your ass so perfect.</i>
因為掃帚和你的菊花大小匹配的天衣無縫
回應Message to BA中的 “We're gonna cut your hair off and fuck you with a broomstick”
<i>Cut my hair and I'll cut them balls</i>
剪了我的頭髮那我就剪了你的蛋
<i>'cause I heard you like
giving up the drawers.</i>
因為我聽說你打算不穿內褲了
<i>Gang-banged by your manager, fella
Getting money out</i>
一幫傻小子被生意人騙昏了，從你身上榨出一遝遝的鈔票
<i>your ass like a mothafucking ready teller.</i>
你的菊花就像ATM機
Ready Teller，再次暗喻Jerry Heller
<i>Giving up the dollar bills.</i>
鈔票就這麼沒了
<i>Now they got the villain with
a purse and high heels.</i>
而他們只要給MC Ren買手提包和高跟鞋就讓他高興了
<i>So don't believe what Ren say</i>
所以別相信MC Ren說的一切了
<i>'cause he's going out like Kunte Kinte.</i>
因為他就像黑奴 Kunte Kinte一樣
Kunte Kinte是小說《根》裡的一個奴隸
<i>But I got a whip for ya, Toby
Used to be my homie</i>
但我已經為Toby你準備好皮鞭了，你們曾經是我的兄弟
Kunte Kinte的新主人給他取名Toby，而他不願意，於是主人用皮鞭抽打他
<i>and now you act like you don't know me.</i>
如今卻裝作素未相識一般
<i>It's a case of divide-and-conquer</i>
我現在分而克之
<i>'Cause you let a Jew break up my crew.</i>
因為你們讓一個猶太人毀了我們的團體
<i>House nigga gotta run...</i>
像個奴隸一樣躲躲藏藏……
That shit's kinda funny.
這歌有點意思
That motherfucker got us!
這混帳徹底把我們黑了
Yo, what we about to do?
我們該怎麼辦？
First thing we're gonna do,
we're gonna sue this ignorant fuck.
首先我們得指控他寫的這些歌詞
That's what we're gonna do.
我們一定要這麼做
Defamation of character,
libel, I don't really care.
告他惡意誹謗、人格侮辱什麼的都行，老子不在乎
That anti-Semitic piece of fuckin' shit.
Who the fuck does he think he is?
他竟然提出反猶太，操，這混蛋，他把自己當成誰了？
Un-fucking-believable.
真是難以置信
That kind of fucking bullshit!
Jew-bashing bullshit!
一派胡言！這些反猶太人的髒話！
You know what?
I'll call my friend at the JDL.
總之我這就要打電話找我在猶太人聯合協會裡的朋友
They'll handle him.
We'll see how much he likes that.
他們那邊會處理的，到時候看看是誰付出代價
Jerry, you gotta relax. Ar'ight?
Jerry你冷靜一點，行吧
Niggas don't even know what
anti-Semitic means anyway.
我們黑人壓根就不知道什麼叫“反猶太”
It's just a fucking battle rap.
這只是說唱歌手們之間的較量
Come on, Eric, we gotta get organized.
聽好 Eric 我們要團結一心
We got to fight this kinda
ignorant fucking bullshit.
我們要堅決和他的這些胡言亂語鬥爭到底
You know what? I always knew
that he was a hateful human being.
你知道麼，我很早就看出來他是個滿懷戾氣的傢伙
This is just ignorant shit.
他竟然想玩這一套？
He calls it political?
This is ignorant shit!
這就是赤裸裸的人身攻擊
I always knew it.
Now the whole world is gonna know.
我一直都清楚他的為人，現在我要讓全世界的人知道
I'm gonna make sure of that. Okay?
而且我會說到做到
I don't understand why the fuck
you're not more angry about this?
我真是不明白，你們怎麼一個個無動於衷的？
- Did you hear what he said?
- I heard what he said!
你聽到他說什麼了麼？我聽到了！
- Did you hear what he said?
- I heard what he said!
你聽到他說什麼了麼？我他媽聽到了！
About you? About me? Come on!
關於你，還有我的這些事？你聽聽！
You got your way
of dealing with it, I got mine.
你有你的做法，我也有我自己的套路
We could just go the studio
and just end his fucking career anyway.
我們可以到錄音棚裡錄歌回擊，就此葬送他的音樂事業
I don't know about all that.
這點我可不敢擔保
Fine, you do that.
You call Dre, and you guys go do that.
好，你們去吧，叫上Dre，你們一起去解決這件事情
Do something!
趕緊回擊
Damn, E. Who work for who?
真草蛋，E，誰給誰打工？
What? You questioning that?
什麼？你對此抱有懷疑？
My position is fucking solidified!
我的地位不容動搖！
Don't never question that shit!
別再讓我聽到這種問題！
Fuckin' Cube, man!
該死的 Cube
Nigga.
哥們
Hey, there go the nigga Cube right there.
嘿，那不是Cube麼？
What that Ruthless like, nigga?
Ruthless唱片嚇到你了麼？
Fuck Ruthless! This Lench Mob, nigga.
Ruthless死一邊去，我們Lench Mobb最牛逼！
- Fuck Lench Mob.
- Come here, motherfucker.
去你媽的  -  來啊，混蛋
Oh, shit!
我靠
Shit!
操
Oh, shit!
媽蛋
Motherfucker!
去你媽
<i>We've all seen the pictures
of Los Angeles police officers</i>
我們都看到了這一幕，幾名洛杉磯警員
<i>beating a man they had just pulled over.</i>
不停毆打一個他們逼停的公民
<i>The city's police chief said today</i>
今天警署總長說
<i>he will support criminal charges
against some of the men.</i>
他會支援對其中幾個警員的刑事指控
<i>Here's ABC's Gary Shepard.</i>
這是來自ABC的最新報導
At least we got the motherfuckers on video.
至少這次我們有了確鑿的視頻證據
LAPD gonna have a real good time
on that level three prison yard.
洛杉磯的條子要在三級牢獄裡面吃苦頭了
You know what I'm saying?
你懂的吧
Dre, maybe we should
try to get back to work.
Dre，也許我們該把重心放回工作上了
We are working, Jerry.
我們正在工作 Jerry
I'm having a word with my client.
我是跟我的藝人說話呢
Man, hold up, man! We got this!
等等吧，我們都一塊的
Nah. We got it.
我們才是一塊的
You done? Suge?
你們吵夠了？Suge？
Jerry? E? Huh?
Jerry？E？嗯？
<i>Brutality and misconduct
that goes back a quarter of a century</i>
這樣不當的使用暴力簡直是歷史的倒退
<i>including one incident
that sparked the Watts Riots.</i>
而包括這次引起騷亂的事件在內
<i>So far this year,
there have been more than 125</i>
今年，到現在為止，各監管部門
<i>complaints of police misconduct</i>
收到針對員警濫用職權的投訴
<i>filed with watchdog organizations.</i>
數量已經超過125件
Yo, Dre. Hold up.
喲，Dre，等等
Look, I did what you asked me to do.
上次你找我說的事情
I had my people look at your contracts.
我找人幫你看了你的合同
It didn't look good.
看上去不是太好
But you gotta watch your back.
不過你得小心點
What you mean by that?
你這話什麼意思？
Look, everything you need to know is here.
你需要瞭解的資訊，都在這裡了
And you know I can help you with this.
你知道，我是可以幫你的
May I help you with something?
你有事麼？
This your house?
這是你房子？
Who's asking?
你是誰？
It's a nice house.
房子蠻漂亮的
Who are you? You're with Suge Knight?
你到底是誰？Suge Knight的手下？
Someone else? Ice Cube?
還是別的什麼人？Ice Cube ?
Have yourself a good night.
好好享受今晚
Jerry.
Jerry
Shit.
靠
#NowPlaying: "Appetite for Destruction" by N.W.A
<i>... first to get shot.
Whoever said that what I say and portray is negativity.</i>
人們他們總以為我們在歌裡抹黑街頭
<i>Need to come kick it in the city with me.</i>
如果你不信，那就跟我一起來貧民區
<i>And find the black and crack de fact.</i>
來看看真實存在的黑暗
<i>And take that shit back cuz they don't wanna fuck with that.</i>
然後他們就會收回自己的評價，因為他們害怕
<i>There's too many niggas they're tryin' to calm.</i>
街區裡混子太多，條子管不了
<i>If mothafuckaz could get it, nobody would've fuck with it.</i>
如果生活很容易，那才沒人鋌而走險呢
<i>Appetite for destruction.</i>
嘗試毀滅的欲望
<i>For him to get a bit more shit he gotta commit...</i>
想要得到錢和名聲，你就必須犯罪
So, wassup?
怎麼了？
When you talked to me on the phone, man,
you sounded pretty worked up.
你給我打電話的時候，感覺你狀態不太好
Yeah, I know you don't
like hearing this shit.
我知道你不想聽這些
It's about Jerry.
We gotta get rid of that motherfucker, E.
是關於Jerry的，我們必須擺脫這傢伙，E
That's really why you came here?
你就為了這個來？
I thought all this shit
was in the past, Dre.
我以為過去的事不再提了，Dre
I found some real shit, man. And the shit's
been happening since the beginning.
我發現了一些事情，這些圈套在一開始就有了
I had some people look into this.
I ain't been gettin' my fair share.
我找人看了一下合同，我並沒得到應得的報酬
Do you even know why you rich, though?
你知道為什麼你可以像今天這樣有錢？
Do you know why you got
a big-ass house and you
知道為什麼你會擁有豪宅
ain't sleepin' on your
auntie's couch no more?
而不是繼續睡在你阿姨的沙發上？
Because Jerry made that possible for us.
是Jerry讓這一切成為現實的！
He kicked down the door
for that shit to happen. For us!
他為我們打開了成功之門
And you just gonna turn your back on him?
What, you Cube now?
現在你想把他甩掉？ 像Cube一樣？
Cube was right, fool!
Cube是對的，傻瓜！
E, look at the papers, man, and you'll
see what the fuck I'm talking about.
E 看看合同吧，你就明白了我說的什麼意思
And forget about Jerry, man! You keep
talking about Jerry this, Jerry that.
還有別再三句話不離Jerry了，你總說Jerry這 Jerry那的
We didn't make it because of Jerry,
we made it because our shit is dope!
我們成功不是因為Jerry，是因為我們的歌牛逼
And we can keep going, E.
而我們可以繼續下去
We can own the goddamn world, but we
just can't be fucking with him no more.
咱們可以擁有整個世界，只是前提必須要甩開那個老狐狸
Man, we started this N.W.A shit.
咱們幾個一手建立了N.W.A.
I just want it to be right.
所以我想讓它繼續走在正道上
And this what you think right?
這就是你所謂的正道？
Turnin' your back on somebody
after all he done for us.
背棄一個為你竭盡全力做事的人？
You mean all he done for you.
你是指為你做的事吧？
Right?
是嗎？
Look at me.
看著我
When Tyree died,
Tyree死的時候
you said we was always gonna be brothers.
你說我們會做一輩子的兄弟
I guess you forgot about that.
我想你大概忘了這些諾言了
I'mma start my own company
with Suge Knight, E.
我要和Suge Knight一起創辦公司了，E
Thought we were brothers, man.
我還以為我們是兄弟呢
#NowPlaying: "Deep Cover" by Dr. Dre, Snoop Dogg
What up, Dre?
你好，Dre
This Death Row. We about to do this shit.
Death Row廠牌， 我們要大幹一場了！
This shit sound good.
這首聽起來贊
Yeah. None of it means anything
while I'm under contract with Ruthless.
嗯，但只要我和Ruthless的合同還在，這些就都沒實際意義
I told you about that.
這個和你說過了
I'mma get you outta your contracts,
I promise you.
我會讓你順利解約的，我保證
Yeah, ar'ight.
嗯，好吧
What up with you, cuz?
怎麼樣啊哥幾個？
Wuddup?
你好
What up, Lo?
你好啊，哥們
Wuddup, Dre?
你好，Dre
- Wassup, Warren?
- Chilin' man.
你好，Warren  - 還不錯哈
- You good?
- I'm great. You good?
怎麼樣？  -  挺好，你呢
- All right.
- Dr. Dre.
不錯，不錯  -  Dr. Dre
- 'Sup?
- Wuddup with you?
你好  -  你好哥們
What's goin' on, man?
怎麼樣啊，哥們
Yeah, yeah.
嗯，嗯
So, look, I listened to your demo.
對了，我聽了你的試音小樣
It was tight.
很不錯
You see that little look he gave me?
你看到他表情了？
Yo, yo, yo, hold up.
Who the fuck is this guy?
喲，喲，等等，這傢伙是誰？
My bad, Suge. This the homie, Snoop.
噢，不好意思Suge，這是Snoop
Snoop D-O-double-G, cuz. Who you?
Snoop D-O-G-G ，你誰啊？
What? What up?
什麼？
What the fuck you say, Blood?
你小子說什麼？
Hold on! Hold on, hold on.
He with me. He with me.
等等，等等，他是我朋友
He ain't with me.
他可不是我朋友
Nah! He here to work, ar'ight?
This is business, Suge. Come on, man.
他是來錄歌的，都為了工作，Suge
Anyway, what's this
you workin' on, cuz, I like this.
你這首歌是什麼來頭？很帶感
So look, you know...
這個嘛
It's a new track for this new movie.
It's called <i>Deep Cover.</i>
是給電影《臥底戰警》配的主題曲
- Woo-wee.
- Yeah. Yeah, yeah.
哇噢，真的？  -  嗯
- For a movie, huh?
- Yeah, a movie.
給電影配的？ -  是的
Dre doing big shit. Okay, okay, okay.
Dre 你玩得夠大啊
You think you can get down on it?
你想想你能唱一段麼？
Oh, most definitely.
Throw me in the booth one time.
沒問題，讓我進去試試
All right.
好的
<i>It's perhaps the most notorious
police brutality case in recent memory.</i>
這也許是近期以來最臭名昭著的員警劣行
<i>Those blows from
Officer Powell and Officer Wind's batons</i>
Powell 和 Wind 兩位警員對受害人的毆打持續不斷
<i>continued and continued for no just reason.</i>
而這毫無公正的理由
They just let them people do
whatever the hell they want.
他們就讓底下的人為所欲為
<i>Rodney King's leg
and facial bones were broken.</i>
受害人Rodney King 的腿骨、面骨均有骨折
<i>Three of the four accused officers took
the stand and admitted that it was brutal,</i>
4位被指控的警員中3位在法庭承認了其暴行
<i>but said, "Police work is brutal."
And that the video tape only showed that.</i>
但卻認定員警的暴力是正確的
Here.
你的電話
- Who is it?
- I don't know.
誰打的？ - 不知道
You watchin' this shit upstairs?
你在樓上看這段新聞了麼？
Hello?
你好
<i>Yo, it's Suge.</i>
我是Suge
<i>We gotta talk about these contracts.</i>
我們得談談合同的事情了
Why you don't talk to
Jerry about that shit?
為什麼不找Jerry談？
<i>I don't wanna talk to Jerry.
It's your company. You the man.</i>
我不想跟他談，你是公司老闆，你管事
Ar'ight. Whatever, man.
I'll be through there.
好，隨便你，我一會過去
- Who was that?
- Nobody.
誰打來的？ - 沒誰
<i>Right across the top of the cheekbone,</i>
在這個部位，把他的臉從耳朵
<i>splitting his face
from the top of his ear to his chin.</i>
上端到下巴打成重傷錯位
Where Dre at?
Dre 呢？
You said he was gonna be here.
你說過他會來的
I'll get with you outside.
你先出去等我
Don't worry about Dre.
別管Dre了
Truth be told,
he got nothing to do with this.
實話跟你講，他對此毫不知情
This what's gonna happen.
現在情況是這樣的
You gonna sign these,
releasing Dre and D.O.C. from Ruthless.
你要在這合同上簽字，讓Dre和D.O.C.與Ruthless正式解除關係
Whatever, homie.
是嗎，哥們
Think I'm signing that?
You crazier than I thought you was.
我覺得我會簽？ 你比我想像的更狂
I'm out.
我走了
Get your ass up.
站起來
Nah. I think you're gonna
stay here for a while.
那，我想你要在這多呆一會兒了
Fuck you, Suge!
Y'all niggas don't scare me.
去你的，Suge，你們嚇不倒我
You can talk tough all you want,
but this ain't no record.
隨你怎麼虛張聲勢，反正沒什麼用
Don't make me change you, Eric.
別逼我給你下狠手
Fuck that's supposed to mean?
你想怎麼樣
Keep talkin',
you're gonna fuck around and get smoked.
你接著逞強的話，等會兒就好好教訓你
Nah, nah.
But you better choose right.
仔細想想吧
You know where the fuck I'm from.
This Bompton, nigga.
你知道我來自哪裡麼？我來自康普頓的血幫
Oh, my fucking God.
噢，我的老天
Eric.
Eric
Jesus Christ.
我的天啊
What the hell are you doing here?
You can't sneak in here like that.
你怎麼進來的，你不能偷偷摸摸就過來啊
I thought you were...
我還以為你……
Oh, my God. What's going on, man?
Are you okay?
天呐，什麼情況，你還好麼？
What happened to your face?
你得臉這是怎麼了？
I gotta kill this motherfucker,
Suge Knight.
我要宰了Suge Knight這個人渣
I just came here to let you know,
我就是想來告訴你這件事
'cause shit might get a little thick.
I need to stay protected.
事情越來越危險了，你要保護好自己
No, you're not gonna do that. No.
不，你別做傻事，不
I didn't come here to ask for permission.
我不是來這徵求你意見的
I came here to let you know.
我只是來告訴你一聲
You wanted to be involved
with this gangster shit?
你想踏入這些幫派的紛爭麼
Here we go.
一塊搞吧
You do that and you're gonna ruin
everything we've worked for.
你要真這麼幹，咱們就前功盡棄了
You really think I got a fucking choice?
你覺得我還有選擇麼？
Look at my face!
看看我的臉
This the streets. Motherfuckers came at me!
這就是街頭，他們擺明是沖著我來的
Came at us!
沖著咱們來的
If I don't hit back, we finished.
It's over.
如果不回擊，我們就等死吧
I'm not saying that we're
not gonna hit back.
我不是說不回擊
But this is not Compton,
但這裡不是康普頓
if you haven't looked around.
看看這周圍
Drop that shit, okay?
打消這念頭，好麼？
We don't hit back with bullets,
we hit back with lawyers.
咱們不需要用子彈反擊，咱們可以請律師
We drain these assholes.
咱們榨幹他們的老本
That really takes 'em down.
自然他們就會垮臺
It ain't about the money, Jerry!
這跟錢沒關係 Jerry
I don't care about no money.
我不在乎錢
Of course it is. And you should
fucking care about the money.
當然離不開錢的關係，你也理應要在乎這些錢
You're so much smarter
than these fuckin' thugs.
你比那些混混要聰明太多了
You wanna kill somebody?
你想殺人麼？
You're gonna go to jail forever.
那只會讓你下半輩子過鐵窗生涯
No more family,
no more Ruthless, no more anything.
失去家庭、失去公司，一無所有
If you kill this man,
his problems will be over
你殺了他，關於他的麻煩是解決了
and yours will just be beginning.
可你的問題就來了
Don't be a fuckin' fool.
千萬別做傻事
Hey.
嘿
Why the fuck I gotta be the bigger man?
我為什麼要做好人？
'Cause it's better than
you being a dead man.
因為做好人總比做死人強
I don't want you fuckin' dead.
而我可不想看到你死
You okay?
你還好嗎
Baby. Let me see.
寶貝，讓我看看
- Why you so tense, Dre?
- No, I'm cool.
你最近怎麼不在狀態？  - 沒啊，還好
Man. No, you're not, man.
哥們，你確實不在狀態
You've been in that house, what?
A month now?
你在工作室待了差不多一個月了
Nigga, and not one track?
I mean, what's up?
然後居然一首歌都沒寫出來，怎麼了？
There's too much interference.
有太多干擾了
Man, you know how they
tryin' to starve me out.
你知道嗎有很多人想榨幹我
Playin' games with
my motherfuckin' money, man.
跟我玩各種花招就是想套我的錢
That's why the house
was so goddamned empty.
怪不得你那間房裡沒人住
- Hey, come on, man.
- I'm fucking with you, cuz. Hit this.
別生氣，我跟你逗樂呢，你試試這個
- All right, man, give me that shit.
- Here.
好吧，給我  - 給
Fuck I'm taking about.
這個給勁
Have you feeling righteously together.
這玩意絕對給你滿滿正能量
- Holy shit.
- Oh, hell no. Give me that.
我靠！ -  來，給我
Goddamn, man!
What the fuck is in this shit, Snoops?
我！靠！ - Snoop你抽的這是什麼鬼
- That right there, that's that chronic, cuz.
- Yeah.
這個勁兒特別大，叫Chronic
- Chronic.
- Yes, sir.
Chronic  -  沒錯
- Let me hit that once.
- Yeah.
我也抽一口  -  來
- Look it.
- Wow, man.
試試  -  哇喔
- All right. Let's head back to the studio.
- Let's go.
好，走，我們回工作室  -  走吧
I got something for this.
我來靈感了
Damn, Dre.
What the fuck is that? Feeling that shit.
喔，Dre你做的這歌有點意思
- Yeah. You feelin' it?
- Yeah!
有感覺嗎？  -  嗯！
Hey, hey, look,
I'mma spit a little something.
嘿，來，我要即興來一段
You feel me? You say whatever...
你找找感覺，先試試
You just jump in, nigga, and just...
你直接開始就行，來吧
Hold on, look, I got something. Here we go.
我想想，有了，走起來
#Rap: "Nuthin' But A G Thang" by Dr. Dre & Snoop Dogg
<i>One, two, three and to the four.</i>
一，二，三，然後是四
<i>Snoop Doggy Dogg and Dr.
Dre is at the door.</i>
Snoop Dogg和Dr.Dre要大開殺戒了
<i>Ready to make an entrance so back on up</i>
準備好破門而入所以請有所防備
<i>'Cause you know we about to rip shit up.</i>
因為你知道我們會撕碎一切
<i>Give me the microphone first</i>
給我一個麥克風
<i>so I could bust like a bubble.</i>
我先給你來一段炫技
<i>Compton and Long Beach together</i>
康普頓和長島的組合
<i>now you know you in trouble.</i>
你知道你有麻煩了
<i>Ain't nothin' but a G thang, baby.</i>
只不過是幫派那些事兒，寶貝
<i>Two loc'ed out niggas so we're crazy.</i>
兩個無法無天的哥們，我們都瘋了
<i>Death Row is the label that pays me.</i>
“死囚區”是給我發薪水的廠牌
<i>Un-fadable so please
don't try and fade this.</i>
我們不可侵犯，所以別再試圖招惹我們
<i>But back to the lecture at hand.</i>
但是，嗯，說到身邊的事兒
<i>Perfection is perfected...</i>
一切都很完美……
I want to thank you
for having us here.
感謝你接受我們的採訪
- Of course.
- Very generous for you to give your time
沒事  -  你現在這麼忙
with everything that's going on right now.
還能抽出時間錄這個訪談
Not a problem.
沒事
Now if I may,
冒昧地問一句
are you anti-Semitic?
請問你反猶太人麼
Now, I thought
this was about the Rodney King trial.
我還以為你是為了員警打人的事件來的
Well, the JDL recently got involved
現在猶太人保護協會已經開始關注了
citing the lyrics about
your former manager Jerry Heller.
他們引用的就是你之前講到你前經紀人的那些歌詞
I'm not anti-Semitic.
I'm anti-Jerry Heller.
我不是反猶太人，我是反Jerry Heller
Let me ask you something.
我要反問你
Do the JDL condone Jerry's behavior
when it comes to my situation?
Jerry 想讓我在沒有法人代表的情況下簽合同
Him trying to get me to sign a contract
without legal representation?
猶太人保護協會，他們會無視並容忍Jerry的所作所為麼？
I have no idea.
這點我並不知情
I didn't think you did.
是啊，想必你也不知道
But when you got that for me,
we can continue on this topic.
當你瞭解清楚這個情況了，咱再好好談談這話題
Until then, I'm here to talk about the
beating of an unarmed motorist, Rodney King.
但在那之前，我會一直探討員警對手無寸鐵的公民的毆打事件
And four guilty LAPD officers
who seem to be Daryl Gates' standard issue.
那四個有罪的洛杉磯員警，才應該是局長應該負責的事情
It's also the LAPD and the FBI
洛杉磯警局和聯邦調查局認為
who feel that your negative portrayal
of police condones violence.
你在歌詞裡對員警的反面塑造也是一種暴行
"Fuck Tha Police" is just a warning,
that's it.
《Fuck The Police》這首單曲只是個警告而已
You can't treat people like that
and expect 'em not to rise up.
你這樣欺壓人民，還想大家不做出反抗？
I'm a journalist just like you.
我就像你一樣也是個記者
Reporting what's goin' on in the hood.
我用說唱報導街區裡的真實情形
The only thing that's different
is that I'm brutally honest.
而咱倆的區別就是，我從不隱瞞事實
What's your relationship
with the Nation of Islam?
那你和伊斯蘭民族組織的關係怎麼樣？
They my brothers.
他們就像是我的兄弟
You know what?
That question right there proves to me
你知道嗎，你問這個問題
what kind of a unprepared
sandbag reporter you are.
就說明你根本就沒做功課
You talkin' to me
like I'm some elected official.
你問我的語氣好像我是什麼政要官員
Like I'm running for office.
好像我是競選的候選人一樣
But I get it, that's your job.
但我明白，這就是你的工作
Bigger the story,
the bigger the check in your field of work.
誇誇其談，渲染著事實，這樣你的報酬就越豐厚
It's not your fault, I shouldn't blame you.
What's your name, man?
這不是你的錯，我不該指責你，你怎麼稱呼？
Brian.
Brian
Eat a dick, Brian.
Get the fuck out my house. Y'all done here.
滾出我房子，Brian，採訪到此結束
Can we cut, please?
切掉這段好麼？
#NowPlaying: "One Nation Under a Groove" by Funkadelic
Excuse me, excuse me,
excuse me, excuse me.
不好意思，不好意思
You look like you ready to go.
你要準備走了？
Yeah. I'm just waiting on my friend.
I should've drove.
是啊我在等我朋友，我應該開車過來才對
You're not havin' a good time?
玩的不盡興？
No! No. I had a really good time,
沒有啊，玩得挺好的
but now it's starting to get a little wild.
不過感覺有一點點玩過頭了
Yeah.
是啊
We've been known to get crazy
from time to time.
我們有時候偶爾會瘋狂一下
I'm Andre.
我叫Andre
I'm Nicole.
我叫Nicloe
Come on, man. Lighten up.
好了，往好處看
We're about to get back in the game.
Big time.
我們就要殺回圈子裡了
- Yeah?
- Yeah.
是嗎？  -  是啊
How do you figure?
你為什麼這麼覺得
Are you trying to piss me off?
Come on. God almighty.
你是故意氣我嗎？行了吧，我的老天
Did you forget about Ren's new album?
你忘了 Ren 要發行新專輯了？
Or did you forget about the fact
that you are working on something
難道你也不記得，你自己也正要做一些新作品嗎
I think is gonna be bigger
than anything N.W.A ever did.
我覺得這些新作品的高度會超越N.W.A.的水準
All I know... Mmm!
我只知道…… 嗯
Fucking Cube out here,
他媽的 Cube 現在火了
- doing it big. Making movies and shit.
- Oh, yeah, yeah, yeah.
他太火了，還拍電影呢  -  好吧，好吧
Then I keep hearing about
this album Dre about to drop.
而且我還一直聽人說 Dre 做了一張專輯準備發行
Dre is a fucking producer, Eric.
Dre只是個製作人
Producers don't rap.
製作人還能說唱？
We have him under contract.
He can't do anything.
而且他還在我們的合約裡，他不能發專輯
Cheer up.
高興點兒
Eat, drink and be merry.
吃吃喝喝，享受生活，還有結個婚
- Suge.
- Hey.
Suge  -  嘿
- How you doin'?
- All right.
你好嗎  -  還好
Jimmy Iovine, Interscope Records.
Nice to meet you.
我是 Interscope唱片公司的Jimmy，很高興見到你
You, too.
我也是
So, what do I call you?
Dre? Dr. Dre? Doc?
我應該怎麼稱呼你呢 Dre？Dr.Dre？Doc？
Nah, Dre is cool. Go ahead, have a seat.
Dre就行了，請坐吧
All right.
好的
- It's good.
- Yeah.
還好吧  -  嗯
So what do you got today?
今天要談的是什麼？
Um...
呃
Well, you know...
你也知道……
I heard John McClain gave you my album.
What'd you think?
我聽說John Maclean把我的唱片給你了，你覺得怎麼樣
I think it was great.
我覺得很棒
So, you're the artist on the record.
Who produced it?
嗯，你是歌手，那麼誰是製作人？
I did.
我啊
Okay. And who mixed it?
好，那誰做的混音？
Come on, man. I did.
哈，還是我
Huh.
嗯
Listen, um...
這樣……
I don't know anything about hip-hop,
我對說唱不甚精通
but I know that this is special.
但是我知道你的東西十分特別
Seriously.
非常認真
Thank you.
謝謝
Hey, look, we'd love
to bring in Interscope,
我們很樂意和Interscope合作
but there's a little problem.
但我們有一個問題
What's the problem?
什麼問題？
Ruthless, lawsuits,
Ruthless的合同
and contracts.
會有一些法律糾紛
How about this?
這樣如何
You give me three weeks
and I don't wanna hear any bullshit
你給我三周時間，這期間
about you shopping this
anywhere around town.
你們儘量低調，別試圖四處兜售這些唱片
If you do that...
如果你們做得到
I believe I can solve your problem
with the contract.
我相信我能搞定你合約上的問題
Lil' nigga, you in my spot.
喂，小子，你占了我的車位！
- Yo.
- Hey, Suge.
喲  -  嘿 Suge
Suge. Easy, man. Yo.
Suge，別這樣……
Hey, Suge, what the...
嘿 Suge，怎麼了
Hey. Suge.
嘿 Suge
You parked in my
motherfuckin' spot or what?
你他媽的占了我的停車位！
- I didn't know, man.
- It's cool, man.
我不知道是你的  -  冷靜點
What the fuck? Suge!
搞什麼，Suge！
Suge, it's just a parking spot.
只是一個停車位而已
Fuck off. Fuck out of my...
別碰我，閃開
Move this piece of shit.
把這破車挪走
And park my car.
把我的車停好
And I better not see
one drop of blood on that motherfucker.
別他媽的把血蹭到我車上
Suge, let's go, man.
Suge，我們走吧
What?
怎麼！？
<i>The jury in the Rodney King case
has delivered its verdict,</i>
陪審團就員警毆打 Rodney King 一案
<i>and not one of the four police officers</i>
作出判決如下：一年前錄影帶上那些
<i>seen on video tape
beating Mr. King a year ago</i>
毆打 Rodney King 的四位員警的行為
<i>is guilty of using excessive force.</i>
都被認為，並非濫用武力
<i>They've all been found not guilty.</i>
他們全部被判無罪
For Christ's sake. Oh, my God.
哦，我的天呐，天呐
<i>Judy, the details.</i>
請聽進一步報導
<i>Peter, it was a clean sweep
for the defendants.</i>
針對被告人的指控都被洗去
<i>Not guilty, the verdict for all of them.</i>
被告全部無罪，法庭認定指控無效
<i>Only on one count against
Lawrence Powell...</i>
除了其中一項指控
I'm sorry.
很抱歉
<i>On excessive use of force
under color of authority.</i>
以執法為名過度使用武力
對毆打黑人的白人員警的判決，引發了著名的洛杉磯暴亂
<i>It's probably the worst case</i>
這是我見過的員警暴力中
<i>of police misconduct that I've ever seen.</i>
最糟糕的一例案件
<i>I think it was devastating
to the image of this city</i>
我認為這對我們城市的形象是一個毀滅性打擊
<i>and especially to our police department.</i>
尤其是對我們執法機構來說……
<i>It looks
kind of like we're in a war zone though.</i>
這裡好像戰爭爆發了一樣
<i>We've got some courageous
shop owners here, who are armed...</i>
一些大膽的店主武裝了起來……
<i>Anarchy is obviously
a statement of political dissatisfaction.</i>
無政府主義思潮由於這些不滿而滋生
<i>Police officers
are still back down,</i>
員警依然在堅守
<i>guarding the area
down there with the Ralph's...</i>
保衛著那些區域……
<i>The police
are using eerily reminiscent</i>
警方為了執行任務，使用了
<i>of military-style assault weapons.</i>
殺傷力強的軍用武器……
<i>You can hear
random gunshots as rioters...</i>
在這裡，你隨時可以聽到槍聲
<i>The cars
have been left abandoned</i>
有些車被遺棄在街頭
<i>because their drivers came under attack...</i>
因為他們的車主被傷……
<i>our city.
We have fires burning.</i>
示威者在城市裡縱火
<i>Olympic, Pico, Wilshire.</i>
多個地區發生暴亂
<i>More than 100 injured,</i>
傷者已經超過百人……
暴亂持續了幾十個小時，暴亂中死亡人數超過50人
<i>mostly in the South-Central
section of Los Angeles.</i>
暴動集中在洛杉磯南部中心地區
You know, If we bag all this shit up in
ounces, we should probably be straight.
聽著，把這些東西分成一盎司一盎司的小包就沒事了
I think we got enough.
我想這些就夠了
No, turn it down. Turn it down.
小點聲，調小點聲
Baby. Can you smoke that shit out there?
寶貝，你可以到外面抽嗎
So, all this weed is for
your Ruthless artists?
這些都是給你們Ruthless藝人的？
Yeah, I mean, shit.
對，是啊
I'm tryin' to take care
of these little money problems, man.
我正在想辦法解決咱們錢的問題
So, they can smoke it, sell it.
他們可以自己抽，或者賣
Fuck, throw a party on it,
for all I give a fuck.
為此開一個派對也可以，無所謂
As long as I just...
只要我還……
Yo, man, you straight?
你還好吧？
- E, you straight?
- Yeah, I'm good.
E，你還好吧？ -  我還好
- No, for real, man. You straight?
- Man, I'm good!
說真的，你還好嘛？ -  我很好！
I'm just fucking tired, man.
只不過有點累
I'm fucking downgrading houses.
How would you feel?
我現在要換小房子住了，你想想什麼感受！
Answer me that!
你說啊
Dre rolled out. Ruthless money low.
Dre走了，Ruthless缺錢了
Tomica asking me all kind of questions
about the house.
Tomica 對房子的事情問這問那
Tomica，Eazy-E的老婆，後來掌管Ruthless唱片公司
Answer me this, would you be all right?
你說你會沒事嗎？
Would you be all right
moving out your fucking house?
被迫搬出家門你會啥事沒有嗎？
You all right with it?
你會嗎？！
E, I'm your boy. I'm in this shit with you.
E，我一直跟著你，我跟你共患難啊哥們
I'm just trying to make
sure you're good, bro.
我只是想確認你沒什麼事兒
I'm good! You good?
我很好！你呢？
- You good?
- Yeah, man.
你好嗎？  -  我沒事
Eric.
Eric
What, Jerry?
怎麼了 Jerry？
Take it easy.
放鬆點
You know what?
Let's get you outta the house.
我跟你說，我們出去一趟吧
I have stuff needs your autograph, okay?
有些檔要你的簽字，走吧？
I'll come when I have time, Jerry.
我有時間就去
Eric, come on.
Eric，走吧
We still got a business to run.
我們還有生意要處理
Don't it look like
I'm running business right now?
我他媽不是正在處理生意嗎！
No. It looks like
you're fucking cutting up weed.
不，你在切你的大麻
I thought that was a job
for fucking jackasses.
這他媽是地痞無賴幹的活兒
You know what, Jerry?
好吧，Jerry
You right. You absolutely fuckin' right.
你說對了，真他媽說對了
We got business to take care of.
我們的確有生意在處理
I'll see you in a minute.
我一會兒就過去
You all right, E?
沒事吧 E
E, are you cool?
E 你還好嗎？
Eric.
Eric
"You got knocked the fuck out."
“你他媽出局了”哈哈
Ice Cube 的電影 Friday 的臺詞
That shit's funny.
太逗了
- Hey, baby.
嘿，寶貝  -  嗨，寶貝
How's <i>Friday</i> coming?
《星期五》劇本寫的怎麼樣了
This shit is funny. I'm feeling it, though.
挺好玩的，我正來靈感呢
What page are you on?
你寫到第幾頁了
100. I'm not going too much longer, though.
一百頁吧，我不會寫太久
Baby, come here. Look!
寶貝，來，你看看
Look how young y'all are.
那時候你們好年輕啊
Shit.
嗯…
Dang!
哈
What?
怎麼
We left a lot of good records on the table.
我們做了很多很棒的專輯
<i>It's like
I don't even know what I'm doing no more.</i>
我好像，已經不知道我在幹嘛了
I don't know where the money going.
我也不知道錢都到哪去了
Why you stressin'?
你幹嘛壓力這麼大？
You know I know the business.
這行生意我還是挺懂
Just... Shit.
只是，唉
Lay out all the files,
contracts, whatever it is,
你的文件啊，合同啊什麼的拿給我
and I'll look into it.
我幫你看看
For real. Come here.
真的，來吧
Come here.
來嘛
You just go to New York,
你只需要去紐約
you take care of this
big ol' distribution deal with Sony.
跟SONY簽好分銷合同
Bring that shit on in.
把這個事兒搞定
All right?
And I'll check into everything else.
好吧？其他事兒我來負責
I love you.
我愛你
You what?
你什麼？
I love you.
我愛你
You what? I can't hear you.
你什麼？我聽不見
So how's your home life, man?
最近的家庭生活怎麼樣？
What? That small-ass house
I just moved into in Norwalk?
你說我最近剛搬的那個小房子？
Fuckin' hate it.
很不爽
No, come on. You know what I mean.
不是，你知道我的意思
I mean your love life, Eric. Hmm?
我的意思是，愛情生活，對吧
You seem pretty serious about this girl.
你好像對這個姑娘動真心了
- I ain't in love.
- Oh? You had me scared there for a minute.
我沒有  -  噢？嚇我一跳，還真有點像真的
You're too young to settle down.
你現在穩定下來結婚確實還太早
Well, you don't have to be scared of that.
嗯，你不用怕這個
Oh, man. Wait till you taste this.
哦對了，等你嘗嘗這個
Kung Pao chicken.
宮保雞丁
Fantastic.
非常棒
And it is better the second day.
放一段時間味道更好
There you go.
來，給你
Dig in.
試試
So, where is this girl from again?
這個姑娘是從哪來的來著？
Look, Jerry.
嘿 Jerry
I actually ate right before I came.
我來之前吃過了
So I'm just gonna take this and go.
我只是來拿這個走
Hold on. Hold on. Where are you going?
等等，等等，你要去哪啊
I just came to get this.
我只是來拿這個
These are my bills, my checks.
這些是我的帳單
Look, I'm gonna have a bite of your food.
你看，你準備的吃的，我嘗一下
I'm gonna say farewell.
我就先走了
I'll talk to you later.
回頭再聯繫
Your neighbors,
they've been complaining a lot.
你的鄰居跟我抱怨了幾次
The noise.
啪啪啪的聲音
Stop.
討厭
I just think a little
privacy would be better.
有一點咱們自己的空間不是更好嗎
So what? You want me to move?
怎麼，你是要我搬去你家
Yeah.
是啊
And I...
You know, I happen to know of a place.
我，剛好知道一個地方
There's plenty of room,
and I know the owner.
有很多房間，我又剛好認識房主
Are you sure you're ready for that, Andre?
你真的準備好同居了嗎，Andre
Yeah, I am.
是啊
'Cause I'm really feeling you like that.
我已經準備好跟你一起生活
I'm really feeling you too.
我也有這樣的想法
But...
但……
Hey, don't even worry about it.
It was just a thought.
嘿，你也不用太多慮，只是個想法而已
What's up?
怎麼了
All right. Good night.
好啦，晚安
Oh, whoa, whoa! Really? Good night?
等等，什麼，晚安？
You okay to drive?
你能開車嗎？
No. Look at you.
不了，看看你
Good night, Andre.
晚安吧，Andre
Nah. See...
別，你看
See, I can't help thinking,
我一直在想，你是不是
maybe you want me to come inside.
會邀請我去你家
Of course I do.
我是想啊
So, what's different now?
那現在又有什麼不可？
I got a lot to think about.
我得好好考慮
You're asking me to move in with you.
你要我搬去跟你一起住
That is a huge step!
這可是一大步
I like you, Andre,
Andre 我喜歡你
but there's a lot going on around you.
但你身邊事兒太多了
Whatchu mean?
什麼意思？
I know about the whole Death Row business,
我知道你們Death Row的運作方式
the assault charges,
還有那些指控
the shooting.
甚至還有開槍什麼的
Just seems dangerous.
看起來都太危險了
My son is my world.
我兒子就是我的全部
I hear you.
我明白了
Good night.
晚安
#Rap: "Hail Mary" by 2Pac
<i>Hail Mary, run quick see.</i>
向心中的聖人祈禱
<i>What do we have here now?</i>
我們又面臨什麼選擇
<i>Do you wanna ride or die?</i>
是否能忘乎生死去奔命
<i>I ain't a killer but don't push me.</i>
我不是殺人狂，但別逼我
<i>Revenge is like
the sweetest joy next to getting pussy.</i>
復仇的感覺跟做愛一樣爽
<i>Picture paragraphs unloaded
Wise words being quoted.</i>
那些攻擊我的詞語，溫故知新，讓我充滿靈感
<i>Peeped the weakness
in the rap game and sewed it.</i>
我來補上說唱遊戲裡缺少的那一環
<i>Bow down, pray to God
Hoping that he's listening.</i>
雙膝跪地向上帝祈禱，但他是否會聽
<i>Seeing niggas coming for me
and my diamonds...</i>
有些人想搶劫我的鑽石，但……
此句鑽石暗喻Pac的才能
What up, Dre?
你好啊 Dre
What up, Pac?
你好 Pac
I'm about to bust niggas in the mouth
with this new album.
我在新專輯裡要大發神威了
Okay, I feel that.
我感覺到了
- Suge said you got some heat for a nigga.
- Hell yeah!
Suge說你給我準備了一個特火的Beat？ -  絕對的
- Play that for him.
- Okay.
放給他聽一下  -  好
#NowPlaying: "California Love" by Dr.Dre, 2Pac, Roger Troutman
<i>California Love.</i>
加州之愛
Yeah. You feel that?
有感覺
Yeah. Fuck with me.
好啊，找找靈感
<i>California...</i>
加利福尼亞
<i>- "California Love."</i>
- Yeah.
加州之愛  -  對
<i>Knows how to party.</i>
最懂得如何玩樂
<i>California...</i>
加利福尼亞
<i>knows how to party.</i>
最懂得如何逍遙
What the hell was that?
怎麼回事？
Hold on, Pac.
等一下，Pac
Stay right there, man.
別出來，哥們
#NowPlaying: "What Would U Do?" by Tha Dogg Pound
Yo. Shut up. Shut up. Shut up.
喲，小聲點，小聲點
- Come on.
- Come on, man.
別這樣哥們，別這樣
Stop, man! Stop.
Chop, chop.
快點，快點
Get him. Get hype.
咬他，咬他
Get hype.
狠一點
Yo!
喲！
What the fuck are y'all doing?
你們在這幹嘛！
Check this out.
你看看
Get him. Time to eat. Who's hungry?
咬他，該吃東西了，餓了沒
You hungry, nigga? Yeah!
你餓了？嗯？
- Get up.
- Come on!
起來  -  快點
Bring your bitch-ass up.
他媽的，給我起來
Tight-whitey ass nigga.
白內褲小崽子
You know what to do.
你知道要做什麼
I'd like to make a toast.
我給大家敬杯酒
To what?
給誰？
To Death Row Records...
給了 Death Row 唱片
Death Row!
And Suge
還有 Suge
for making all this happen.
讓這一切成為現實
And may the West Coast reign forever.
還有讓西海岸永遠稱王
Come on. Come on.
說啊  -  說啊
And may the West Coast reign forever.
祝西海岸永遠稱王
Now toast to Dr. Dre.
然後再給Dr.Dre敬酒
Put your glass down.
你把杯子放下
I said, put the fucking glasses down!
我說都他媽的把杯子放下！
Hey, yo, slow your roll, Dre.
喲，別激動啊 Dre
Come on.
來啊
This why we got money?
我們為什麼要掙錢？
To act like we ain't got no goddamn sense?
我們怎麼一點理智都沒了？
We coulda did all this dumb shit
這種破事兒我們窮的時候
back in Compton!
在康普頓都可以做
But this what the fuck y'all turned into.
你們現在還想那樣嗎？
You sittin' up here eatin' fuckin' crab.
坐這兒吃著海鮮
Who the fuck are you? Huh?
你他媽誰啊？啊？
This my motherfucking name
on the wall, man!
這牆上他媽的都是我的名字
And y'all in here acting like
y'all on motherfucking vacation.
你們在這High的好像在度假一樣
I got Pac in the next motherfucking room.
2Pac就他媽的在隔壁錄音棚
Grindin', man! Workin'!
辛苦錄歌，在工作
And y'all niggas in here partyin'?
你們卻在這喝酒、玩樂
One time?
還有條子？
- You trippin'.
- That's right.
你一根筋了  -  對啊
We can do anything we wanna do.
我們想幹什麼就可以幹什麼
We started this thing. This is us.
Nah, nigga. Death Row, that's us.
不是，Death Row 是我們的
I don't know what the fuck this shit is.
但這些傢伙我一個都不認識
Better watch your mouth, Blood.
你嘴裡放乾淨點兒，夥計
And who the fuck you talking to, huh?
你以為你跟誰說話呢？
Nigga, you ain't nothing but a producer.
你不過是個製作人而已…
Get the fuck out my face!
你給我滾開
Shit!
靠
Dre.
Dre
This is bullshit.
真扯淡
Dre!
Always fucking with me!
都他媽來找我麻煩
<i>Stop the vehicle now.</i>
請立即停車
Driver, hold it right there.
請停車
<i>Turn your vehicle off.</i>
把車熄火
<i>Drop the keys out of the window!</i>
把鑰匙扔到車窗外
<i>Open the door.</i>
打開車門
<i>Step out of the vehicle. Hands in the air.</i>
雙手舉過頭頂，走出車外
<i>Keep them up! Hold it there.</i>
雙手舉起，雙手舉起
<i>Turn around.</i>
轉身
<i>Turn around. Fingers behind your head.</i>
轉身，雙手抱頭
Hold it right there.
別亂動
#NowPlaying: "Flava In Ya Ear" by Craig Mack
Hey, that's Eazy.
嘿，那不是 Eazy嗎
Wazzup, E! I didn't know that was you.
你好啊 E，沒想到真是你
- Hey, wassup? Wassup, homie?
- Hey. Yo, wuddup?
嘿，你好，你好哥們  -  你好
Nah. Hold up.
嗯，等一下
Hey, hey. Hold up. Relax, homie.
We in a club.
嘿，嘿，等等，放鬆點，我們是來玩的
Cube, I just heard you was over here.
Cube，我聽說你在這
Yeah, I'm here. Whatchu need?
是啊，我在這，有何貴幹？
Everybody to calm the fuck down
from the looks of it.
大家都淡定一點別這麼劍拔弩張
I mean, I was just in
the neighborhood, man.
我正好在附近
I came here with Bone Thugs.
只是和 Bone Thugs 路過
Eazy-E 簽約的組合 Bone Thugs-N-Harmony
I was just coming to say wassup.
順便過來問個好的
Wassup?
嗯
I saw <i>Boyz in the Hood.</i> It was good.
我看了你新拍的電影《街區男孩》
You ain't called that shit
a after school special?
你不是說這部片子是“課後特輯”嗎？
I like after school specials, Cube.
You know that.
我還就喜歡“課後特輯”，你知道的
What's up, man?
你還好嗎哥們
How you feel? You good?
怎麼樣？感覺還好嗎
Hell yeah, nigga, I'm good.
那還用說嗎，我很好
It's good to see you.
又見到你很不錯
It's good to see you right now.
現在看到你太好了
Look at you!
看看你
Pull your fuckin' homies off me then
你要真的看到我挺高興
if it's good to see me.
就讓你這幫哥們別圍著我
You had niggas jump us.
你的兄弟們對我們也不太客氣
God damn!
我靠
How you go from selling rocks
in the dope house
你是怎麼從賣白粉賣房子到後來
to having dinner
in the White House with the President?
居然去白宮跟總統吃晚餐了？
They still trying to figure that shit out.
嗯，好多人還是不明白呢
But, hey, all publicity...
不過，你懂的，所有的曝光
is good publicity.
都是好的宣傳
You know it.
這話沒錯
You know that's right.
你知道這話沒錯
Man.
哥們
Look, man, I wish that dumb shit
我真希望那段爛事兒
really would've never
popped off between us.
從來都沒發生過
We shouldn't have
dissed each other in the first place.
我們其實一開始就不應該互相侮辱
Making the fans choose between us?
還逼著歌迷也選擇陣營
That wasn't cool.
這可太缺了
You right.
你說得對
You ever think we'd be that big, though?
你以前能猜到我們現在會這麼有名嗎？
Hell, no.
絕想不到
I was just talking to my wife about that.
我最近還跟老婆談起
How it was in the beginning.
我們一開始的時候是怎麼想的
Shit, we just wanted to do music
for the neighborhood.
我們只是想做一個描述咱們當地的音樂
Be ghetto stars.
貧民區歌手
But what if we had the chance
如果我們有機會能猜到
to find out how big we can really be?
我們會多麼出名就好了
Come on, man. You got my mind workin'.
你這話說到點子上了
I've been thinking
about that shit all the time.
我也一直在想這個問題
If we could just take that shit
back to '89. We changed the world!
時間倒退回1989，我們在一起改變了世界啊
I hear you.
It was a simpler time, you know?
沒錯，那個時代很簡單
It was hard then.
但做事情更難
But I've had days
不過有時候…
where I almost wish
we was gettin' arrested in Detroit again.
我甚至希望我們能再在底特律被捕
Shit. You know?
你知道嗎
Shit ain't gotta stop there.
事情就不會那麼結束，我們還會是一個組合
But if we go do this,
不過，如果我們要一起再做點事
we gotta do it right.
我們就要做到最好
And if Dre with it, I'm with it.
Dre 沒問題的話，我也沒問題
But I don't know your
relationship with dude.
但我不知道你跟他關係如何
But if you want me, Eric,
Jerry can't be there.
但如果你要我回去，Jerry絕不能在
All right.
明白
Hey, man.
嘿，哥們
Shit!
靠
It's 'cause you
ain't got them damn gloves on.
是不是你出去花天酒地不戴套啊
Man, whatever.
別扯
But I hear you.
你說的我記下了
Yeah?
是嗎
Shit. Ar'ight.
嗯，好啊
These invoices haven't been paid.
這些帳單還沒有付
They're two or three years outdated.
已經過期兩三年了
These are cancelled checks.
They all bounced.
還有些支票被退回來了，都是被拒付了的
And these are past due.
還有過期未付的
Jerry took advantage of you.
Jerry 把你坑了
I know it's a lot,
我知道，數目挺大的
but you had to know the truth sometime.
但你遲早要知道真相的
Now you do.
現在你知道了
You know Dre and Cube
tried to warn me about this.
Dre，Cube 他們都曾經想警告我這事兒
I've been fuckin' up for a long time.
我他媽糊塗了這麼長時間
Don't. Don't.
別這樣
Real long time.
這麼長的時間
Shit.
媽的
Hey, man.
嘿
Where you been?
I've been calling you all day.
你去哪了？我一直給你打電話
Sit down, Jerry.
坐下，Jerry
What is this all about? The groupie?
你想談什麼？組合的事兒？
The executive assistant?
還是你那個助理告訴了你什麼？
She even go to college?
她還上過大學呢？
Man, you're so much fuckin'
smarter than this.
你還不至於這麼笨吧
Sit down, Jerry.
坐下，Jerry
This ain't about Tomica, Jerry.
這跟我媳婦沒關係，Jerry
It's about you.
我要說的是你
And you can stop acting
like you ain't never done nothing wrong.
你別在這裝沒事兒人
You know what, man?
I know that you're upset. I understand.
我知道，你很生氣，我理解
But I'm asking you,
I'm advising you, take a breath, okay?
我請你、建議你，深呼吸一下
I'm gonna look at the paperwork, Eric.
我會處理這些書面的東西 Eric
- You can stop giving me advice as of now.
- It's fucked up.
你從現在開始就不用給我提建議了
Here's what's about to happen.
我告訴你現在要發生什麼
I'mma get N.W.A back together,
我要促成N.W.A.的重組
and you ain't gonna have
nothing to do with it this time.
這次跟你一點關係都沒有
How the fuck can you even say
something like that?
你怎麼能這麼說呢？
What the fuck is going on with you, man?
你到底怎麼了？
I know what's good for you,
我知道什麼對你好
I know what's good for Ruthless...
我知道什麼才是對Ruthless公司好
And we have worked up a trust
after years of hard work,
我們共患難，打拼這麼久建立起來的
and that trust is our foundation, Eric.
信任是我們合作的基礎，Eric
I don't give a shit.
我不在乎
Eric?
Eric
You look lousy, man. Are you okay?
你看上去氣色很差，你還好嗎
Trust?
信任？
Trust is a motherfucker.
信任有時候會玩弄人
Is it?
是嗎？
Let me ask you something.
那我問問你
Eric, if what I'm doing is so illegal,
如果我一直是非法運作
how come I've never been sued?
那為什麼我一直沒被告？
If I'm such a fuckin' thief,
如果我真是個賊
such a liar, such a motherfucker,
騙子，混蛋，吃裡扒外
how come nobody's ever come to collect?
那為什麼沒有人找上門來收帳？
Because this is business
and this is how it works.
因為這是生意，生意就是這麼運作的
And it's not always pretty. No.
生意不是看上去那麼光鮮
Do I cover my own ass?
我要給自己留後路嗎？
Do I cover my own end? Absolutely.
我要給自己留後路嗎？那當然
But don't you dare fuckin' tell me
但你他媽別說我
that I have not taken care of you.
說我從未關心過你
Don't you fuckin' tell me
that I have not had your back from day one!
但你他媽別說，我從未支持過你
Day one!
從最初開始，第一天！
Is this taking care of me?
這就叫，照顧我？
Are you fucking kidding me?
你在開玩笑嗎？
It's taking care of the
whole fucking thing.
我這是照顧整個事業
It's business!
這就是生意
And this is how it works.
生意就是如此
Have I covered my end?
Do I cover my ass? Absolutely.
我要給自己留後路嗎？那當然
But don't you dare fuckin' tell me
但你他媽別說我
that I have not taken care of you.
從未關心過你
This business, too?
你這一套都是“生意”嗎？
Yes! This is business.
沒錯，這也是生意
This is how fucked up it can get.
這就是生意導致的結果
But I didn't start this.
I didn't fuck it up.
但這不是我引起的，事情也不是我搞砸的
You did!
是你！
No.
不
You did.
是你
You fired, Jerry.
你被解雇了，Jerry
Oh, for Christ...
噢天啊
Eric, this is not how we do things.
Eric，這不是我們做事的方式
This is not you.
你不是這樣的人
你不是這樣的
Eric!
Eric
This is an important company.
這是一個非常重要的公司
Eric, I'm not gonna let you fuck this up.
Eric，我不會讓你把事兒搞砸
Eric?
Oh, for Christ's sake!
看在上帝的份上
Eric!
<i>Yeah, hello?</i>
喂，你好
Wuddup, Dre?
你好啊 Dre
<i>- Who this?
</i>-Eric.
你是誰？  -  Eric.
E?
<i>Just felt like calling.</i>
我就是想給你打個電話
<i>Yeah. Okay.</i>
嗯，好啊
What's up?
怎麼樣？
<i>I mean, you know me, man. Doing my thing.</i>
你也知道我，做我自己的事兒
Killin' all this pussy.
忙著上那些妞兒
How about you?
那你呢？
<i>You know, man.</i>
你知道的
I'm just making tracks. Doing my thing.
我就是做音樂，我自己的事兒
Yeah, that Snoop joint you did was crazy.
That was dope.
你跟 Snoop做的那些歌不錯，挺棒的
Yeah? Thanks, E. Good looking out, man.
是嗎？你還一直關注我，謝了
Look, Dre, I know you be busy,
Dre，我知道你挺忙
but I talked to Cube and we were talking
但我和Cube聊過了
about some possibilities.
我們聊了一些事兒
Possibilities? Okay.
什麼事兒，說吧
<i>Yeah, like,</i>
就是……
without Jerry Heller
type of fucking possibilities.
把Jerry排除在外的一些事情
<i>Really?</i>
真的？
Well, it's about time.
那這正是時候
Man, I mean, I know shit kinda went crazy.
哥們我知道，我們之前曾經鬧的很僵
You know, the money
kinda had everybody divided, man,
錢的事兒讓大家都不和了
but I really wish it didn't.
但我真的希望沒有這樣
To be honest, man,
I'm not proud of all the shit I did either.
實話說，我對自己所做的事兒也挺慚愧
So, whatchu think, man?
那你覺得怎麼樣
You think we could get together or what?
Whatchu think?
你覺得我們還能重聚嗎？你覺得如何？
Yeah, man.
好啊
Yeah, that sound good.
聽上去不錯
Let's do it, E. Let's do it.
就這麼幹吧，E ，就這麼幹
<i>I'mma let you know when we can get back
into the studio, you know?</i>
我回錄音室的時候告訴你
Lay down some tracks like the old days.
像以往一樣，一起做點兒歌
Fair enough.
好啊
<i>A'ight.</i>
好的
It's good to hear from you, man.
很高興又聽到你消息
A'ight.
好
Man, y'all niggas
ain't making no music in here.
我沒在這的時候，你們哥幾個什麼也沒做啊
Hey!
嘿
'Sup, E?
你好啊，E
What up? What up? What up?
你好你好… 你好
Yo, hey, when are Dre and Cube
gonna roll up in here, man?
Dre和Cube什麼時候過來啊
- Yeah, man.
- I'm ready!
對啊  -  我準備好了
'Cause I'm ready
to get this new shit going.
我開始做一個新曲子了
I'm ready, too.
我也準備好了
But long as we stay ready,
只要我們準備好
we gonna know we go beyond, man.
我們就一定能作出更牛的東西
You already know
this new N.W.A shit about to be crazy.
你懂的，我們N.W.A.重聚一定太屌了
Here ya go, baby.
給你這個，寶貝
E, I got books of new shit.
I got libraries of new shit.
E，我寫了一圖書館的詞，就等這個
That's what I'm talking about, Ren.
沒錯，Ren，我說的就是這個
That's what I'm talking about.
我說的就是這個
I got the tracks. You like that?
我把音軌都弄好了，怎麼樣？
Hell yeah.
'Chu think you Dre now?
給力，你以為你成Dre了？
I'm trying to murder Dre.
我這歌絕對比他的還燥
I'm about to murder both of y'all
on the track, though. Check me out.
我這段比你們倆都燥，聽我的
Check me out.
聽聽我的
What you doing, E?
You know you don't play no instruments.
你幹什麼，E？ 你不會演奏樂器好嘛
You gonna play it?
你要彈嗎？
E, you all right?
E，你還好嗎？
Eric.
Eric
Baby, you good?
寶貝你還好嗎？
Yeah. I'm all right.
嗯，我沒事
- Eric! Eric!
- Call 911.
Eric! Eric!  -  打911，打911
- Eric! Baby?
- Eric. Get up, man.
寶貝？  -  Eric，快起來，哥們
- Get him up.
- Yo, call 911. Call 911.
扶他起來  -  喲，快打911，打911
- You all right, E?
- Baby? Eric?
你沒事吧，E？ -  寶貝，Eric
- Eazy, wake up.
- Eric! Baby.
Eazy 快醒醒！  -  Eric，寶貝
Open your eyes.
你睜開眼
Yes, we need an ambulance.
我們需要一輛救護車……
Wait... Ain't you gonna say something?
你不說些什麼嗎?
What is it? A respiratory infection?
他怎麼回事？呼吸道感染嗎
Pneumonia? What?
肺炎，還是什麼？
Yes, well, um, it is those things,
這個…… 他的情況
and more, I'm afraid.
還要更嚴重
We ran a full blood battery, and, uh...
我們給他做了全面血液檢測
I'm sorry, Mr. Wright,
but you've tested positive for HIV.
抱歉，Wright先生，你的HIV測試結果顯示呈陽性
Get the fuck outta here.
你別胡說
What?
什麼？
A normal T-cell count
正常的淋巴細胞
is anywhere between 500 and 1,500.
數量應該是五百到一千五
Right now, your T-cell count is 14.
而你現在的數是十四
But I ain't no faggot.
我又不是基佬
Mr. Wright, actually,
Wright先生，實際上
the virus can be transmitted
in quite a few ways,
HIV有多種感染方式
including unprotected heterosexual sex.
包括無保護的異性性行為
That's wrong.
You got to test that over. Test that again!
一定是搞錯了，你得再測試一次，再測一次
We've run the test five times
我們做了五次測試
with five different samples
and the result remains the same.
五個不同的樣本，結果還是一樣的
- Shit!
- Tomica.
天哪！ -  Tomica
Tomica.
Tomica
But she's pregnant, Doc. What's this mean?
但她懷孕了，醫生，這意味什麼
It doesn't necessarily mean
that she's contracted the virus,
這不一定表示她染上了病毒
but we have to test her to be sure.
但是保險起見，我們也會對她做個測試
What do we do? When we start the treatment?
我們該怎麼辦啊，我們什麼時候開始治療啊
I mean, what... I gotta get healthy.
我得，我一定要恢復健康
I got things to do. I got...
我還有好多事情沒做完呢
What am I supposed to do?
我該怎麼辦？
Mr. Wright, you need to understand
Wright先生你要知道
that you are very, very sick.
你現在已經病入膏肓了
But I don't even feel that bad, Doc.
Don't tell me that.
我感覺不那麼糟啊，別告訴我這些東西
With care and palliative care,
用一些藥物和護理
we can probably keep you comfortable
我們大概可以讓你舒服地
for maybe six months, at the very most.
度過幾個月，差不多半年
Comfortable?
舒服？
What do you mean, comfortable?
你什麼意思，舒服？
It's just a matter of time.
你的時間不多了
I am truly, truly sorry, Mr. Wright.
我非常非常抱歉，先生
I'll leave you time to process this.
我會給你點時間接受這件事
Doc. Come on, Doc. No.
別啊，醫生，別這樣
Doc.
醫生
Come on!
天啊！
<i>And one of the pioneers of gangster rap,</i>
一位匪幫說唱的代表人物
<i>as the leader of the group N.W.A
has revealed he has AIDS...</i>
N.W.A.的領袖，被查出患有HIV
<i>We were totally unprepared</i>
我們沒有料到的是
<i>for the kind of outpouring
of fan calls that we had.</i>
歌迷們的來電如潮水一般
<i>We had over 7,000 calls.</i>
我們已經接到了七千多個歌迷電話
I can't.
我覺得我不行
Shh.
慢點
Just let me make this right.
我只想做好這件事
Please.
求你了
'Cause you healthy, hmm?
因為你還健康
- And the baby healthy.
- Yeah. We're healthy.
而且你懷的寶寶也健康
- So?
- Okay.
可以嗎？  -  好
But I just...
我只是……
I love you.
我愛你
And I don't want none of this.
I just want you to be...
我不管一切別的事情，我只想要你
Here.
能在這……
- Are we ready?
- Yeah.
可以了嗎？ -  嗯
Tomica Woods, do you take Eric Wright
to be your lawfully wedded husband?
Tomica，你是否願嫁給 Eric，讓他成為你的合法丈夫？
It's Bone Thugs' new LP, man.
咱們的藝人 Bone Thugs 的新專輯出來了
Everybody thinks
it's gonna be cool when it drop.
剛一發佈，大家都覺得它很酷
- It's gonna be huge, man.
- That's great.
它會特別火的  -  那就好
Do you wanna hear it, man?
You wanna hear it?
你聽過嗎，哥們，你想聽嗎？
Nah, man.
先不了
Just leave it here for me.
把磁帶留下來就行了
I'll check it out later. Thanks.
我有時間就聽，謝了
This is bullshit, man.
這真是太操蛋了，哥們
Hey, Yella, why don't you check
on him, man? See if he ar'ight.
嘿，Yella你去看看他怎麼樣了
Ar'ight? I'll call you
when I get out of here.
好嗎？我出院的時候會給你打電話
Ar'ight?
好嗎
<i>What's his condition?</i>
他現在怎麼樣？
<i>His condition... He's in intensive care.</i>
他現在…… 正在接受加強護理
<i>We're not certain where it's headed.</i>
我們不知道會怎麼樣
'Sup, Eric?
怎麼樣，Eric?
It's Dre.
我是 Dre 啊
Man, I've been makin' some dope new tracks.
我現在在製作一些超勁的歌曲
This next N.W.A album,
it's about to be dope.
N.W.A.的下一張專輯一定超棒
It's about to be huge, you know?
會火到爆的
Hey, you remember that time
嘿，你還記得嗎
when we was making <i>Boyz-N-The Hood?</i>
當年，我們錄 Boyz-N-The Hood
Your non-rappin' ass.
你一開始都不會說唱
You was trippin' out, man.
你差點氣瘋了
I love you, E.
我愛你，E
You hear me? I love you, man.
你聽得見我嗎？我愛你，兄弟
Dre.
Dre
Yo, Cube.
喲 Cube
How is he doing? Can he talk? Can he...
他現在怎樣？他能說話嗎？他能……
Nah, man. He in a fuckin' coma.
不，他一直在他媽的昏迷
Got the machines breathing
for him and shit.
要用呼吸機來替他喘氣
He ain't even conscious.
他連意識都沒有
I need to hear his voice, Dre.
我想聽見他的聲音 Dre
I wanna talk to him.
我想跟他說話
I want him to talk to me.
或者他對我說話也行
I feel that.
我明白
It's all right, man.
一切都會好起來的，哥們
It was good to see you, man.
很高興見到你
You too.
我也是
Peace.
保重
<i>In Los Angeles this morning,</i>
說唱歌手Eazy-E，在經歷
<i>rapper Eazy-E has died
after a battle with AIDS.</i>
與HIV病魔的抗爭後，於今早在洛杉磯去世
<i>He was among the most
powerful voices of his generation.</i>
他是他們那個時代的最強音
<i>Towards the end
of his life, the rapper received</i>
創造了歷史直至生命的終點
<i>more than two and a half thousand calls
a day from well-wishers...</i>
這位說唱者每天收到兩千五百多個電話
<i>Member of the group N.W.A,</i>
Eazy-E 是 N.W.A.組合的成員之一
<i>which helped popularize
harsh inner-city rap music.</i>
他的才華使得說唱音樂的影響力更加強大
<i>Wright was 31.</i>
享年，三十一歲
Eazy's gone.
Eazy 去世了
He gone?
他去世了？
Shit.
靠
<i>- Okay.
</i>-Okay.
好吧  -  好吧
Damn, E.
唉，E
<i>Eazy wrote me a personal letter</i>
Eazy親筆給我寫了一封信
<i>to read to each and every one
of his fans and loved ones.</i>
讓我致給每一位愛他的歌迷和他愛的人們
<i>"I just feel that I've got
thousands and thousands of young fans"</i>
“我感覺到數以千計的年輕歌迷們”
<i>"that have to learn
about what's real when it comes to AIDS."</i>
“需要去瞭解愛滋病的真相”
<i>"I would like to turn my own problem
into something good"</i>
“我想把我的遭遇變成什麼有用的東西”
<i>"that will reach out
to all my homeboys and their kin."</i>
“來傳遞給我的兄弟朋友，還有他們的孩子”
<i>"Much love to those
who have been down for me"</i>
“我深愛那些愛著我的人”
<i>"and thanks for your support."</i>
“感謝有你們的支持”
Pac is in the
studio writing every day.
Pac 每天在錄音室裡搞創作
Snoop is doing his thing.
Whatcha all doing?
Snoop 也在忙他的事情
Y'all niggas are getting too comfortable.
你們這幫傢伙在幹什麼？你們過的太舒服了
- Handle this shit.
- Suge.
搞定這件事…  -嘿！Suge
What's the urgency, Dre?
Dre 有什麼事兒著急要說？
Plotz.
I'm out.
我退出
I'm outta Death Row.
我要退出 Death Row
You ain't done.
你還沒完
Dr. Dre and Death Row are one and the same.
Dr.Dre和Death Row是一回事
You just can't up and leave.
你不能說走就走
I'm doing my own thing, Suge.
我要做我自己的事兒了，Suge
Starting fresh.
從新開始
Nobody to answer to but myself.
沒人能替我做決定
It's time.
就是現在
You're one stupid motherfucker.
你真是夠笨的
You gonna walk away from all this money?
你真的要離開嗎？
If you leave,
如果你走了
everything we created is mine.
所有我們創造的財富就都是我的了
We? Okay.
我們創造的？
You know what? You can have it.
這樣，錢你都拿走吧
You ain't taking nobody with you.
還有，你誰也不能帶走
Death Row stays Death Row.
Death Row 廠牌維持不變
And you even think
about touching my money...
你要是想拿走我一分錢
Motherfucker, you know how I gets down.
你知道我是什麼人，會做什麼事
Do what the fuck you gotta do.
你願意怎麼做就怎麼做吧
You can have the artists, the money,
你還有你的藝人、錢、麻煩
the masters, all your fuckin' bullshit.
還有你的那些狗屁事情
I'm done.
我不幹了
I'm starting my own thing.
我要自己創立自己的廠牌
You can't put a price on peace of mind.
內心的平靜是錢買不到的
I'm out.
我走了
I got all this nigga's money.
我給這些兄弟們足夠的錢
I got everything.
我擁有這兒的一切
Get the fuck out. Go!
那你滾蛋吧，走啊
So whatchu gonna call that bullshit?
所以你的破廠牌要叫什麼名字？
Aftermath.
<i>You are now about to witness</i>
你即將見證
<i>the strength of street knowledge.</i>
來自街頭的力量
<i>It's just, like,
they try to hide what's goin' on</i>
他們想把真相都隱藏起來
<i>and we tell it like it is, you know?</i>
但我們會去還原這些真實
<i>Straight outta Compton
Crazy motherfucker named Ice Cube</i>
Ice Cube:
沖出康普頓，我是狂熱份子Ice Cube
<i>From the gang called Niggas Wit Attitudes</i>
我們的幫派叫“有態度的黑哥們”
<i>You know it's gotta be hard,</i>
你知道我們的東西很強硬
<i>'cause if it ain't hard, it's weak.</i>
否則，我們就太慫了
<i>You too boy if you fuck with me</i>
誰跟我做對就要小心人身安全
<i>The police are gonna have to come and get me</i>
殺人案太多了員警也要想法抓我
<i>MC Ren in the house.</i>
MC Ren 在此
<i>When you making a record,</i>
要做一張夠棒的唱片
<i>you gotta have some hype lyrics.</i>
必須有夠贊的歌詞
<i>And you got that, it's gonna sell.</i>
歌詞夠好，就能大賣
<i>Straight outta Compton
Another crazy ass nigga</i>
MC Ren:
沖出康普頓，又是一個你管不住的大哥
<i>More punks I smoke, yo my rep gets bigger</i>
當我滅掉的敵人越多，我的名氣就更大
Eazy-E probably was one of the nicest
people you ever would have known.
Eazy-E 其實是個特別和善的人
<i>Not as Eazy, but as Eric Wright.</i>
不是Eazy-E這個形象，而是 Eric Wright他本人
<i>But I don't give a fuck, I'ma make my snaps</i>
你說什麼我都不在乎，我有我的路子
<i>If not from the records, from jacking or craps</i>
如果搞唱片不賺錢，我就回到街頭賭骰子
<i>Just like burglary……</i>
就像入室搶劫……
<i>We make our records based on</i>
我們的唱片是根據
<i>stuff that's happening where we live.</i>
我們的地盤所發生的事兒創作的
<i>And if people out there
that don't like it, fuck 'em.</i>
如果有些人不喜歡我們，去他媽的
<i>Straight outta Compton
Is a brother that'll smother your mother</i>
Eazy-E:
沖出康普頓，我出現讓你的老媽都窒息
Dre and Eazy, they had already
been selling it as cassette tapes.
Dre和Eazy在用磁帶的方式銷售他們的歌曲
<i>And they just blew up.</i>
他們現在已經火了
Eazy and Dr. Dre Wild and Wet Pool Party.
Eazy-E和Dr.Dre的瘋狂泳池派對
<i>This is what it's all about!</i>
這就是我們想要的！
<i>We wanted to invite you
to the President's luncheon.</i>
我們希望邀請您參加總統的午餐會
<i>I said if I go down there,
this'll start some shit.</i>
我說，如果我去了，這肯定引起轟動
<i>When I think of N.W.A,
they weren't really music to me.</i>
Kendrick Lamar:
我想起N.W.A，其實不只是說他們的音樂
It was more like a real lifestyle.
而更像是一種真實的生活方式
<i>Brothers from my neighborhood made it out.</i>
來自家鄉康普頓的前輩做到了這個
<i>Niggas start to mumble, they wanna rumble</i>
Ice Cube:
有些夥計支支吾吾想要對我們提出質疑
<i>Mix em and cook em in a pot like gumbo</i>
我把這些聲音煮熟了再烹炒，這是我的菜系
- You got the dopest album out this year.
- Thanks, man.
你的專輯是今年最屌的！ -  謝了
<i>More than happy to get my career</i>
我很幸運，我的職業生涯
<i>going like I want it to go.</i>
能按我的設想順利前進
Damn!
哇喔
<i>You do not know
how long I waited to get in his booth</i>
2Pac:
我都不知道我等了多久才進了他的錄音室
<i>and to have Dre out there goin',
"You ready?"</i>
Dre出來問我，你準備好了嗎？
<i>I waited all my life for that,
since</i> Straight Outta Compton.
自從《沖出康普頓》專輯以來，我就一直等這個機會呢
Dre's direction was helping me
Snoop Dogg:
Dre的指導讓我成為了
become a strong lyricist, which I am now.
一個很強的詞作者，像我現在這樣
<i>Dre has taught me a lot.</i>
Eminem:
Dre教會了我很多東西
<i>Not just rap-wise, but business-wise,</i>
不只是說唱，還有商業上的東西
<i>you know what I'm sayin'?</i>
你明白吧
<i>You'd have to even credit
both Eminem's and my success'</i>
50 Cent:
你其實可以把Eminem和我的成功的一部分
to Dr. Dre.
歸功於Dr.Dre
<i>Apple's purchase of Beats</i>
蘋果公司收購Beats
<i>will be the biggest deal in its history.</i>
是它歷史上最大的一樁交易
<i>Our music was like our weapon.</i>
音樂就好像是我們的武器
<i>We let people know that it's okay</i>
我們讓大家明白，你想說什麼
<i>to say whatchu wanna say.</i>
就可以去說什麼
<i>As I leave, believe I'm stomping</i>
當我退場，也必定帶來震撼
<i>But when I come back boy</i>
但當我再出來
<i>I'm coming straight outta... straight outta...</i>
我一定是沖出…… 沖出……
<i>I'm coming Straight outta Compton</i>
沖出康普頓
<i>Damn, that shit was dope!</i>
這太屌了
<i>I just need y'all to try to bear with me for a minute</i>
希望大家能耐心聽我說幾句
<i>While I talk about the pages of my diary</i>
聊聊我留下的日記，我的經歷
<i>Listen up</i>
聽好
<i>I remember when I got started my intention was to win</i>
我還記得年輕的我當時一心想要出人頭地
<i>But a lot of shit changed since then</i>
但在我的生涯中，世事無常
<i>Some more friends became enemies in the quest of victory</i>
我的一些朋友之間為了名利反目成仇
<i>But I made a vow, never let this shit get to me</i>
但我暗自起誓，不要被這些破事改變我
<i>I let it pass, so I consider that part of my history</i>
這是已經翻過的一篇，但也是我的記憶
<i>And I'm strong; financially, physically</i>
我現在強太多了，不論財富，還是身體
<i>Mentally I'm on a whole 'nother level</i>
甚至精神，我已經超越之前一個層次
<i>And don't forget that I came from the ghetto</i>
別忘了我還是那個來自貧民區的小夥子
<i>Sold a new house for my moms, that's special</i>
曾經賣掉一處房子，為了我的母親
<i>I let you going shopping 'til your feet get tired</i>
帶老媽去逛街購物，直到腿都走累了
<i>Then a new Benz just for you to ride in</i>
買一輛大奔，帶她享受兜風
<i>When I didn't have it, you provided</i>
因為當我沒有成功的時候，是她一直在給予
<i>Don't be surprised that I built an enterprise</i>
別懷疑，我創造了一個音樂帝國
<i>And my house got a view of the city like a highrise</i>
我家陽臺能俯瞰整個城市
暗喻Dre的目光和野心遠大
<i>I'm just talking to my diary</i>
我只是在敘述我的日記
我只是在敘述我的經歷
<i>When I open up my book, I think about the world later</i>
當我翻開日記，讓我先暫時忘掉全世界
<i>No ink in the pen, no lines on the paper</i>
沒有墨水再續寫，沒有格子讓我寫下去
<i>I'm just, I'm just, I'm just talking to my diary</i>
我只是，只是，只是在敘述我的日記
我只是，只是，只是在回憶我的經歷
<i>Sometimes when I got a lot of shit on my mind</i>
有時候我需要考慮的東西太多了
<i>I'm just staring at the sky, you probably thinkin' I'm high</i>
我望著天空放空一下自己，也許你以為我又抽飛了
<i>I'm just, I'm just, I'm just talking to my diary</i>
我只是，只是，只是在敘述我的日記
我只是，只是，只是在回憶我的經歷
<i>Now puff-puff-pass got a nigga having flashbacks</i>
抽一口，傳一下，視線恍惚，閃現回憶
<i>I remember how it used to be</i>
我想起了從前的太多太多
<i>Now my money like NASDAQ, my checks you can cash that</i>
我的錢真的堆成了山，感覺永遠花不完
<i>I remember how it used to be</i>
我想起了太多太多的從前
<i>I used to be a starving artist, so I would never starve an artist</i>
我曾經是一個不能溫飽的藝人，現在我讓旗下藝人都發大財
<i>This is my passion, it's where my heart is</i>
這是我的熱情，我的心血就用在這上面
<i>It gets the hardest when I think about the dearly departed</i>
想到那些曾經的啟程，都是充滿困難的
<i>Like the nigga I started with</i>
跟我一起奮鬥的兄弟
<i>I know Eazy can see me now, looking down through the clouds</i>
我知道，穿過雲層，Eazy-E在天堂看著我們
<i>And regardless, I know my nigga still proud</i>
不管如何，我想我的哥們會為我自豪
<i>It's been a while since we spoke but you still my folks</i>
雖然我們曾經太久沒溝通，但我們永遠是兄弟
<i>We used to sit back, laugh and joke</i>
我們曾經一起扯淡，互相開玩笑
<i>Now I remember when we used to do all-nighters</i>
我還記得我們曾經一起為了音樂忙通宵
<i>You in the booth and Cube in the corner writing</i>
你在錄音室裡，Cube窩在角落寫詞
<i>Where Ren at? Shout out to my nigga Yella</i>
MC Ren呢？我的哥們，還有Yella
<i>Damn, I miss that... shit, a nigga having flashbacks</i>
唉，我依然很懷念，有太多的記憶閃回
<i>When I open up my book, I think about the world later</i>
當我翻開日記，讓我先暫時忘掉全世界
<i>No ink in the pen, no lines on the paper</i>
沒有墨水再續寫，沒有格子讓我寫下去
<i>I'm just, I'm just, I'm just talking to my diary</i>
我只是，只是，只是在敘述我的日記
我只是，只是，只是在回憶我的經歷
<i>Sometimes when I got a lot of shit on my mind</i>
有時候我需要考慮的東西太多了
<i>I'm just staring at the sky, you probably thinkin' I'm high</i>
我望著天空放空一下自己，也許你以為我又抽飛了
<i>I'm just, I'm just, I'm just talking to my diary</i>
我只是，只是，只是在敘述我的日記
我只是，只是，只是在回憶我的經歷